<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1305" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinance.</fw>
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE.</head>
<p>Whereas, various contracts have been entered into by the President of the Republic of Texas, with divers individuals, with the expressed in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tention of colonizing an enormous amount of the public domain of Texas; and</p>
<p>Whereas, it is believed that said contracts are unconstitutional, and therefore, void from the beginning, and if carried out would operate as a monopoly of upwards of seven millions of acres of the public do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main of Texas, in the hands of a few individuals&#8212;when, in truth, the citizen soldiers and creditors of the Republic of Texas had, by the laws and Constitution of said Republic, a clear and indisputable pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viously subsisting right to locate upon the public domain thus at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tempted to be assigned to said contractors:&#8212;</p>
<p>Sec. 1. Therefore it is hereby ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Attorney General of this State, or the District Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney of the District in which any portion of the colonies may be situ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate, as soon as the organization of the State shall be completed, to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute legal proceedings against all colony contractors who have entered into contracts with the President of Texas; and if, upon such investiga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, it shall be found that any such contract was unconstitutional, illegal or fraudulent, or that the conditions of the same have not been complied with according to its terms, such contract shall be adjudged and decreed null and void: provided, however, that all actual settlers under any such contract, shall be entitled to their quantity of land as colonists&#8212;not to exceed six hundred and forty acres to the head of a family, and three hundred and twenty acres to a single man. And in all suits brought by or against any contractors, or any person claiming under, by or through them, or either of them, it shall be lawful for the adverse claimant to set forth any plea that it would have been competent for the State to plead; and the party may introduce testimony to prove the claim or title to have been forfeited, as well for frauds, or illegality, or unconstitutionality, as on account of a failure to comply with the conditions of the original grant or contract; and any such pleas shall be deemed good and valid in law, in all such suit or suits in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained, That the Legislature is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strained from extending any contract for settling a colony, and from relieving any contractor from the failure of the conditions, or the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feiture accruing from non-compliance with the contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. And be it further ordained, That this Ordinance shall be presented to the people for their adoption or rejection, at the same time that this Constitution shall be presented to them, and the returns of the votes taken on this Ordinance shall be made to the office of the Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1306" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinance.</fw>retary of State of the Republic of Texas, at the same time the votes for the Constitution may be returned.</p>
<p>Adopted in Convention, this twenty-seventh day of August, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and forty-five.</p>
<closer>
<signed>THOS. J. RUSK, President.</signed>
<signed>Attest,<lb/> JAMES H. RAYMOND,<lb/> Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div1>
</body>
</text>