<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="878" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>Whereas, by a Proclamation issued on the eleventh day of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, A. D. 1840, in contravention of law and Treaty stipulations, by Mirabeau B. Lamar, (then President,) &#8220;the duties on all wines, the product of France, imported direct from any of the Ports of France, in French or Texian Vessels&#8221; were abolished: And where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as, in further violation of law and Treaty stipulations, &#8220;all col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lectors of customs were required to permit all wines, as aforesaid, to be admitted free of duty, into any of the ports of this Republic, until this proclamation shall be revoked by the President:&#8221; And whereas, neither propriety, policy nor a just regard due to the rights of our citizens requires the continuance of such an immunity to any foreign power: And whereas, other Governments have made the same a cause of complaint to this:&#8212;</p>
<p>Therefore, be it known that I, SAM HOUSTON, President of the Republic of Texas, by virtue of the power vested in me by law, do, hereby, solemnly revoke the said proclamation, and require all collectors of customs in the Republic to demand and receive the duties imposed upon wines, the product of France, imported into Texas, according to the rates established by law, and by the exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Treaty between the two countries: This proclamation to be in force and take effect from and after the fiftenth day of Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary next.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and caused the great seal of the Republic to be affixed.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>Done at the town of Washington, the twenty-first day of December, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty two, and of the Independence of Texas the seventh.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> ANSON JONES,<lb/> Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="879" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>Whereas, by an act of Congress of the Republic of Texas, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 5th, 1840, the eighth section, it is provided, that all free persons of color shall remove out of this Republic, within two years from the passage of said act, under certain penalties: And whereas, it has been represented to me, that there are a num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of honest and industrious persons of that description, who have been citizens of this country for a number of years, and have al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ways heretofore conducted themselves so as to obtain the confidence and good opinion of all acquainted with them, and are now anx<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ious to be permitted to remain in the Republic for the next two years, from and after the fifth day of February next:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it known, that I, SAM. HOUSTON, President of the Republic of Texas, in virtue of the power and authority vested in me by the constitution and the law, do, in the name and by the authority of said Republic, issue this, my proclamation, remitting the penalty of the law that might otherwise attach against them for remaining in the Republic; to be in effect and operative for the term of two years from the fifth day of February next: Provided, those who wish to obtain the benefit of this proclamation, apply to the Chief Justice of the county in which they reside, and make satisfactory proof of their good character, and also enter into bond and security, in the penal sum of five hundred dollars, payable to the President and his successors in office, for their good behavior during the term specified in this proclamation.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and caused the great seal of the Republic to be affixed.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>Done at the town of Washington, the twenty-first day of December, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty two, and of the Independence of Texas the seventh.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> ANSON JONES,<lb/> Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="880" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>To all and singular to whom these presents shall come,&#8212;Greeting: Whereas a Treaty of Commerce and Navigation, between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, was concluded and signed by the Plenipotentiaries of this Republic and her Britanic Majesty, at the city of London, on the thirteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty; which Treaty is, word for word, as follows:</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">TREATY OF COMMERCE AND NAVIGATION BETWEEN THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS AND GREAT BRITAIN.</head>
<p>The Republic of Texas, and her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, being equally de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sirous of affording every facility and encouragement to their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective Citizens and Subjects, engaged in commercial intercourse with each other, have nominated as their Plenipotentiaries to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clude a Treaty for this purposes, that is to say:&#8212;</p>
<p>The Republic of Texas, General James Hamilton, &#38;c., &#38;c., And Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, the Right Honorable Henry John, Viscount Palmerston, Baron Temple, a Peer of Ireland, a Member of Her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Most Honorable Privy Council, a Member of Parliament, Knight Grand Cross of the Most Honorable Order of the Bath, and Her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Principal Secretary of State for Foreign Affiairs;&#8212;</p>
<p>Who, after having communicated to each other their respective Full Powers, found in good and due form, have agreed upon and concluded the following Articles:</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<p>There shall be reciprocal liberty of Commerce and Naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion between and amongst the Citizens of the Republic of Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as, and the subjects of Her Britannic Majesty; and the Citizens<pb n="881" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> or Subjects of the two countries, respectively, shall not pay, in the Ports, Harbors, Roads, Cities, Towns, or Places whatsoever, in either State, any other or higher duties, taxes, or imposts, under whatsoever names designated or included, than those which are there paid by the Citizens or Subjects of the most favored Na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; and the Citizens and Subjects, respectively, of the Two High Contracting Parties, shall enjoy the same rights, privileges, liber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, favors, immunities, and exemptions, in matters of Commerce and Navigation, that are granted, or may hereafter be granted, in either Country, to the Citizens or Subjects of the most favored Na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>No duty of Customs, or other imposts, shall be charged upon any goods the produce of one Country, upon importation by sea or by land, from such country into the other, higher than the duty or impost charged upon goods of the same kind, the produce of, or imported from, any other Country; and the Republic of Texas, and Her Majesty the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Brit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ain and Ireland, do hereby hind and engage themselves not to grant any favor, privilege or immunity, in matters of Commerce and Navigation, to the Citizens or Subjects of any other State, which shall not be also, and at the same time, extended to the Citizens or Subjects of the other High Contracting Party, gratuitously, if the concession in favor of that other State shall have been gratuitous; or on giving as nearly as possible the same compensation or equiva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lent, in case the concession shall have been conditional.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<p>No duties of Tonnage, Harbor, Lighthouses, Pilotage, Quaran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tine, or other similar or corresponding duties, of whatever nature, or under whatever denomination, shall be imposed in either Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try, upon the Vessels, or upon any articles the growth, produce, or manufacture of the other, in respect of voyages between the two Countries, if laden, or in respect of any voyage, if in ballast, which shall not be equally imposed, in the like cases, on National Vessels; and in neither country shall any duty, charge, restriction, or prohibition, be imposed upon, nor any draw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />back, bounty, or allowance be withheld from, any goods imported from, or exported to, any Country, in the Vessels of the one Country, which shall not be equally imposed upon, or withheld from, such goods, when so imported or exported in the Vessels of the other Country.</p>
<pb n="882" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<p>The Citizens and Subjects of each Country shall enjoy full lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty to go to the Ports and Harbors of the other Country, where other foreigners are allowed to enter, to unlade their Merchandize therein, to hire and occupy Houses, and peaceably to conduct their respective Trades and Professions.</p>
<p>The Ships of War of both Countries, respectively, shall have the liberty to enter freely and touch at all such Ports in each Country, into which the Ships of War of any other Nation are per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to enter; subject, however, to the Regulations, Laws, and Statutes of the respective Countries.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IV.</head>
<p>The stipulations of the present Treaty shall not be considered as applying to the Navigation and carrying Trade between one Port and another situated in the Dominions of one Contracting Party, by the Vessels of the other, as far as regards Passengers, Commodi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, and Articles of Commerce; such Navigation and transport be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing reserved by each Contracting Party to National Vessels.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE V.</head>
<p>The High Contracting Parties reserve for future negotiation, at such time as they may mutually agree upon, the conditions upon which the Trade and Navigation shall be regulated between the Republic of Texas and Her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Colonial Posses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions in Europe, Asia, Africa, and America.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VI.</head>
<p>Whereas, in the present state of Texian Shipping, the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas would not enjoy the full benefit of the recipro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />city intended by this Treaty, if no Vessel were to be admitted into British Ports as a Texian Vessel, unless it had been built within the territory of Texas; it is therefore agreed, that for the space of eight years, to be reckoned from the date of the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />change of the Ratifications of this Treaty, any Vessels, where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />soever built, being bona fide the property of, and wholly owned by, one or more Citizens of the Republic of Texas, and whereof the Master and three fourths of the Mariners, at least, are naturalized Citizens of the said Republic, or persons domicilia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="883" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>ted in that Republic by act of the Government, as lawful citizens of the Texian Republic, to be certified according to the Laws of that Country, shall be considered as Texian Vessels:&#8212;Her Majesty the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland reserving to Herself the right, at the end of the said term of eight years, to claim that the provisions of the British Navigation Act, relative to the nationality of Foreign Vessels, shall be strictly ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied to Texian Vessels in British Ports.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VII.</head>
<p>The Consuls and Vice-Consuls of each Country shall, within the territory of the other, enjoy all the rights, privileges, and immuni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties which are accorded to such Functionaries by the Law of Na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions. And it is provided, that, in the Ports of each Country, es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pecially, the authorities shall give all due legal assistance and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tection to the apprehension, safe keeping, and delivery of all de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serters from the Ships of War and trading Vessels of either Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try. And all the powers and privileges granted in respect to the matters to which the stipulations of this Article relate, by either of the Contracting Parties to any other Nation, shall be granted by such Contracting Party to the Consuls, Vice-Consuls, Ships of War, and trading Vessels of the other.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VIII.</head>
<p>If any Ships of War or Merchant Vessels should he wrecked on the Coasts of either of The High Contracting Parties, such Ships or Vessels, or any parts thereof, and all furniture and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />purtenances belonging thereunto, and all goods and merchan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dize which shall be saved therefrom, or the produce thereof, if sold, shall be faithfully restored to the Proprietors, upon being claimed by them, or by their duly authorized Factors; and if there are no such Proprietors or Factors on the spot, then the said goods and merchandize, or the proceeds thereof, as well as all the papers found on board such wrecked Ships or Vessels, shall be delivered to the Texian or British Consul, in whose dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict the wreck may have taken place; and such Consul, Proprietors or Factors, shall pay only the expenses incurred in the preservation of the property, together with the rate of sal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vage which would have been payable in the like case of a wreck<pb n="884" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> of a national Vessel; and the goods and merchandize saved from the wreck shall not be subject to duties, unless cleared for con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sumption.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IX.</head>
<p>The exercise of the rites of religious Worship and freedom of conscience, shall be reciprocally secured to the Citizens and Sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects of each Country, by the Government of the other. The right of sepulture shall be reciprocally accorded by each of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracting Parties to the other; and there shall be no Law passed by either Government, that shall violate the rights of property, or limit the power of bequeathing Personal Estate by Will or Testa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>
<p>The Citizens or Subjects of the one Country, residing in the other, shall not be liable, under extraordinary Warrants, or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, to compulsory services, or to forced Loans; and on all ques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions affecting the rights of Person or Property, the Courts of Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicature of the one Country shall be impartially open to the Citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens or Subjects of the other.</p>
<p>In the event of War between the Contracting Parties, the Citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens or Subjects of the one Country, residing in the other, shall reciprocally have Twelve Months, after a formal Declaration of the same, to depart with their property and effects, and without any hindrance or disturbance whatsoever.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE X.</head>
<p>The present Treaty, when the same shall have been ratified by the President of the Republic of Texas, by and with the Advice and Consent of the Senate, and by Her Britannic Majesty, shall be binding and obligatory on the Contracting Parties for eight years from the date of its Signature; and further, until the expiration of Twelve Months after One of The High Contracting Parties shall have notified to the other an intention to terminate its duration. It is further agreed, that in Twelve Months after One of the High Contracting Parties shall have received from the other such notification, this Treaty, and all the stipulations it contains, shall cease to be obligatory upon either Party.</p>
<pb n="885" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XI.</head>
<p>The present Treaty shall be ratified, and the Ratifications shall be exchanged at London, as soon as possible within the space of Nine Months from this date.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentiaries have signed the same, and have affixed thereto the Seals of their Arms.</p>
<p>Done at London, the thirteenth day of November, in the Year of our Lord One Thousand Eight Hundred and Forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON. [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>PALMERSTON. [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>And whereas, the said Treaty has been duly ratified on both parts, and the respective ratifications of the same were exchanged at the City of London, on the twenty-eighth day of June, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and forty-two, by Ashbel Smith, Minister Charg&#233; d&#8217;Affaires of the Republic of Texas, and the Earl of Aber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deen, Her Majesty&#8217;s Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, on the part of their respective Governments:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, be it known that I, SAM. HOUSTON, Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Republic of Texas, have caused the said Treaty to be made public, to the end that the same, and every clause and article thereof, may be observed and fulfilled with good faith by the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, and the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, caused the Great Seal of the Republic of Texas to be affixed. Done at the City of Houston, this six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, and of the Independence of Texas the Seventh.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> JOSEPH WAPLES,<lb/> Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="886" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" />
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>To all and singular to whom these presents shall come,&#8212;Greeting:</p>
<p>Whereas a Convention between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, was concluded and signed at London, on the fourteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty, by the Plenipotentiaries of this Republic and Her Britannic Majesty, duly and respectively authorised for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose; which Convention is, word for word, as follows:&#8212;</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONVENTION.</head>
<p>Whereas Her Majesty the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, being desirous of putting an end to the hostilities which still continue to be carried on between Mexico and Texas, has offered Her Mediation to the Contending Parties, with a view to bring about a pacification between them; and where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as the Republic of Texas has accepted the mediation so offered; the Republic of Texas and Her Britannic Majesty have determined to settle, by means of a Convention, certain arrangements which will become necessary in the event of such pacification being ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fected, and have for this purpose named as their Plenipotentiaries, that is to say:&#8212;</p>
<p>The Republic of Texas, General James Hamilton, &#38;c., &#38;c., And Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, the Right Honorable Henry John, Viscount Palmerston, Baron Temple, a Peer of Ireland, a Member of Her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Most Honorable Privy Council, a Member of Parliament, Knight Grand Cross of the Most Honorable Order of the Bath, and her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Principal Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs;&#8212;</p>
<p>Who, after having communicated to each other their respective Full Powers, found in good and due form, have agreed upon and concluded the following Articles:</p>
<pb n="887" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Convention, &#38;c.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<p>The Republic of Texas agrees that if, by means of the Media<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Her Britannic Majesty, an unlimited Truce shall be estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished between Mexico and Texas, within thirty days after this present Convention shall have been communicated to the Mexican Government by her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Mission at Mexico; and if, within Six Months from the day on which that communication shall have been so made, Mexico shall have concluded a Treaty of Peace with Texas, then and in such case the Republic of Texas will take upon itself a portion, amounting to One Million Pounds Sterling, of the Capital of the Foreign Debt contracted by the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Mexico before the 1st of January, One thousand Eight Hundred and Thirty-Five.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<p>The manner in which the Capital of One Million Pounds Ster<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ling of Foreign Debt, mentioned in the preceding Article, shall be transferred from the Republic of Mexico to the Republic of Texas, shall be settled hereafter by special Agreement between the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas and the Republic of Mexico, under the Mediation of Her Britannic Majesty.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<p>The present Convention shall be ratified, and the Ratifications shall be exchanged at London, as soon as possible within the space of Nine Months from this date.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentiaries have signed the same, and have affixed thereto the Seals of their Arms.</p>
<p>Done at London, the Fourteenth day of November, in the Year of our Lord One Thousand Eight Hundred and Forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON. [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>PALMERSTON. [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>And whereas, the said Convention has been duly ratified on both parts, and the respective ratifications of the same exchanged at the City of London, on the twenty-eighth day of June, one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, by Ashbel Smith, Minister Charg&#233; d&#8217;Affaires of the Republic of Texas, and the Earl of Aberdeen, Her Majesty&#8217;s Secretary of State for Foreign Affiairs, on the part of their respective Governments:</p>
<pb n="888" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ix" /><fw type="header" place="top">Convention, &#38;c.</fw>
<p>Now, therefore, be it known that I, SAM. HOUSTON, Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Republic of Texas, have caused the said Convention to be made public, to the end that the same, and every clause and article thereof, may be observed and fulfilled with good faith by the Republic of Texas, and the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the Great Seal of the Republic of Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as to be affixed. Done at the City of Houston, this sixteenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, and of the Independence of Texas the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enth.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> JOSEPH WAPLES,<lb/> Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="889" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="x" />
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>To all and singular to whom these presents shall come,&#8212;Greeting:</p>
<p>Whereas, a treaty between the Republic of Texas and Great Brit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ain, for the suppression of African slave trade, was concluded and signed at the City of London, on the sixteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with two forms of Warrants and Instructions to cruisers, thereunto annexed, by the Plenipotentiaries of this Republic and her Britannic Majesty, duly and respectively authorized for that purpose; which Treaty and forms of Warrants and Instructions are, word for word, as follows:</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">TREATY BEWEEN THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS AND GREAT BRITAIN FOR THE SUPPRESSION OF AFRICAN SLAVE TRADE.</head>
<p>Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Brit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ain and Ireland, wishing to give fuller effect to the principles which form the basis of the Treaties which have been concluded between Great Britain and several other European powers, for the suppression of the African Slave Trade, and the Republic of Texas being likewise desirous of rendering effectual the fundamental ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticle in her Constitution, which declares the said trade piracy, have determined to negotiate and conclude a Treaty for the more ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fectual extinction of this traffic.</p>
<p>For this purpose the Republic of Texas and Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, have named as their Plenipotentaries, that is to say:&#8212;The Republic of Texas, Gen. James Hamilton, &#38;c, &#38;c.; and Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, the Right Honorable Henry John, Viscount Pal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />merston, Baron Temple, a Peer of Ireland, a member of Her Britannic (Majesty&#8217;s Most Honorable Privy Council, a Member of Parliament, Knight Grand Cross of the Most Honorable Order<pb n="890" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> of the Bath, and Her Britannic Majesty&#8217;s Principal Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs; who, after having communicated to each other their respective Full Powers, found in good and due form, have agreed upon and concluded the following articles:</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<p>The Republic of Texas and Her Majesty, the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, engage to prohibit African Slave Trade, either by their respective citizens or subjects, or under their respective flags, or by means of capital belonging to their respective citizens or subjects, and to declare such trade piracy. And the high contracting parties further declare, that any vessel attempting to carry on the slave trade shall, by that act alone, lose all right to claim the protection of their flag.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<p>In order more completely to accomplish the object of the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent treaty, the high contracting parties mutually consent that those ships of their respective navies which shall be provided with special warrants and orders, according to the form in Annex A, to this treaty, may visit such merchant vessels of either of the high con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracting parties as may, upon reasonable grounds, be suspected of being engaged in the aforesaid traffic in slaves, or of having been fitted out for that purpose, or of having, during the voyage on which they are met with by the said cruisers, been engaged in the aforesaid traffic; and that such cruisers may detain, and send or carry away such vessels, in order that they may be brought to trial in the manner hereinafter agreed upon.</p>
<p>But the above mentioned right of searching merchant vessels of either of the high contracting parties, shall be exercised only by ships of war, whose commanders shall have the rank of captain, or at least that of lieutenant in the navy, unless the command shall, by reason of death or otherwise, be held by an officer of inferior rank, and the commander of such ship of war shall be furnished with a warrant according to the form an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nexed to this treaty, letter A, and the said right shall not be exercised within the Mediterranean sea, nor within those seas in Europe which lie without the Straits of Gibralter, and to the northward of the 37th parallel of north latitude, and within and<pb n="891" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> to the eastward of the meridian of longitude, twenty degrees west of Greenwich; nor in the Gulf of Mexico, to the northward of the 25th parallel of north latitude, nor to the westward of the 90th degree of longitude, west of Greenwich.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<p>Each of the high contracting parties reserves to itself the right to fix, according to its own convenience, the number of ships of its navy which shall be employed on the service mentioned in the second article of this treaty, and the stations on which such ships shall cruize.</p>
<p>The names of the ships so to be employed, and of their com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manders, shall be communicated by each contracting party to the other; and information shall be reciprocally given by each to the other, when a cruizer is moved from or to a cruizing station, in order that the necessary warrants for the cruizers may be delivered by the Government of either party, as the case may be, and may, when no longer wanted for use under this treaty, be returned to the government which issued them, by the government which re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived them.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IV.</head>
<p>Immediately after the government which employs the cruizers shall have notified to the government which is to authorize the visit, the number and names of the cruizers intended to be employed, the warrants authorizing the visit shall be made out according to the form annexed to this treaty, letter A, and shall be delivered by the government authorizing the visit, to the government em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ploying the cruizer.</p>
<p>In no case shall the right of mutual visit he exercised upon the ships of war of either nation.</p>
<p>The high contracting parties shall agree upon a particular signal to be used by those cruizers exclusively which are invested with the right to visit.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE V.</head>
<p>The cruizers of the high contracting parties, authorized to exercise the right of visit and detention in execution of this treaty, shall, in all that relates to the formalities of the visit and of the detention, as well as in regard to the measures to be taken for delivering up to the proper jurisdiction, vessels sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="892" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xiii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw>pected of being engaged in the slave trade, conform strictly to the instructions annexed to the present treaty, letter B.</p>
<p>The high contracting parties reserve to themselves the power of making in these instructions, by common consent, any altera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions which circumstances may render necessary.</p>
<p>The cruizers of the high contracting parties shall afford to each other mutual assistance, on all occasions when it may be useful that they should act in concert.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VI.</head>
<p>Whenever a merchant vessel, navigating under the flag of either of the contracting parties, shall have been detained by a cruizer of the other, duly authorized to that effect, conformably to the provisions of this treaty, such merchant vessel, as also her master, her crew, her cargo, and the slaves who may be on board of her, shall be carried to such place as shall have been appointed to that end by the contracting parties, respectively; and they shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livered over to the authorities appointed for that purpose by the government within whose territory such place shall be, to be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeded against before the proper tribunals, as hereinafter directed.</p>
<p>When the commander of the cruizer shall not think proper to take upon himself to carry in and deliver up the detained vessel, he shall not entrust that duty to an officer below the rank of lieutenant in the navy, unless it be to the officer who at the time shall not be lower than third in command of the detaining ship.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VII.</head>
<p>If the commander of a cruizer of either of the contracting par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties shall have reason to suspect that a merchant vessel, navigating under convoy of, or in company with, a ship of war of the other contracting party, has been engaged in the slave trade, or has been fitted out for the said trade, he is to make known his suspicions to the commander of the ship of war, who shall proceed alone to visit the suspected vessel; and if the last mentioned commander shall find that the suspicion is well founded, he shall cause the vessel, together with her master, her crew, and the cargo, and the slaves who may be on board of her, to be taken into a port of her own nation, to be proceeded against before the proper tribunals, as hereinafter directed.</p>
<pb n="893" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xiv" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw></div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VIII.</head>
<p>As soon as any merchant vessel, detained and sent in for adju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />the provisions of annex B, to this treaty, the commander of the cruizer which shall have detained her, or the officer appointed to bring her in, shall deliver to the authorities appointed for that purpose, a copy, signed by himself, of all the lists, declarations, and other documents, specified in the instructions which are an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nexed to the present treaty, letter B; and the said authorities shall, in consequence, proceed to a survey of the detained vessel and her cargo, and to an inspection of her crew, and of the slaves who may be on board, after having previously given notice of the time of such survey and inspection to the commander of the cruizer, or to the officer who shall have brought in the vessel, in order that he, or some person on his behalf, may be present thereat.</p>
<p>A declaration of these proceedings shall be drawn up in dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate, signed by the persons who shall have acted therein, or who shall have been present at the same; and one of the said declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions shall be delivered to the commander of the cruizer, or to the officer who shall have been appointed to bring in the detained ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IX.</head>
<p>Any merchant vessel of either of the high contracting parties, which shall be visited and detained in pursuance of the provisions of this treaty, shall, unless proof be given to the contrary, be deemed to have been engaged in the African Slave Trade, or to have been fitted out for the purposes of such traffic, if any of the particulars hereinafter specified shall be found in her outfit or equipment, or to have been on board during the voyage on which the vessel was proceeding when captured, videlicet:</p>
<p>First:&#8212;Hatches with open gratings, instead of the close hatches which are usual in merchant vessels;</p>
<p>Secondly:&#8212;Divisions or bulk-heads in the hold or on deck, in greater number than are necessary for vessels engaged in lawful trade;</p>
<p>Thirdly:&#8212;Spare plank fitted for being laid down as a second or slave deck;</p>
<p>Fourthly:&#8212;Shackles, bolts, or handcuffs;</p>
<p>Fifthly:&#8212;A larger quantity of water in casks or in tanks,<pb n="894" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> than is requisite for the consumption of the crew of the vessel, as a merchant vessel;</p>
<p>Sixthly:&#8212;An extraordinary number of water casks, or of other receptacles for holding liquid; unless the master shall produce a certificate from the custom-house at the place from which he clear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed outwards, stating that sufficient security had been given by the owners of such vessel, that such extra quantity of casks or of other receptacles should only be used to hold palm-oil, or for other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses of lawful commerce;</p>
<p>Seventhly:&#8212;A greater quantity of mess-tubs or kids, than are requisite for the use of the crew of the vessel, as a merchant vessel.</p>
<p>Eighthly:&#8212;A boiler, or other cooking apparatus, of an unusual size, and larger, and fitted for being made larger, than requisite for the use of the crew of the vessel as a merchant vessel; or more than one boiler, or other cooking apparatus of the ordinary size;</p>
<p>Ninthly:&#8212;An extraordinary quantity of rice, of the flour of Brazil manioc, or cassada, commonly called farina, of maize, or of Indian corn, or of any other article of food whatever, beyond what might probably be requisite for the use of the crew; such rice, flour, maize, Indian corn, or other articles of food, not being entered in the manifest, as part of the cargo for trade;</p>
<p>Tenthly:&#8212;A quantity of mats or matting, greater than is neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the use of the vessel as a merchant vessel.</p>
<p>Any one or more of these several things, if proved to have been found on board, or to have been on board during the voyage on which the vessel was proceeding when captured, shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered as prima facie evidence of the actual employment of the vessel in the African Slave Trade; and the vessel shall thereupon be condemned and be declared lawful prize, unless clear and incon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />testible evidence on the part of the master or owners shall estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish, to the satisfaction of the court, that such vessel was, at the time of her detention or capture, employed in some legal pursuit; and that such of the several things, above enumerated, as were found on board her at the time of her detention, or which had been put on board her during the voyage on which she was proceeding when captured, were needed for legal purposes on that particular voy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE X.</head>
<p>A vessel detained as before mentioned, together with her master, crew, and cargo, shall be forthwith proceeded against<pb n="895" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xvi" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> before the proper tribunals of the country to which she belongs, and shall be tried and adjudged by, and according to, the estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished forms and laws in force in that country; and if, in conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quence of such proceedings, the said vessel shall be found to have been employed in the African Slave Trade, or to have been fitted out for the purposes thereof, the vessel and her equipments, and her cargo of merchandize, shall be confiscated; and the master, the crew, and the accomplices shall be dealt with conformably to the laws by which they have been tried.</p>
<p>If the said vessel shall be confiscated, the proceds arising from her sale shall, within six months from the date of such sale, be paid into the hands of the government of the country to which the captor belongs, to be distributed according to law among the officers and crew of the capturing ship.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XI.</head>
<p>If any of the things specified in Article IX of this treaty shall be found on board, or to have been on board, of any merchant vessel, during the voyage, on which the vessel was proceeding when captured, no compensation for losses, damages, or expenses, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequent upon the detention of such vessel, shall, in any case, be granted, either to her master, or to her owner, or to any other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son interested in her equipment or lading, even though sentence of condemnation should not be pronounced against her, in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequence of her detention.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XII.</head>
<p>In all cases in which a vessel shall, under this treaty, be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained as having been engaged in the African Slave Trade, or as having been fitted out for the purposes thereof, and shall be ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />judged and confiscated accordingly, the government whose cruizer detained the vessel, or the government by whose tribunal the vessel may be condemned, may purchase the condemned vessel for the use of its navy, at a price to be fixed by a competent person, to be chosen for that purpose by the said tribunal, the government whose cruizer detained the condemned vessel having the first choice of purchasing her. But if the condemned vessel shall not be so pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased, the said vessel shall, immediately after the sentence of confiscation, be broken up entirely, and shall be sold in separate parts, after having been so broken up.</p>
<pb n="896" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xvii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XIII.</head>
<p>When a merchant vessel, detained under this treaty, shall, upon adjudication before the proper tribunal, be held not to have been engaged in the African Slave Trade, and not to be fitted up for the purposes thereof, she shall be restored to her lawful owner or owners; and if, in the course of adjudication, it shall be proved that she has been visited and detained illegally, or without suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient cause of suspicion; or if it shall be proved that the visit and detention have been attended with any abuse, or with vexatious acts, the commander of the cruizer, or the officer who shall have boarded the said vessel, or the officer who shall have been appointed to bring her in, and under whom (as the case may be) the abuse or vexatious acts shall have been committed, shall be liable to costs and damages to be paid to the master and to the owners of the ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel and cargo.</p>
<p>These costs and damages may be awarded by the tribunal be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore which the proceedings against the detained vessel, her master, crew, and cargo, shall have been instituted: and the government of the country to which the officer whose proceedings gave occasion for such award belongs, shall pay the amount of the said costs and damages within the period of one year from the date of the award.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XIV.</head>
<p>If in the visit or detention of a merchant vessel under this treaty, any abuse or vexation shall have been committed, and if the vessel shall not have been delivered over to the jurisdiction of her own nation, the master of the vessel shall make a declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, on oath, of the abuses or vexations of which he has to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plain, and of the costs and damages to which he lays claim; and this declaration shall be made to him before the competent autho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rities in the first port of his own country at which he may arrive, or before the Consular Agent of his own nation at a foreign port, if the vessel shall first proceed to a foreign port, where there is such an agent.</p>
<p>This declaration shall be confirmed by an examination, upon oath, of the principal persons among the crew or passengers, who have witnessed the visit or detention; and a formal statement of the whole shall be drawn up, and two copies thereof shall be delivered to the master, who shall forward one of them to his own govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, in support of his claim for costs and damages.</p>
<pb n="897" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xviii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
<p>It is understood, that if any circumstances should unavoidably prevent the master from making this declaration, it may be made by the owner, or by any other person interested in the vessel and in her cargo.</p>
<p>On receiving, officially, a copy of the formal statement, above<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentioned, the Government of the country to which the officer so charged with abuses and vexations shall belong, shall forthwith in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute an inquiry into the matter; and if the complaint be proved to be valid, the said government shall cause to be paid to the mas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter or owner, or to any other person interested either in the vessel which has been molested, or in her cargo, the proper amount of costs and damages.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XV.</head>
<p>The high contracting parties engage, reciprocally, to communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate each to the other, when asked to do so, and free of expense, copies of proceedings instituted, and of judgments given, relative to vessels visited or detained in execution of the provisions of this treaty.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVI.</head>
<p>The high contracting parties agree to ensure the immediate free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dom of slaves who shall be found on board vessels detained and condemned in virtue of the stipulations of the present treaty; and, for this purpose, it is agreed that all slaves found on board a Texian vessel detained in the West Indies, shall, if the vessels be condemned by the Texian tribunals, be delivered over by the Texian to the British authorities, to be conveyed, at the expense of the British government, to some one of the British colonies in the West In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dies; and in regard to Texian vessels detained on the coast of Bra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zil, or on the coast of Africa, it is further agreed that, in order that any slave found on board such vessels may not be exposed to the sufferings which would attend a voyage to Texas, such slaves shall, notwithstanding any thing to the contrary in Articles VI and VII of this treaty, be carried or sent, at once, by the commander of the capturing cruizer, to one of the British settlements on the coast of Africa, the vessel herself being sent on to Galveston for adjudica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<pb n="898" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xix" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVII.</head>
<p>The acts or instruments annexed to this treaty, and which it is mutually agreed shall form an integral part thereof, are as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:&#8212;</p>
<p>A. Forms of warrants to authorize, and of orders to guide, the cruizers of either nation, in making visits and detentions under this treaty.</p>
<p>B. Instructions for the cruizers of the respective Navies, em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed, under this treaty, to prevent the African Slave Trade.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVIII.</head>
<p>The present treaty, consisting of eighteen Articles, shall be rati<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, and the ratifications thereof shall be exchanged at London, in nine months from this date, or sooner if possible.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentiaries have signed the same, and have affixed thereto the seals of their arms.</p>
<p>Done at London, the sixteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON. [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>PALMERSTON. [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">ANNEX A.</head>
<p>To the Treaty between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, for the suppression of African Slave Trade, signed at London, November 16th, 1840.</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">FORM I.</head>
<p>Warrant, in virtue of which a cruizer of either of the high con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracting parties may visit and detain a merchant vessel belonging to, or bearing the flag of the other, and suspected of African Slave Trade, or of being fitted out for it.</p>
<p>Whereas, by a treaty between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, signed at London, on the 16th. of November, 1840, for the total extinction of the African Slave Trade, it was<pb n="899" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xx" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> stipulated that certain cruizers belonging to the said countries respectively, shall be authorized, under the special instructions thereto annexed, to visit and detain, within particular limits, mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chant vessels of the other contracting party, engaged in the African Slave trade, or suspected of being fitted out for that traffic: and</p>
<p>Whereas, the Government of ______ has thought fit that the ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel you command shall be one of the ______ cruizers furnished with the said special instructions, and you will accordingly re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive instructions from the said Government for your guidance on the said service;</p>
<p>You are, therefore, authorized and empowered, by virtue of those instructions, and of this present warrant, to visit merchant vessels under the ______ flag, suspected of being engaged in the African Slave Trade, within the limits set forth in the second article of the aforesaid treaty, and to deal with such vessels as shall have en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged in the African Slave Trade, or shall be suspected of being fitted out for that traffic, as pointed out in the said treaty, and in the instructions thereunto annexed.</p>
<p>Given under our hands, and the seal of the Office of Admiralty, this ______ day of ______ 18&#8212;.</p>
<p>(Signature.)</p>
<p>To the Commander of the ______ ship, the &#8220;______&#8221;</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">FORM II.</head>
<p>Order for the guidance of the commander of the cruizer of either of the high contracting parties, in visiting and detaining a mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chant vessel belonging to, or bearing the flag of the other.</p>
<p>Whereas, by a treaty between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, signed at London, on the 16th. of November, 1840, for the total extinction of the African Slave Trade, it was stipulated that certain cruizers belonging to the said countries respectively, should be authorized, under the special instructions thereto annexed, to visit and detain, within particular limits, mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chant vessels of the other contracting party, engaged in the African Slave Trade, or suspected of being fitted out for that traffic: and</p>
<p>Whereas, we think fit that the vessel you command shall be one of the ______ cruizers furnished with the said special instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions:</p>
<p>We, herewith, transmit to you a copy of the said treaty, and of the instructions thereto annexed; and you are accordingly authorized<pb n="900" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> and empowered, by virtue of this present order, and of the accompanying warrant from the Government of ______, to visit, within the limits set forth in the second article of the afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said treaty, merchant vessels under the _____ flag, suspected of being engaged in the African Slave Trade, and to deal with such vessels as shall have engaged in the said traffic, or shall be suspected of being fitted out for that traffic, in the manner pointed out in the said treaty, instructions and warrant; and we charge and require you to conform most strictly to all the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions and stipulations contained therein, taking care to exercise the authority so conferred upon you in the mildest manner, and with every attention which is due between allied and friendly na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and to co-operate cordially with the commanders of any ______ vessels of war employed in the same service.</p>
<p>Given under our hands, the ______ day of ______ 18&#8212;.</p>
<p>(Signature.)</p>
<p>To the Commander of the ______ ship, the &#8220;______&#8221;</p>
<p>These forms of warrants and orders shall be annexed to the treaty signed this day between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, for the suppression of African Slave Trade, and shall be considered as an integral part of that treaty.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective plenipotentiaries have signed the present annex, and have affixed thereto the seals of their arms. Done at London, the sixteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON, [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>PALMERSTON, [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">ANNEX B.</head>
<p>To the Treaty between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, for the suppression of the African Slave Trade; signed at London, November 16th, 1840.</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INSTRUCTIONS TO CRUIZERS.</head>
<p>First.&#8212;Whenever a merchant vessel belonging to, or bear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the flag of either of the high contracting parties to the treaty of this date, shall be visited by a cruizer of the other, the officer commanding the cruizer shall, before he proceeds to the visit, exhibit to the master of such vessel, the special orders which confer upon him, by exception, the right to visit her; and he<pb n="901" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw> shall deliver to such master a certificate signed by himself, specify<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing his rank in the navy of his country, with the name of the ship which he commands, and declaring that the only object of his visit is to ascertain whether the vessel is engaged in the African Slave Trade, or is fitted out for the purpose of such traffic, or has been engaged in the said traffic during the voyage in which she is met with by the said cruizer. When the visit is made by an officer of the cruizer other than her commander, such officer shall not be un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the rank of lieutenant in the navy, unless he be the officer who, at the time is second in command of the ship by which the visit is made; and, in these cases, such officer shall exhibit to the master of the merchant vessel a copy of the special orders above mentioned, signed by the commander of the cruizer: and shall likewise deliver to such master, a certificate, signed by himself, specifying the rank which he holds in the navy of his country, the name of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mander under whose orders he is acting, the name of the cruizer to which he belongs, and the object of his visit, as herein before re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited.</p>
<p>If it shall be ascertained by the visit, that the ship&#8217;s papers are regular, and her proceedings lawful, the officers shall certify upon the log-book of the vessel, that the visit took place in virtue of the special orders, above mentioned; and these formalities having been completed, the vessel shall be permitted to continue her course.</p>
<p>Secondly.&#8212;If, in consequence of the visit, the officer command<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the cruizer shall be of opinion that there are sufficient grounds for believing that the vessel is engaged in the African Slave Trade, or has been fitted out for that traffic, or has been engaged in that traffic during the voyage in which she is met with by the cruizer; and if he shall, in consequence, determine to detain her, and to have her delivered up for adjudication, he shall forthwith cause a list to be made out, in dpulicate, of all the papers found on board; and he shall sign this list and the duplicate, adding, after his own name, his rank in the navy, and the name of the vessel under his command.</p>
<p>He shall, in like manner, make out and sign, in duplicate, a declaration, stating the place and time of the detention, the name of the vessel, and that of her master, the names of the persons com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posing her crew, and the number and condition of the slaves found on board.</p>
<p>This declaration shall further contain an exact description of the state of the vessel and of her cargo.</p>
<p>Thirdly. &#8212; The commander of the cruizer shall, without<pb n="902" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxiii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> delay, carry or send this detained vessel, with her master, crew, passengers, cargo, and the slaves found on board, to one of the ports or places hereinafter specified, in order that proceedings may be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted in regard to them, conformably to the laws of the country under whose flag the vessel is sailing; and he shall deliver the same to the competent authorities or to the persons who shall have been specially appointed for that purpose, by the Government within whose territory such port or place shall be.</p>
<p>Fourthly.&#8212;No person whatever shall be taken out of the detained vessel; nor shall any part of her cargo, nor any of the slaves found on board, be removed from her until after such vessel shall have been delivered over to the authorities of her own nation&#8212;excepting in the cases otherwise provided for in the treaty to which these in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions form an annex, or in the present instructions; or unless the removal of the whole, or of part, of the crew, or of the slaves found on board, shall be deemed necessary, either for the preserva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of their lives, or from any other consideration of humanity, or for the safety of the persons who shall be charged with the navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation of the vessel after her detention. In any such case, the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mander of the cruizer, or the officer appointed to bring in the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained vessel, shall make a declaration of such removal, in which he shall specify the reasons for the same; and, except as otherwise provided for with respect to slaves in the said treaty, or in these instructions, the master, sailors, passengers, or slaves so removed, shall be carried to the same port or place as the vessel and her cargo; and they shall be received in the same manner as the ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel, agreeably to the regulations hereinafter set forth.</p>
<p>Fifthly: &#8212; All Texian vessels which shall be detained by the cruizers of Great Britain in consequence of being engaged in the African Slave Trade, shall be carried and delivered up to the Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ian jurisdiction at Galveston. But any slaves found on board of Texian vessels detained on the coast of Brazil, or on the coast of Africa, whether by a British or by a Texian cruiser, under the treaty to which these instructions form an annex, shall at once be carried or sent by the commander of the capturing cruizer, to one of the British settlements on the coast of Africa. And any slaves found on board of Texian vessels detained in the West Indies, whether by a British or Texian cruizer, under the treaty to which these instructions form an annex, shall, together with the vessels so detained, be carried and delivered up to the Texian authorities at Galveston to be disposed of, after adjudication, according to the provisions of the said treaty.</p>
<pb n="903" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxiv" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
<p>All British vessels which shall be detained by the cruizers of Texas, in consequence of being engaged in the African Slave Trade, shall, together with the slaves found on board be carried and deliv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered up to the British jurisdiction at Bathurst on the river Gambia, if taken off the coast of Africa; or at Port Royal in Jamaica, if taken in the West Indies.</p>
<p>Sixthly:&#8212;As soon as a merchant vessel, which shall have been detained as aforesaid, shall arrive at one of the ports or places above mentioned, the commander of the cruizer, or the officer appointed to bring in such detained vessel, shall forthwith deliver to the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorities duly appointed for that purpose by the Government with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in whose territory such place shall be, the vessel and her cargo, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the master, crew, and passengers, and the slaves found on board, unless such slaves shall have been carried or sent to an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other port or place as hereinbefore directed, and also the papers which shall have been seized on board the vessel, and one of the duplicate lists of the said papers, retaining the other in his own possession, such officer shall at the same time deliver to the said authorities, one of the declarations made out in duplicate, as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inbefore specified, adding thereto a statement of any changes which may have taken place, from the time of the detention of the vessel to that of the delivery, as well as a copy of the statement of any removals which may have taken place, as above provided for.</p>
<p>In delivering over these several documents, the officers shall make, in writing, and on oath, an attestation of their truth.</p>
<p>Seventhly:&#8212;If the commander of a cruizer of either of the high contracting parties, who shall be duly furnished with the aforesaid special instructions, shall have reason to suspect that a merchant vessel, sailing under convoy of, or in company with, a ship of war of the other party, is engaged in the African Slave Trade, or has been fitted out for the purpose of that traffic, or has been engaged in the said traffic during the voyage in which she is met with by the said cruizer, he shall confine himself to communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cating his suspicions to the commander of the ship of war, and he shall leave it to the latter to proceed alone to visit the suspected vessel, and to deliver her up to the jurisdiction of her own country, if there should be cause for doing so.</p>
<p>These instructions shall be annexed to the treaty signed this day between the Republic of Texas and Great Britain, for the suppres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of African Slave Trade, and shall be considered as an integral part of that treaty.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentiaries have signed the present annex, and have affixed thereto the seals of their arms.</p>
<pb n="904" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw>
<p>Done at London, the sixteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thosand eight hundred and forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON, [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>PALMERSTON, [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>And whereas, the said Treaty as well as the forms of Warrants and Instructions thereto annexed, have been ratified on both parts, and the respective ratifications of the same exchanged at London, on the twenty-eighth day of June, one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, by Ashbel Smith, Minister Charg&#233; d&#8217;Affaires of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, and the Earl of Aberdeen, Her Majesty&#8217;s Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, on the part of their respective Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, be it known, that I, SAM. HOUSTON, Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Republic of Texas, have caused the said Treaty and forms of Warrants and Instructions to cruizers, to be made public, to the end that the same, and every clause and article contained therein may be observed and fulfilled with good faith by the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas, and the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have caused the Great Seal of the Republic to be affixed, and hereunto set my hand. Done at the City of Houston, the sixteenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, and of the Independence of Texas the seventh.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> JOSEPH WAPLES,<lb/> Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="905" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxvi" />
</div1>
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION.</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>To all and singular to whom these presents shall come,&#8212;Greeting:</p>
<p>Whereas, a Treaty of Amity, Commerce and Navigation, between the Republic of Texas and His Majesty the King of the Nether<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lands was concluded and signed by the Plenipotentiaries of the two countries, at the Hague, on the 18th day of September, one thousand eight hundred and forty, which treaty is, word for word, as follows:&#8212;</p>
<p>The Republic of Texas and His Majesty the King of the Nether<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lands, desiring to regulate the relations of Commerce and Navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation between the two countries, and to consolidate and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect their mutual interest by means of a Treaty of Friendship, Commerce and Navigation, have appointed Plenipotentiaries for that purpose, namely: The President of the Republic of Texas, James Hamilton, Esquire; and His Majesty the King of the Netherlands, John Gisbert Baron Verstolk de Soelen, Member of the Body of Nobles of the Province of Holland, Knight Grand Cross of the Orders of the Netherland Lion, of Saint Stephen of Hungary, of Nichan Istihar of the Ottoman Porte, of Christ of Portugal, of Charles III. of Spain, and of the Crown of Wertem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />berg, His Minister of State, holding the Department of Foreign Affairs:&#8212;who, after exchange of their respective full powers, found in good order, have agreed upon the following articles:</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<p>There shall be a firm and sincere friendship between the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas and His Majesty the King of the Netherlands, his heirs and successors, and between the citizens and subjects of the two states, without exception of persons and places.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<p>There shall be reciprocal liberty of commerce and naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion between and amongst the subjects of His Majesty the King<pb n="906" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxvii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> of the Netherlands and the citizens of the Republic of Texas, and the said subjects and citizens respectively shall not pay in the ports, harbors, roads, cities towns or places whatsoever in either of the two countries, any other or higher duties, taxes or imposts, under what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />soever names designated or included, than those which are there paid by the subjects of the most favored nation; and the subjects and the citizens of both contracting parties shall enjoy the same rights, privileges, liberties, favors, immunities and exemptions in matters of commerce and navigation, that are granted or may hereafter be granted in the states of either of the two contracting parties to the subjects of the most favored nation.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<p>The inhabitants of both countries, respectively, shall enjoy lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty and security to proceed with their ships and cargoes, to all places, ports and rivers where other foreigners are at present or shall be in future admitted, and to remain and reside in any part of the said possessions and states, and also to hire and occupy houses and warehouses for the purpose of their trade.</p>
<p>In like manner the ships of war of both countries respectively shall have the same liberty freely and securely to touch at all ports, rivers and places where the ships of war of any other nation are per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted or shall in future be permitted to enter; subject however to the laws and statutes of the respective countries.</p>
<p>In the right mentioned in this article to enter all places, ports and rivers is not included that of trading from port to port, nor the coasting trade, (cabotage,) which is allowed only to national ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IV.</head>
<p>Vessels of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands arriving at or sailing out of the ports of Texas, and vessels of the Republic of Texas on their entry into the ports of the Netherlands, shall not be subject to other or higher duties of tonnage, of light-money, port charges or pilotage, quarantine, or any other affecting the body of the vessel, than those which are paid, or shall be paid, by the ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel of the country itself.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE V.</head>
<p>Goods and merchandize, whatever their origin may be, im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="907" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxviii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>ported into or exported from the ports of the Netherlands in Eu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rope from or into the ports of the Republic of Texas, in vessels of the Netherlands, shall pay no higher or other duties than shall be levied on the like goods and merchandize so imported or exported in national vessels.</p>
<p>And reciprocally, goods and merchandize, whatever their origin may be, imported into or exported from the ports of the Republic of Texas, from or into the ports of the Netherlands in Europe, in vessels of the said Republic, shall pay no higher or other duties than shall be levied on the like goods and merchandize so imported, or exported, in national vessels.</p>
<p>The bounties, drawbacks, or other favors of this nature which may be granted in the states of either of the contracting parties, on goods imported or exported in national vessels, shall also and in like manner be granted on goods directly imported or exported in vessels of the other country, to and from the ports of the two countries, it being understood that in the latter as in the preced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing case, the goods shall have been loaded in the ports from which such vessels have been cleared.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VI.</head>
<p>No duty of customs or other impost shall be charged upon any goods the produce of one country, upon importation, higher than the duty or impost charged upon goods of the same kind the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duce of or imported from any other country: and His Majesty the King of the Netherlands and the Republic of Texas do hereby bind and engage themselves not to grant any favor, privilege or immun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity in matters of commerce and navigation to the subjects of any other state which shall not be also and at the same time extended to the subjects and citizens of the other contracting party, gratuit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ously if the concession in favor of that other state shall have been gratuitous, and on giving as nearly as possible the same compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or equivalent in case the concession shall have been condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional. In such a case the matter will be made the object of a par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticular convention between the contracting parties. The Dutch spirituous liquors shall not be subjected to higher duties than those of the most favored nations.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VII.</head>
<p>The contracting parties agree to consider and treat respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ively as vessels of the King of the Netherlands, and as vessels, of the Republic of Texas, all such as being furnished by the<pb n="908" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxix" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> competent authority with a passport or sea letter, shall under the then existing laws and regulations be recognized as national ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels by the country to which they belong.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VIII.</head>
<p>The subjects of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands in the Netherlands colonies, and the products of those colonies shall enjoy in Texas all the advantages which are, or shall be granted to the most favored nations.</p>
<p>Reciprocally the citizens and products of Texas shall enjoy in the colonies of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands all the advantages which are or shall be granted to the most favored na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of Europe and America.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IX.</head>
<p>All traders, shipmasters and other subjects of his said Majesty shall have full liberty in the Republic of Texas to conduct their own business themselves or to entrust the management thereof to whomsoever they may choose, either ship-agent, brokers, agent or interpreter, and they shall not be obliged to employ other persons for that purpose, or to pay them higher salaries or remuneration than in similar cases are employed or paid by natives. In like manner buyer and seller shall be at full liberty in all cases to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late and fix at their option, the price of imported or exported goods and merchandize of whatever kind, conforming themselves to the established laws and customs of the country. The same privilege shall be enjoyed under the like conditions by the citizens of Texas in the possessions of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE X.</head>
<p>In all what relates to the police of the ports, to the loading and unloading of ships, and the security of goods, merchandizes and wares, the subjects and citizens of the contracting parties recipro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cally shall be subject to the laws and local regulations of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try where they reside.</p>
<p>They shall be free of all forced military service, by land or by sea, no forced loans shall exclusively be imposed upon them, and their property shall be subject to no other charges, demands or tax, than what is paid by the natives of the country itself.</p>
<pb n="909" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxx" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XI.</head>
<p>The subjects and citizens of the contracting parties shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciprocally enjoy the most complete and constant protection with respect to their persons, houses and property. They shall have a free and ready access to the courts of justice, for the prosecution and defence of their rights. They shall be at liberty to employ the advocates, attorneys or agents of whatever denomination, whom they may choose, and in general in the administration of justice, and also with regard to all that concerns the inheritance of per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal property, by will or otherwise, and the faculty of disposing either by sale, gift, exchange, will or any other manner, of personal property, they shall enjoy the same privileges and freedoms as the natives of the country where they reside: and in neither of these cases or circumstances shall heavier taxes or charges be imposed on them than are imposed on the natives.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XII.</head>
<p>The subjects of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding in the Republic of Texas, shall not be in any way molested on account of their religion; it being understood that they on their part shall respect that of the country, together with its constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, laws and customs. They shall also have the privilege of inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment in the places set apart for that purpose for the subjects of His Majesty dying in the Republic of Texas, and the funerals and burying grounds shall in nowise be molested under any pretext.</p>
<p>The citizens of Texas in all the possessions of His Majesty shall have the free exercise of their religion, whether in public or in private, in their own dwellings or in edifices destined for public worship, and all and everything according to the principle of uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versal toleration established by the fundamental law of the king<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dom.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XIII.</head>
<p>With a view of greater security in the intercourse between the subjects and citizens of the two contracting parties, it is more<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />over agreed, that should at any time the friendly relations that now exist between them be disturbed, the merchants that reside on the coast shall be allowed six months, and those that reside inland a full year to arrange their affairs and to dispose of their<pb n="910" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxxi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas</fw> property, and they shall also receive safe conduct to embark in whatever port they may choose.</p>
<p>All the other subjects and citizens residing in the respective territories, for the exercise of any traffic or special business, shall have the privilege to remain, and continue such traffic without being in any manner disturbed in the complete enjoyment of their liberty and of their property, so long as they shall conduct them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves peaceably, and not commit any offence against the laws of the country, their property and effects of whatever nature shall not be subject to seizure or sequestration, nor to any charge or imposition than such as occur with respect to natives.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XIV.</head>
<p>It is further agreed between the two contracting parties, that the Consuls and Vice Consuls of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands, in the ports of Texas, and reciprocally those of the Republic of Texas within the dominions of His Majesty the King of the Netherlands in Europe, shall enjoy all those rights, privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leges and immunities which are accorded to such functionaries by the law of nations, and that in the ports of each country respective<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly the authorities shall give all due legal assistance and protection, for the apprehension, safe-keeping and delivery of all deserters from private or public vessels of either country, as the case may be; and all the powers and privileges given by the contracting par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties to other nations, shall belong to both, reciprocally, as it re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gards the apprehension, safe-keeping and delivery of such deserters.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XV.</head>
<p>In case of average or of shipwreck, the like protection and as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistance shall reciprocally be afforded to the vessels of the two con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracting parties, as are enjoyed by the vessels of the country in which the accident occurs.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVI.</head>
<p>Should one of the contracting parties be at war it shall be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed to the subjects or citizens of the other to prosecute their commerce and navigation with the exception only of contraband goods, and of such places as are actually under seige, or are block<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aded by billigerent powers with a force adequate to prevent the neutral from entering.</p>
<pb n="911" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxxii" /><fw type="header" place="top">and Great Britain.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVII.</head>
<p>By contraband shall be understood guns, mortars, firearms, pis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tols, bomb shells, grenades, shot, muskets, flints, matches, powder, shields, pikes, swords, accountrements, pouches, saddles, bridles, &#38;c., except such quantities of these articles as are necessary for the defence of the vessel and the crew.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XVIII.</head>
<p>In cases where a merchant ship of one of the contracting parties may be searched by a ship of war of the other, it is agreed that the search shall only be made by a boat manned with at most six men, that the master of the merchant vessel shall not be obliged to quit his ship, and that the papers shall not be taken from on board.</p>
<p>If the merchant vessel is under convoy of a ship of war, no search shall take place, and the assurance of the commandant of the convoy on his word of honor that the merchant vessel has no contraband on board shall be held sufficient.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XIX.</head>
<p>In the ports of the neutral party, the vessel of war of the other, and the prizes which she carries in there, shall meet with all that aid and protection which are compatible with the law of nations.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XX.</head>
<p>In case the contracting parties should at any time mutually be at war with a third power, it is stipulated that the ships of war of the one party shall convoy the merchant vessels of the other as often as they hold the same course; that the prizes made by the ships of war of the one, shall be admitted in the ports of the other, and may be sold there, after legal adjudication, and that in case of recapture by the one of prizes made on the other by the enemy, the same shall be restored to the original owner, deducting in favor of the vessel recapturing not more than one-eighth of the value, in case the recapture was made by a ship of war, or of one-sixth if made by a privateer.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XXI.</head>
<p>The present treaty shall be in force for the term of eight years,<pb n="912" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xxxiii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Treaty Between Texas, &#38;c.</fw> commencing three months after the exchange of the ratifications, and further until the end of twelve months, after either of the contracting parties shall have given to the other notice of its in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tention to terminate the same: each of the contracting parties re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serves to itself the right of giving such notice to the other after the expiration of the said term of eight years; and it is hereby mutually agreed that in case of such notice, this treaty and all the provisions thereof shall, at the end of the said twelve months, altogether cease and determine.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE XXII.</head>
<p>The present treaty shall be ratified, and the ratifications shall be exchanged at the Hague, within nine months of its date, or sooner if practicable.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentaries have signed the same, and have affixed thereto the seals of their arms.</p>
<p>Done at the Hague, this eighteenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. HAMILTON. [L. S.]</signed>
<signed>VERSTOLK VAN SOELEN. [L. S.]</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>And whereas the said treaty has been duly ratified on both parts, and the respective ratifications of the same were exchanged at the Hague, on the fifteenth day of June, one thousand eight hundred and forty-one, by the duly authorized Plenipotentiaries of their respective governments:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, be it known, that I, SAM. HOUSTON, Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Republic of Texas, have caused the same to be made public, to the end that every clause and article thereof may be ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served and fulfilled with good faith by the Republic of Texas, and the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto signed my name and caused the great seal of the Republic to be affixed. Done at the town of Washington, this fourth day of January, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and forty-three, and of the Inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendence of Texas the seventh.</p>
<closer>
<signed>SAM. HOUSTON.</signed>
<signed>By the President:<lb/> ANSON JONES,<lb/> Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
