<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1715" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="409" />
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">PRIVATE LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To Legalize the Marriage of Samuel M. Parry with Elizabeth Neese, and Legitimating certain Children therein named, the issue of said Marriage.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the rights of matrimony heretofore celebrated be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween Samuel M. Parry and Elizabeth Neese, be, and the same are hereby declared to be valid in law, as though at the time of the celebration of said marriage no legal disability existed thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the following named child<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ren, the issue of said marriage, to wit: Samuel, Mary, Catharine, Rosand, John, William, David and Martha, be, and they are hereby declared the lawful heirs of the said Samuel M. Parry and Eliza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />beth Neese his wife, any legal disability existing at the time of their birth to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>4th April, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting the Honorable John Hemphill, Chief Justice of the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court, leave of absence from the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John Hemphill, chief justice of the supreme<pb n="1716" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="410" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> court, shall have leave of absence from this State from the month of May until the first Monday of November next, or until the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencement of the fall session of the supreme court.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>27th April, 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the Relief of James Gilliam, assignee of Jesse Billingsly.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent to James Gilliam, as assignee of Jesse Billingsly, upon a certificate for one league of land, issued to said Jesse Billingsly by the board of land commissioners of Bas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trop county, under the provisions of &#8220;an act making provisions for persons who have been permanently disabled in the service of Texas,&#8221; approved December 18th, 1837.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>27th April, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize E. G. Rector to sell and transfer his six hundred and forty acres of Donation Land, to which he is entitled for having participated in the Battle of San Jacinto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That E. G. Rector be, and he is hereby authorized to sell and transfer his six hundred and forty acres of donation land, to which he is entitled for having participated in the battle of San Jacinto, on the 20th of April, 1836, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>29th April, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="1717" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="411" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of John Karner.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office, be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent to John Karner for one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land, the same being his head right, which was not recommended by the traveling board of land commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>7th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a Patent to Joseph McGee.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a patent on certificate number two hundred and forty, as issued by the board of land commissioners for Jasper county, on the 10th day of January, A. D. 1840, to Joseph McGee, a native born citizen, for three thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand one hundred and twenty-nine (3129) acres, instead of three hundred and sixty-nine, (369,) it being the remainedr of said Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Gee&#8217;s headright league and labor of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>7th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="1718" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="412" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of Charles B. Snow.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the comptroller of public accounts is hereby required to respect the claim of Charles B. Snow, late lieutenant of the navy, of Texas, for the sum of eight hundred and sixteen dollars, the amount to which he was entitled under the act of congress, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved 5th February, A. D. 1844, entitled &#8220;an act making appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation for part pay of officers and seamen of the navy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the comptroller shall issue certificates to the said Charles B. Snow, in amounts of not less than twenty dollars, which may be transferred by said Snow, and shall be receivable in the hands of any person for dirct taxes due the Government, previous to the first of January, 1846.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Vetoed by the Governor, and passed by a constitutional ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority, <date>May 9th, 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of Thomas Anderson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to correct the field notes of league No. 17, granted to Thomas Anderson, in accordance with the intention of the survey, as evidenced by the plat or diagram, and to make a note of such corrections on the original title on file in his office: Provided, that nothing herein contained shall preju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dice the rights of third persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>11th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="1719" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="413" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of the heirs of John G. Welchmeyer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the board of land commissioners for the county of Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />risburg, having issued to John G. Welchmeyer his headright certificate for one league and labor of land, and whereas the board of traveling commissioners having rejected the same upon the ground that the former husband of the wife of the said John G. Welchmeyer having drawn the same quantity of land, and whereas the constitution of the Republic of Texas plainly and expressly declares that every head of a family shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to one league and one labor of land, and that the said J. G. Welchmeyer, by virtue of his marriage is, in the language of the constitution, the head of a family, and in order to protect and secure to the heirs their constitutional rights, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to the heirs of John G. Welchmeyer the headright certificate of the said Welchmeyer, for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>11th May, 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of Andrew J. Yates.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby required to respect as valid, land certificate No. 641, issued by the board of land commissioners for Bexar county, to Andrew J. Yates, assignee of Juan Fran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cisco Bueno, upon the presentation and file in his office of a certified copy of the decree of the district court of Bexar county, bearing date 19th day of April, 1839, ordering the<pb n="1720" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="414" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> issuing of said certificate, and issue patent thereon as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>12th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requiring the Comptroller of the State of Texas to settle certain accounts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the comptroller be, and he is hereby required to settle the accounts of E. W. Moore, post captain, commanding the late navy of Texas, for disbursements of money received from the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of Yucatan, and for supplies of provisions and stores fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished the navy, while in active service, in command of the mari<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />time force of the Republic, as well as all the accounts for monies received by him from the Government of Texas and other sources, and report his action to the next legislature of the State for their final ratification.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>13th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of Nathaniel Amory.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, drafts of fifty dollars each, receivable in payment of direct taxes, were issued to Nathaniel Amory in conformity with an act of Congress, approved January 27, 1845; and whereas, all of the said drafts, except twelve, have been returned to the treasury for taxes; and whereas, proof has been produced that ten of the aforesaid twelve were stolen from the agent of the said Amory; Therefore,</p>
<pb n="1721" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="415" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the comptroller of public accounts be authorized and required to give public notice, that if the said stolen drafts be not returned to the treasury of this State, or reported to the said comptroller by the holders of the same, within ninety days from and after the date of such notice, the said ten stolen drafts or the portion of same unreturned, or unreported, shall be considered as cancelled, and that the same shall not be thereafter received in payment of any public dues; and moreover, that the comptroller be authorized after the expiration of said term of notice, to issue to said Nath<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aniel Amory drafts for the amount of the unreturned or unre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ported portion of said ten stolen drafts, which new drafts so issued, shall be receivable for any dues in payment of which those in place of which they are issued, would have been valid: Provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, that if any of said stolen drafts should have been or should be received by any collector of taxes in payment of the same, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the aforesaid term of notice shall have expired, such drafts, so received, shall be receivable into the treasury of the State on satisfactory proof of the time of their collection being made to the comptroller of public accounts; And provided also, that the drafts which may be issued by the comptroller, according to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, shall be receivable for taxes and dues to the late Republic of Texas, and not otherwise.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>15th May, 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of Milton Hicks.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the land certificate No. 718, issued by the board of land commissioners of Brazoria county, in favor of Milton Hicks, for one league of land, signed by Edwin Waller, president, and A. C. Hyde, associate commissioner, be, and the same is hereby legalized, and the same be as valid as if recommended by the traveling board of land commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the certificate may be laid on any vacant and unappropriated land in this State,<pb n="1722" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="416" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and the commissioner of the general land office is hereby directed to issue a patent for such land, when located, as in other cases of valid claims.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>18th May, A. D. 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<signed>O<smcap>FFICE</smcap> OF S<smcap>ECBETARY</smcap> OF S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</signed>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>I, the undersigned, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify, that the first Legislature of the State aforesaid commenced its session at the city of Austin, on Monday, the 16th day of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, 1846, and adjourned on the 13th day of May, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and forty-six.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>Given under my hand and seal of Office, at Austin, the 10th day of August, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and forty-six.</p>
<signed>DAVID. G. BURNET.</signed>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE 1. All the words, wherever they occur, included in brack<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ets, thus: [ * * * * * *?] are inserted by direction of the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State, and are not in the text.</p>
<p>NOTE 2. Those laws that were signed by the Governor are designated by the word &#8220;Approved&#8221;&#8212;those not signed by him, are said to be &#8220;Passed.&#8221;</p>
<pb n="1723" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="417" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX</head>
<byline>TO THE GENERAL LAWS.</byline>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Arbitration or Conciliation, Disputes settled by 127</p>
<p>Attorney General, Duties of 206</p>
<p>Attorneys and Counsellors at Law, to regulate License and Practice of 245</p>
<p>Austin City, Relief of Purchasers of Lots in 167</p>
<p>Austin City, Incorporated 285</p>
<p>Administrators, Records of transferred to new Counties 294</p>
<p>Appropriations for the support of Government 343</p>
<p>Adjutant General&#8217;s Office, Seal of 346</p>
<p>Bribery, punished by exclusion from office 36</p>
<p>Bills, Cheeks, &#38;c., Issuing of to pass as money, prohibited 53</p>
<p>Briefs, filed in Supreme Court taken as appearance of Plaint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iff or Defendant 133</p>
<p>Boards of Land Commissioners, Official acts of legalized 163</p>
<p>County of Anderson, created 20</p>
<p>&#8220; Anderson, to pay a portion of the debt of Houston county 182</p>
<p>&#8220; Angelina, created 120</p>
<p>&#8220; Austin, Seat of Justice of 22</p>
<p>&#8220; Burleson, created 16</p>
<p>&#8220; Burleson, to pay a portion of the debt of Milam County 142</p>
<p>&#8220; Brazoria, Boundaries of 18</p>
<p>&#8220; Brazoria, County Court of, to have a duplicate made of the records contained in Book C 291</p>
<p>&#8220; Comal, created 13</p>
<pb n="1724" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="418" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>&#8220; County of Comal, Seat of Justice of 14</p>
<p>&#8220; Collin, created 44</p>
<p>&#8220; Calhoun, created 48</p>
<p>&#8220; Calhoun, Seat of Justice of 41</p>
<p>&#8220; Cherokee, created 63</p>
<p>&#8220; Cass, created 135</p>
<p>&#8220; De Witt, created, 18</p>
<p>&#8220; De Witt, Seat of Justice of 14</p>
<p>&#8220; Dallas, created 26</p>
<p>&#8220; Dallas, Seat of Justice of 93</p>
<p>&#8220; Dallas, Election of Officers for 242</p>
<p>&#8220; Denton, created 57</p>
<p>&#8220; Fannin, boundaries of 6</p>
<p>&#8220; Fannin, Debt of, apportioned 166</p>
<p>&#8220; Fort Bend, boundaries of 15</p>
<p>&#8220; Guadalupe, created 33</p>
<p>&#8220; Guadalupe, Seat of Justice of 14</p>
<p>&#8220; Grayson, created 7</p>
<p>&#8220; Grimes, created 50</p>
<p>&#8220; Grimes, Seat of Justice of 125</p>
<p>&#8220; Grimes, to pay portion of debt of Montgomery 140</p>
<p>&#8220; Hopkins, created 24</p>
<p>&#8220; Hunt, created 58</p>
<p>&#8220; Henderson, created 141</p>
<p>&#8220; Jackson, boundaries of 37</p>
<p>&#8220; Leon, created 8</p>
<p>&#8220; Leon, Seat of Justice of 242</p>
<p>&#8220; Lavaca, created 49</p>
<p>&#8220; Lavaca, Seat of Justice of 47</p>
<p>&#8220; Lavaca, to pay portion of debt of Colorado 228</p>
<p>&#8220; Limestone, created 72</p>
<p>&#8220; Limestone, Seat of Justice of 92</p>
<p>&#8220; Limestone, to pay one-fourth of Debt of Robert<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son 119</p>
<p>&#8220; Matagorda, Boundaries of 34</p>
<p>&#8220; Milam, Seat of Justice of 45</p>
<p>&#8220; Milam, Western Boundary of 259</p>
<p>&#8220; Nueces, created 90</p>
<p>&#8220; Nacogdoches, Boundaries of 93</p>
<p>&#8220; Nacogdoches, New Counties taken from territory of, to pay portion of Debt 327</p>
<p>&#8220; Newton, created 122</p>
<p>&#8220; Newton, to pay portion of Debt of Jasper 178</p>
<pb n="1725" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="419" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>County of Navarro, created 132</p>
<p>&#8220; Polk, created 27</p>
<p>&#8220; Polk and Tyler to pay portion of Debt of Liberty 149</p>
<p>&#8220; Panola, created 31</p>
<p>&#8220; Panola, Seat of Justice of 166</p>
<p>&#8220; Panola and Upshur, Duties of Cimmissioners to lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate County Seats of 181</p>
<p>&#8220; Paschal, Treasurer to pay over all money in his hands 179</p>
<p>&#8220; Rusk, Map of 21</p>
<p>&#8220; Robertson, Boundaries of 60</p>
<p>&#8220; Robertson, Concerning Roads in 145</p>
<p>&#8220; Smith, created 55</p>
<p>&#8220; San Patricio, established 86</p>
<p>&#8220; San Patricio and Nueces, organized 154</p>
<p>&#8220; Tyler, created 42</p>
<p>&#8220; Tyler, Courts to be holden at Town Bluff 151</p>
<p>&#8220; Titus, created 198</p>
<p>&#8220; Titus, to pay portion of Debt of Red River 227</p>
<p>&#8220; Upshur, created 139</p>
<p>&#8220; Victoria, Boundaries of 35</p>
<p>&#8220; Victoria, De Witt, Lavaca, Jackson and Calhoun, Conflicting rights of settled 124</p>
<p>&#8220; Wharton, created 38</p>
<p>&#8220; Wharton, Seat of Justice of 39</p>
<p>&#8220; Wharton, to pay portion of debt of Colorado and Matagorda 88</p>
<p>&#8220; Walker, created 51</p>
<p>Counties, Organization of 74</p>
<p>&#8220; Incorporation of the several 320</p>
<p>County Surveyors, to record certain Field Notes 164</p>
<p>&#8220; Lines, manner of running 231</p>
<p>&#8220; Courts, Organized 333</p>
<p>&#8220; Treasurer, Office of regulated 338</p>
<p>Custom Houses, ceded to United States 35</p>
<p>Customs, incurred under the Laws of the Republic, secured to the State of Texas 86</p>
<p>Census, to be taken 62</p>
<p>Comptroller of Public Accounts, Duties of 68</p>
<p>Conservators of the Peace, officially named and designated 84</p>
<p>Corpus Christi, established and Incorporated 130</p>
<p>Comm&#8217;r Gen. Land Office, Seals heretofore used by, legalized 151</p>
<pb n="1726" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="420" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Comm&#8217;r Gen. Land Office, to issue patents in the name of the State 169</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To issue patents for land lying in two or more counties 188</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To issue patents for Scrip located in two surveys 52</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To issue patents on unconditional Certificates 260</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To issue patents to Assignees of good and genuine unconditional Head Eight Certificates 264</p>
<p>Chief Justices, to act until their successors are qualified 165</p>
<p>Commissioners, to take acknowledgment of Deeds, &#38;c., to be appointed 187</p>
<p>Constitution and certain Laws to be translated into the Ger<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man and Spanish languages 85</p>
<p>Constables, Duties of 261</p>
<p>Crockett, Town of Incorporated 323</p>
<p>Coroners, Duties 358</p>
<p>District Courts, time of holding postponed 6</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To establish Districts of 59</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Organized and powers defined 200</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding 270</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; and Inferiour Courts, concurrent jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of 292</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Proceedings in, regulated 363</p>
<p>District Attorneys, Duties of 295</p>
<p>Defendants may plead a partial failure of consideration 40</p>
<p>Duval Academy, Incorporated 67</p>
<p>Despatches to be sent for better security of the country 169</p>
<p>Duplicate Land Warrants, &#38;c., act supplementary to act au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorizing the issuing of, repealed 164</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8220; 1st section of act authorizing the issuing of, amended 226</p>
<p>Elections, mode of voting in 12</p>
<p>&#8220; Regulating 209</p>
<p>Enumeration, of inhabitants provided for 62</p>
<p>Frontier, concerning protection of 9</p>
<p>Free Schools, at Galveston, tax levied for support of 30</p>
<p>Forgery and Counterfeiting, Punished 36</p>
<pb n="1727" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="421" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Free Masons, Lodges and Chapters of, Incorporated 144</p>
<p>Forts and Arsenals, ceded to United States 219</p>
<p>Funded Debt, mode of transferring 220</p>
<p>Fugitives, Governor to offer rewards for 92</p>
<p>Field Notes, Copies of made valid 293</p>
<p>Galveston, Corporation of, may levy tax for free schools 30</p>
<p>&#8220; Island and main land, connected 91</p>
<p>Governor, How notified when a private corporation bill has passed 152</p>
<p>&#8220; To take command of troops in person 195</p>
<p>General Land Office, establishment of 232</p>
<p>House of Representatives, manner of organizing 61</p>
<p>Huntsville Academy, Incorporated 65</p>
<p>Household Furniture, &#38;c. $250 worth, exempt from taxation. 76</p>
<p>Herman&#8217;s University, 8th and 11th sections of act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate, amended 78</p>
<p>Indian Tribes, agent to proceed to 168</p>
<p>Juries, in criminal cases to assess fines 161</p>
<p>&#8220; Regulating 170</p>
<p>Jury Fund manner of raising a 184</p>
<p>Jurisdiction, concurrent, given to courts in some cases 292</p>
<p>Justices&#8217; Courts, organized and powers defined 298</p>
<p>Judicial Proceedings, to prevent confusion in 319</p>
<p>Legislature, members of, appropriation for pay and mileage of 5</p>
<p>&#8220; members of, Pay and mileage established 320</p>
<p>&#8220; Contingent expenses of 12</p>
<p>&#8220; Time of meeting of the 73</p>
<p>Lamar Academy, Incorporated 76</p>
<p>Lands sold for Taxes, restored to former owners 138</p>
<p>Laws, Civil and Criminal, to be revised, digested, &#38;c. 161</p>
<p>&#8220; Of the State, publication of 328</p>
<p>La Grange Female Institute, incorporated 229</p>
<p>Land District, composed of San Patricio and Nueces counties. 269</p>
<p>Militia, organization of 94</p>
<p>Mail Contractors, requesting relief for 118</p>
<p>Mail Routes, establishment of, requested 142</p>
<p>Married Women, registration of property of 153</p>
<p>Married women, Mode of conveying property of 156</p>
<p>Minute Men, supplement to acts for relief of 162&#8212;178</p>
<p>Maps, of new counties to be made 199</p>
<p>Moneys due from U. S. Governor to demand 132</p>
<pb n="1728" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="422" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Notaries Public, duties of 341</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Chief Justice of counties to be notified of the appointment of 160</p>
<p>New Braunfels, Incorporated 276</p>
<p>Odd Fellows, Grand Lodge of, incorporated 53</p>
<p>Public Property, ceded to United States 25</p>
<p>Parties to Suits, may Appear in person 26</p>
<p>Perjury, punished by exclusion from office 36</p>
<p>Pilots, regulation of 79</p>
<p>Petitioners, to Legislature, may withdraw vouchers 129</p>
<p>Public Buildings, in Austin, disposed of 134</p>
<p>Patrols, appointment and duties of 191</p>
<p>Penitentiary, establishment of a 221</p>
<p>Purchasers of lots, in Austin, relief of 167</p>
<p>Partnerships, regulated 279</p>
<p>Probate Courts, organized 308</p>
<p>Representatives, to U. S. Congress, election of 3</p>
<p>&#8220; Governor to pay expenses to circulate the law for the election of 78</p>
<p>&#8220; Supplement to act, for election of 117</p>
<p>&#8220; Time of holding elections for 241</p>
<p>Religious Meetings, Protected 123</p>
<p>Revenue, to be raised by direct taxation 146</p>
<p>Right of the State, to jurisdiction over the soil, declaration of. 155</p>
<p>Rail Road, Lavaca, Guadalupe and San Saba, Incorporated 185</p>
<p>Rail Road, Colorado and Wilson Creek, Incorporated 218</p>
<p>Registry of Deeds, &#38;c., provided for 236</p>
<p>State Treasurer, duties of 10</p>
<p>Suits, against the State authorized 134</p>
<p>Secretary of State, duties of 189</p>
<p>Slaves, prevented from hiring their own time 195</p>
<p>Supreme Court, to organize 249</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Briefs filed in, taken as appearance of plaintiff or defendant 133</p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Appeals to, in criminal cases, regulated 330</p>
<p>Sheriffs, duties of 265</p>
<p>Taxation, revenue raised by direct 146</p>
<p>Turnpike Road, from Houston to Brenham 257</p>
<p>Taxes, assessment and collection of, provided for 347</p>
<p>United States, property ceded to 25</p>
<p>United States, Moneys due from, to be demanded by Governor 132</p>
<p>Vacancies, in office, may be filled by Governor 40</p>
<pb n="1729" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="423" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Volunteers, authorized to elect their own officers 318</p>
<p>War and Marine Department, business of, closed 143</p>
<p>Wife&#8217;s Property, mode of conveying 156</p>
<p>Wreck Masters, regulated 158</p>
<p>Weights and Measures, regulated 180</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX</head>
<byline>TO THE PRIVATE LAWS.</byline>
<p>Anderson, Thomas, relief of 412</p>
<p>Amory, Nathaniel, relief of 414</p>
<p>Gilliam, James, assignee of Jesse Billingsly, relief of 410</p>
<p>Hemphill, John, leave of absence granted to 409</p>
<p>Hicks, Milton, relief of 415</p>
<p>Karner, John, relief of 411</p>
<p>McGee, Joseph, relief of 411</p>
<p>Moore, E. W., accounts of, to be settled 414</p>
<p>Parry, Samuel M. and Elizabeth Neise, marriage of, legalized. 409</p>
<p>Rector, E. G., relief of 410</p>
<p>Snow, Charles B., relief of 412</p>
<p>Welschmeyer, J. G., heirs of, relief of 413</p>
<p>Yates, A. J., relief of 413</p>
<pb n="1730" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="424" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
