<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="820" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">ABSTRACT<lb/> OF<lb/> PRIVATE ACTS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS<lb/> PASSED AT A SPECIAL SESSION OF THE SIXTH CONGRESS, CONVENED AND HELD AT THE CITY OF HOUSTON, J<smcap>UNE</smcap> 27th, 1842.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of F. Dawson,&#8221; approved July 19th, 1842&#8212;requires the Secretary of the Treasury to cancel cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain bonds of the Government, held by the said Dawson, and to issue, in lieu thereof, bonds of a smaller denomination.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Thomas Johnson,&#8221; approved July 19th, 1842&#8212;directs the payment, to the said Thomas John<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, late Judge of the first Judicial District, of the sum of $828.00 &#8212;half the salary to which he is by law entitled for the term of six months and nineteen days, during which he served as Judge as aforesaid.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act to divorce certain persons therein named,&#8221; approved July 23d, 1842&#8212;divorces, a vinculo matrimonii, the following per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, that is to say; Francis W. Johnson and Rosella Johnson; Ben<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jamin Conner and Julia E. Conner; Andrew Jackson Morgan and Jane Morgan; Daniel Tuttle and Mary Tuttle; William Mays and Mary Mays; J. C. Weal and Louisa Weal; Dennis Neil and Julia Weil; Henry Tierwester and Ann Tierwester; and Jacob Duckworth and Nancy Duckworth.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>&#8220;An act to divorce Thomas F. McKinney and Nancy McKinney and others from the bonds of matrimony,&#8221; approved July 18th, 1842&#8212;divorces, a vinculo matrimonii, the following persons, that is to say;&#8212;the said Thomas F. McKinney and Haney McKinney; James P. Hutchison and Celia Hutchison; and David Hodges and Lucinda Hodges.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Captain Augustus Williams&#8221; passed by a Constitutional majority, July 23d, 1842&#8212;restores him to his command as Captin of Company<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of Tennessee Volun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teers&#8212;but does not exempt him from trial by a Court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />martial, and punishment, for any mutinous or insubordinate conduct.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
