<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1231" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">THE DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE AND ARTICLES OF CONFEDERATION AND CONSTITUTION OF UNITED STATES</head>
<dateline>1789</dateline>
<pb n="1232" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="1233" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE.</head>
<byline>JULY 4<smcap>TH</smcap>, 1776.</byline>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">THE UNANIMOUS DECLARATION OF THE THIRTEEN UNITED STATES OF AMERICA IN CONGRESS ASSEMBLED.</head>
<p>When, in the course of human events, it becomes necessary for one people to dissolve the political hands which have connected them with another, and to assume among the powers of the earth the separate and equal station to which the laws of nature and of nature&#8217;s God entitled them, a decent respect to the opinions of man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kind requires that they should declare the causes which impel them to the separation.</p>
<p>We hold these truths to be self-evident: that all men are created equal; that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able rights; that among these, are life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness; that, to secure these rights, governments are instituted among men, deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed; that, whenever any form of government becomes de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structive of these ends, it is the right of the people to alter or to abolish it, and to institute new government, laying its foundation on such principles, and organizing its powers in such form, as to them shall seem most likely to effect their safety and happiness. Prudence, indeed, will dictate that governments long established should not be changed for light and transient causes; and, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ingly, all experience hath shown that mankind are more disposed to suffer, while evils are sufferable, than to right themselves by abolishing the forms to which they are accustomed. But when a long train of abuses and usurpations, pursuing invariably the same object, evinces a design to reduce them, under absolute despotism, it is their right, it is their duty, to throw off such gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, and to provide new guards for their future security.&#8212; Such has been the patient sufferance of these colonies, and such <pb n="1234" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Declaration of Independence.</fw>is now the necessity which constrains them to alter their former systems of government. The history of the present king of Great Britain is a history of repeated injuries and usurpations, all having in direct object the establishment of an absolute tyranny over these States. To prove this, let facts be submitted to a candid world:&#8212;</p>
<p>He has refused his assent to laws the most wholesome and neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the public good.</p>
<p>He has forbidden his governors to pass laws of immediate and pressing importance, unless suspended in their operation till his assent should be obtained; and, when so suspended, he has utterly neglected to attend to them.</p>
<p>He has refused to pass other laws for the accommodation of large districts of people, unless those people would relinquish the right of representation in the legislature&#8212;a right inestimable to them, and formidable to tyrants only.</p>
<p>He has called together legislative bodies at places unusual, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />comfortable, and distant from the repository of their public rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ords, for the sole purpose of fatiguing them into compliance with his measures.</p>
<p>He has dissolved representative houses repeatedly for opposing with manly firmness his invasion on the rights of the people.</p>
<p>He has refused, for a long time after such dissolutions, to cause others to be elected; whereby the legislative powers, incapable of annihilation, have returned to the people at large for their exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise&#8212;the state, remaining, in the meantime, exposed to all the dangers of invasion from without and convulsions within.</p>
<p>He has endeavored to prevent the population of these states&#8212;for that purpose obstructing the laws of naturalization of foreigners, refusing to pass others to encourgae their migration hither, and raising the conditions of new appropriations of lands.</p>
<p>He has obstructed the administration of justice, by refusing his assent to laws for establishing judiciary powers.</p>
<p>He has made judges dependent on his will alone for the tenure of their offices and the amount and payment of their salaries.</p>
<p>He has erected a multitude of new offices, and sent hither swarms of officers to harrass our people and eat out their substance.</p>
<pb n="1235" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Declaration of Independence.</fw>
<p>He has kept among us, in times of peace, standing armies, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out the consent of our legislatures.</p>
<p>He has affected to render the military independent of, and su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perior to, the civil power.</p>
<p>He has combined with others to subject us to a jurisdiction for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign to our constitution and unacknowledged by our laws&#8212;giving his assent to their acts of pretended legislation.</p>
<p>For quartering large bodies of armed troops among us;</p>
<p>For protecting them, by a mock trial, from punishment for any murders which they should commit on the inhabitants of these states;</p>
<p>For cutting off our our trade with all parts of the world;</p>
<p>For imposing taxes on us without our consent;</p>
<p>For depriving us, in many cases, of the benefits of trial by jury;</p>
<p>For transporting us beyond seas to be tried for pretended of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fences.</p>
<p>For abolishing the free system of English laws in a neighboring province, establishing therein an arbitrary government, and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />larging its boundaries, so as to render it at once an example and fit instrument for introducing the same absolute rule into these colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nies;</p>
<p>For taking away our charters, abolishing our most valuable laws, and altering, fundamentally, the forms of our governments.</p>
<p>For suspending our own legislatures, and declaring themselves invested with power to legislate for us in all cases whatsoever.</p>
<p>He has abdicated government here by declaring us out of his protection and waging war against us.</p>
<p>He has plundered our seas, ravaged our coasts, burnt our towns, and destroyed the lives of our people.</p>
<p>He is at this time transporting large armies of foreign mercena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ries to complete the works of death, desolation and tyranny, already begun with circumstances of cruelty and perfidy scarcely paralleled in the most barbarous ages, and totally unworthy the head of a civil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized nation.</p>
<p>He has constrained our fellow-citizens, taken captive on the high seas, to bear arms against their country, to become the executioners of their friends and brethren, or to fall themselves by their hands.</p>
<pb n="1236" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Declaration of Independence.</fw>
<p>He has excited domestic insurrections among us, and has en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deavored to bring on the inhabitants of our frontiers the merciless Indian savages, whose known rule of warfare is an undistinguished destruction of all ages, sexes, and conditions.</p>
<p>In every stage of these oppressions, we have petitioned for redress in the most humble terms. Our repeated petitions have been an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swered only by repeated injury. A prince, whose character is thus marked by every act which may define a tyrant, is unfit to be the ruler of a free people.</p>
<p>Nor have we been wanting in attentions to our British brethren. We have warned them, from time to time, of attempts, by their legislature, to extend an unwarrantable jurisdiction over us. We have reminded them of the circumstances of our emigration and set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement here. We have appealed to their native justice and mag<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nanimity, and we have conjured them, by the ties of our common kindred, to disavow these usurpations, which would inevitably in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terrupt our connexions and correspondence. They, too, have been deaf to the voice of justice and of consanguinity. We must, there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore, acquiesce in the necessity which denounces our separation, and hold them, as we hold the rest of mankind, enemies in war, in peace, friends.</p>
<p>We, therefore, the representatives of the United States of Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ica, in general Congress assembled, appealing to the Supreme Judge of the World for the rectitude of our intentions, do, in the name, and by the authority of the good people of these colonies, solemnly publish and declare that these united colonies are, and of right ought to be, free and independent states; that they are absolved from all allegiance to the British crown, and that all political con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nexion between them and the state of Great Britain is, and ought to be, totally dissolved; and that, as free and independent states, they have full power to levy war, conclude peace, contract alliances, establish commerce, and to do all other acts and things which in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependent states may of right do. And for the support of this declaration, with a firm reliance on the protection of Divine Providence, we mutually pledge to each other our lives, our for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tunes, and our sacred honor.</p>
<pb n="1237" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Declaration of Independence.</fw>
<p>The foregoing declaration was, by order of Congress, engrossed and signed by the following members:</p>
<closer>
<signed>JOHN HANCOCK.</signed>
<signed>NEW HAMPSHIRE.<lb/>
<list><item>J<smcap>OSIAH</smcap> B<smcap>ARTLETT</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> W<smcap>HIPPLE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>M<smcap>ATTHEW</smcap> T<smcap>HORNTON</smcap>,</item></list></signed>
<signed>MASSACHUSETTS BAY.<lb/>
<list><item>S<smcap>AMUEL</smcap> A<smcap>DAMS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OHN</smcap> A<smcap>DAMS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>R<smcap>OBERT</smcap> T<smcap>REAT</smcap> P<smcap>AINE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>E<smcap>LBRIDGE</smcap> G<smcap>ERRY</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>RHODE ISLAND.<lb/>
<list><item>S<smcap>TEPHEN</smcap> H<smcap>OPKINS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> E<smcap>LLERY</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>CONNECTICUT.<lb/>
<list><item>R<smcap>OGER</smcap> S<smcap>HERMAN</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>S<smcap>AMUEL</smcap> H<smcap>UNTINGTON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> W<smcap>ILLIAMS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>O<smcap>LIVER</smcap> W<smcap>OLCOTT</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>NEW YORK.<lb/>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> F<smcap>LOYD</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>P<smcap>HILIP</smcap> L<smcap>IVINGSTON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>F<smcap>RANCIS</smcap> L<smcap>EWIS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>L<smcap>EWIS</smcap> M<smcap>ORRIS</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>NEW JERSEY.<lb/>
<list><item>R<smcap>ICHARD</smcap> S<smcap>TOCKTON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OHN</smcap> W<smcap>ITHERSPOON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>F<smcap>RANCIS</smcap> H<smcap>OPKINSON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OHN</smcap> H<smcap>ART</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>A<smcap>BRAHAM</smcap> C<smcap>LARK</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>PENNSYLVANIA.<lb/>
<list><item>R<smcap>OBERT</smcap> M<smcap>ORRIS</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>B<smcap>ENJAMIN</smcap> R<smcap>USH</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>B<smcap>ENJAMIN</smcap> F<smcap>RANKLIN</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OHN</smcap> M<smcap>ORTON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> C<smcap>LYMER</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>AMES</smcap> S<smcap>MITH</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> T<smcap>AYLOR</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>AMES</smcap> W<smcap>ILSON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> R<smcap>OSS</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>DELAWARE.<lb/>
<list><item>C<smcap>&#198;SAR</smcap> R<smcap>ODNEY</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> R<smcap>EAD</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> M&#8217;<smcap>KEAN</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>MARYLAND.<lb/>
<list><item>S<smcap>AMUEL</smcap> C<smcap>HASE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> P<smcap>ACA</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> S<smcap>TONE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>C<smcap>HARLES</smcap> C<smcap>ARROLL</smcap>, of Carrolton.</item></list></signed>
<signed>VIRGINIA.<lb/>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> W<smcap>YTHE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>R<smcap>ICHARD</smcap> H<smcap>ENRY</smcap> L<smcap>EE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> J<smcap>EFFERSON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>B<smcap>ENJAMIN</smcap> H<smcap>ARRISON</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> N<smcap>ELSON</smcap>, J<smcap>R</smcap>.,</item></list>
<list><item>F<smcap>RANCIS</smcap> L<smcap>IGHTFOOT</smcap> L<smcap>EE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>C<smcap>ARTER</smcap> B<smcap>RAXTON</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<pb n="1238" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Declaration of Independence.</fw>
<signed>NORTH CAROLINA.<lb/>
<list><item>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> H<smcap>OOPER</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OSEPH</smcap> H<smcap>EWES</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>J<smcap>OHN</smcap> P<smcap>ENN</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>SOTTH CAROLINA.<lb/>
<list><item>E<smcap>DWARD</smcap> R<smcap>UTLEDGE</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> H<smcap>EYWARD</smcap>, J<smcap>R</smcap>.,</item></list>
<list><item>T<smcap>HOMAS</smcap> L<smcap>YNCH</smcap>, J<smcap>R</smcap>.,</item></list>
<list><item>A<smcap>RTHUR</smcap> M<smcap>IDDLETON</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
<signed>GEORGIA.<lb/>
<list><item>B<smcap>UTTON</smcap> G<smcap>WINNETT</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>L<smcap>YMAN</smcap> H<smcap>ALL</smcap>,</item></list>
<list><item>G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> W<smcap>ALTON</smcap>.</item></list></signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>