<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1239" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLES OF CONFEDERATION.</head>
<opener>
<salute><i>To all to whom these presents shall come, we, the undersigned, dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates of the States affixed to our names, send greeting.</i></salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the delegates of the United States of America in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress assembled did, on the fifteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-seven, and in the second year of the independence of America, agree to certain articles of confederation and perpetual Union between the states of New Hampshire, Massachusetts Bay, Rhode Island and Provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence Plantations, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Pennsyl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vania, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Caro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lina, and Georgia, in the words following, viz:&#8212;</p>
<p>Articles of Confederation and perpetual Union between the States of New Hampshire, Massachusetts Bay, Rhode Island and Provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence Plantations, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Penn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sylvania, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina and Georgia.</p>
<p>Article 1. The style of this confederacy shall be, &#8220;The United States of America.&#8221;</p>
<p>Article 2. Each state retains its sovereignty, freedom, and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependence, and every power, jurisdiction, and right, which is not by this confederation expressly delegated to the United States in Congress assembled.</p>
<p>Article 3. The said states hereby severally enter into a firm league of friendship with each other for their common defence, the se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity of their liberties, and their mutual and general welfare; bind<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing themselves to assist each other against all force offered to, or attacks made upon them, or any of them, on account of religion, sovereignty, trade, or any other pretence whatever.</p>
<p>Article 4. The better to secure and perpetuate mutual <pb n="1240" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>friendship, and intercourse among the people of the different states in this Union, the free inhabitants of each of these states, paupers, vagabonds, and fugitives from justice, excepted, shall be entitled to all privileges and immunities of free citizens in the several states; and the people of each state shall have free ingress and regress to and from any other state, and shall enjoy therein all the privileges of trade and commerce subject to the same duties, impositions, and restrictions, as the inhabitants thereof respectively, provided that such restrictions shall not extend so far as to prevent the removal of property imported into any state to any other state, of which the owner is an inhabitant: provided also, that no imposition, duties, or restriction, shall be laid by any State on the property of the United States or either of them.</p>
<p>If any person guilty of or charged with treason, felony or other high misdemeanor, in any state, shall flee from justice, and be found in any of the United States, he shall, upon demand of the governor or executive power of the state from which he fled, be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livered up and removed to the state having jurisdiction of his of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence.</p>
<p>Full faith and credit shall be given in each of these states to the records, acts and judicial proceedings of the courts and magistrates of every other state.</p>
<p>Article 5. For the more convenient management of the general interests of the United States, delegates shall be annually appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed in such manner as the legislature of each state shall direct to meet in Congress on the first Monday in November, in every year, with a power reserved to each state to recall its delegates or any of them, at any time within the year, and to send others in their stead for the remainder of the year.</p>
<p>No state shall be represented in Congress by less than two, nor by more than seven members; and no person shall be capable of being a delegate for more than three years in any term of six years; nor shall any person being a delegate, be capable of holding any office under the United States, for which he, or another for his benefit, receives any salary, fees, or emoluments of any kind.</p>
<p>Each state shall maintain its own delegates in a meeting of the states, and while they act as members of the committee of the states.</p>
<p>In determining questions in the United States in Congress assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bled, each state shall have one vote.</p>
<pb n="1241" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>
<p>Freedom of speech and debate in Congress shall not be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peached or questioned in any court or place out of Congress; and the members of Congress shall be protected in their persons from arrest and imprisonments, during the time of their going to and from and attendence on Congress, except for treason, felony, or breach of the peace.</p>
<p>Article 6. No State without the consent of the United States in Congress assembled, shall send any embassy to, or receive any embassy from, or enter into any conference, agreement, alliance, or treaty, with any king, prince, or state; nor shall any person holding any office of profit or trust under the United States, or any of them, accept of any present, emolument, office or title of any kind what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, from any king, prince, or foreign state; nor shall the United States in Congress assembled, or any of them, grant any title of nobility.</p>
<p>No two or more states shall enter into any treaty, confederation, or alliance whatever, between them, without the consent of the United States in Congress assembled, specifying accurately the purposes for which the same is to be entered into and how long it shall continue.</p>
<p>No state shall lay any imposts or duties, which may interfere with any stipulations in treaties entered into by the United States in Congress assembled, with any king, prince, or state, in pursu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of any treaties already proposed by Congress to the courts of France and Spain.</p>
<p>No vessel-of-war shall be kept up in time of peace by any state, except such number only as shall be deemed necessary by the United States in Congress assembled for the defence of such state or its trade; nor shall any body of forces be kept up by any state in time of peace, except such number only as in the judgment of the United States in Congress assembled, shall be deemed requisite to garrison the forts necessary for the defence of such state; but every state shall always keep up a well-regulated and disciplined militia, sufficiently armed and accoutred, and shall provide and have constantly ready for use, in public stores, a due number of field-pieces and tents, and a proper quantity of arms, ammunition, and camp equipage.</p>
<p>No state shall engage in any war without the consent of the United States in Congress assembled, unless such state be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tually invaded by enemies or shall have received certain advice of a resolution being formed by some nation of Indians to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vade such state, and the danger is so imminent as not to admit <pb n="1242" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>of a delay till the United States in Congress assembled can be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sulted; nor shall any state grant commissions to any ships or ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels-of-war, nor letters of marque or reprisal, except it be after a declaration of war by the United States in Congress assembled, and then only against the kingdom or state, and the subjects thereof, against which war has been so declared, and under such regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as shall be established by the United States in Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembled, unless such state be infested by pirates, in which case ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels-of-war may be fitted out for that occasion, and kept so long as the danger shall continue, or until the United States in Congress assembled shall determine otherwise.</p>
<p>Article 7. When land forces are raised by any state for the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon defence, all officers of or under the rank of colonel, shall be appointed by the legislature of each state respectively, by whom such forces shall be raised, or in such manner as such state shall direct, and all vacancies shall be filled up by the state which first made the appointment.</p>
<p>Article 8. All charges of war, and all other expenses that shall be incurred for the common defence or general welfare, and al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed by the United States in Congress assembled, shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />frayed out of a common treasury, which shall be supplied by the several states in proportion to the value of all land within each state granted to or surveyed for any person, as such land and the buildings and improvements thereon shall be estimated accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to such mode as the United States in Congress assembled shall from time to time direct and appoint.</p>
<p>The taxes for paying that proportion shall be laid and levied by the authority and direction of the legislatures of the several states, within the time agreed upon by the United States in Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembled.</p>
<p>Article 9. The United States in Congress assembled shall have the sole and exclusive right and power of determining on peace and war, except in the cases mentioned in the sixth article&#8212;of sending and receiving ambassadors&#8212;entering into treaties and alliances; provided, that no treaty of commerce shall be made whereby the legislative power of the respective states shall be restrained from imposing such imposts and duties on foreigners as their own people are subjected to, or from prohibit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the exportation or importation of any species of goods or commodities whatsoever&#8212;of establishing rules for deciding in all cases, what captures on land or water shall be legal, and <pb n="1243" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>in what manner prizes taken by land or naval forces in the service of the United States shall be divided or appropriated&#8212;of granting letters of marque and reprisal in times of peace&#8212;appointing courts for the trial of piracies and felonies committed on the high seas, and establishing courts for receiving and determining finally ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals in all cases of captures: provided, that no member of Congress shall be appointed a judge of any of the said courts.</p>
<p>The United States in Congress assembled shall also be the last resort on appeal in all disputes and differences now subsisting or that hereafter may arise between two or more states concerning boundary, jurisdiction, or any other cause whatever; which author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity shall always be exercised in the manner following: whenever the legislative or executive authority or lawful agent of any state in controversy with another shall present a petition to Congress, stating the matter in question, and praying for a hearing, notice thereof shall be given by order of Congress to the legislative or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecutive authority of the other state in controversy, and a day as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed for the appearance of the parties, by their lawful agents, who shall then be directed to appoint by joint consent commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers or judges to constitute a court for hearing and determining the matter in question; but if they cannot agree, Congress shall name three persons out of each of the United States, and from the list of such persons each party shall alternately strike out one, the peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioners beginning until the number shall be reduced to thirteen; and from that number not less than seven nor more than nine names, as Congress shall direct shall, in the presence of Congress, be drawn out by lot; and the persons whose names shall be so drawn, or any five of them, shall be commissioners or judges, to bear and finally determine the controversy, so always as a major part of the judges, who shall bear the cause, shall agree in the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termination; and if either party shall neglect to attend at the day appointed, without showing reasons which Congress shall judge sufficient, or being present shall refuse to strike, the Congress shall proceed to nominate three persons out of each state, and the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of Congress shall strike in behalf of such party absent or refusing; and the judgment and sentence of the court to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed in the manner before prescribed, shall be final and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive; and if any of the parties shall refuse to submit to the authority of such court, or to appear, or defend their claim or <pb n="1244" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>cause, the court shall nevertheless proceed to pronounce sentence or judgment, which shall in like manner be final and decisive, the judgment or sentence and other proceedings, being in either case transmitted to Congress, and lodged among the acts of Congress for the security of the parties concerned: provided, that every com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner, before he sits in judgment, shall take an oath, to be ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministered by one of the judges of the supreme or superior court of the state, where the cause shall be tried, &#8220;well and truly to bear and determine the matter in question, according to the best of his judgment, without favor, affection, or hope of reward:&#8221; provided also, that no state shall be deprived of territory for the benefit of the United States.</p>
<p>All controversies concerning the private right of soil, claimed under different grants of two or more states, whose jurisdiction as they may respect such lands and the states which passed such grants are adjusted, the said grants or either of them being at the same time claimed to have originated antecedent to such settlement of jurisdiction, shall, on the petition of either party to the Congress of the United States be finally determined, as near as may be, in the same manner as is before prescribed for deciding disputes re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />specting territorial jurisdiction between different states.</p>
<p>The United States in Congress assembled, shall also have the sole and exclusive right and power of regulating the alloy and value of coin struck by their own authority, or by that of the respective states&#8212;fixing the standard of weights and measures throughout the United States&#8212;regulating the trade and managing all affairs with the Indians not members of any of the states; provided that the legislative right of any state within its own limits be not infringed or violated&#8212;establishing and regulating postoffices from one state to another throughout all the United States, and exacting such postage on the papers passing through the same, as may be requisite to defray the expenses of the said office&#8212;appointing all officers of the land forces in the service of the United States excepting regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental officers&#8212;appointing all the officers of the naval forces, and commissioning all officers whatever in the service of the United States&#8212;making rules for the government and regulation of the said land and naval forces, and directing their operations.</p>
<p>The United States in Congress assembled shall have author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1245" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>ity to appoint a committee to sit in the recess of Congress, to be denominated &#8220;a committee of the states,&#8221; and to consist of one delegate from each state; and to appoint such other committees and civil officers as may be necessary for managing the general affairs of the United States, under their direction&#8212;to appoint one of their number to preside, provided that no person be allowed to serve in the office of president more than one year in any term of three years&#8212;to ascertain the necessary sums of money to be raised for the service of the United States, and to appropriate and apply the same for defraying the public expenses, to borrow money or emit bills on the credit of the United States, transmitting every half year to the respective states an account of the sums of money so borrowed or emitted&#8212;to build and equip a navy&#8212;to agree upon the number of land forces, and to make requisitions from each state for its quota, in proportion to the number of white inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants in such state; which requisition shall be binding, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon the legislature of each state shall appoint the regimental offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, raise the men, and clothe, arm, and equip them, in a soldier<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />like manner, at the expense of the United States; and the officers and men so clothed, armed, and equipped, shall march to the place appointed, and within the time agreed on by the United States in Congress assembled; but if the United States in Congress assembled shall, on consideration of circumstances, judge proper that any state should not raise men or should raise a smaller number of its quota, and that any other state should raise a greater number of men than the quota thereof, such extra number shall be raised, officered, clothed, armed, and equipped, in the same manner as the quota of such State, unless the legislature of such state shall judge that such extra number can not safely be spared out of the same; in which case they shall raise, officer, clothe, arm, and equip, as many of such extra number as they judge can be safely spared. And the officers and men so clothed, armed, and equipped, shall march to the place appointed, and within the time agreed on by the United States in Congress assembled.</p>
<p>The United States in Congress assembled shall never engage in a war, nor grant letters of marque and reprisal in time of peace, nor enter into any treaties or alliances, nor coin money, nor regulate the value thereof, nor ascertain the sums and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses necessary for the defence and welfare of the United States or any of them, nor emit bills; nor borrow money on the credit of the United States, nor appropriate money, nor agree upon the <pb n="1246" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>number of vessels-of-war to be built or purchased, or the number of land or sea forces to be raised, nor appoint a commander-in-chief of the army and navy, unless nine states assent to the same; nor shall a question on any other point, except for adjourning from day to day, be determined, unless by the votes of a majority of the United States in Congress assembled.</p>
<p>The Congress of the United States shall have power to adjourn to any time within the year, and to any place within the United States, so that no period of adjournment be for a longer duration than the space of six months; and shall publish the journal of their proceedings monthly, except such parts thereof relating to treaties, alliances, or miltary operations, as in their judgment re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire secresy; and the yeas and nays of the delegates of each state on any question shall be entered on the journal, when it is desired by and delegate; and the delegate of a state, or any of them, at his or their request, shall be furnished with a transcript of the said journal, except such parts as are above excepted, to lay before the legislatures of the several states.</p>
<p>Article 10. The committee of the states, or any nine of them, shall be authorized to execute, in the recess of Congress, such of the powers of Congress as the United States in Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembled, by the consent of nine states, shall from time to time, think expedient to vest them with; provided that no power be dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gated to the said committee, for the exercise of which, by the articles of confederation, the voice of nine states in the Congress of the United States assembled is requisite.</p>
<p>Article 11. Canada, acceding to this confederation, and joining in the measures of the United States, shall be admitted into, and entitled to, all the advantages of this Union; but no other colony shall be admitted into the same unless such admission be agreed to by nine states.</p>
<p>Article 12. All bills of credit emitted, moneys borrowed, and debts contracted, by or under the authority of Congress, before the assembling of the United States in pursuance of the present confederation, shall be deemed and considered as a charge against the United States, for payment and satisfaction whereof the said United States and the public faith are hereby solemnly pledged.</p>
<p>Article 13. Every state shall abide by the decision of the United States in Congress assembled, on all questions which, by this confederation, are submitted to them. And the articles of this confederation shall be inviolably observed by eve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1247" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>ry state, and the Union shall be perpetual; nor shall any alteration at any time hereafter be made in any of them, unless such altera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be agreed to in a Congress of the United States, and be after<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ward confirmed by the legislature of every state.</p>
<p>And whereas it has pleased the great Governor of the world to incline the hearts of the legislatures we respectively represent in Congress, to approve of and to authorize us to ratify the said ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticles of confederation and perpetual Union: know ye, that we, the undersigned delegates, by virtue of the power and authority to us given for that purpose, do, by these presents, in the name and in behalf of our respective constituents, fully and entirely ratify and confirm each and every of the said articles of confederation and perpetual Union, and all and singular the matters and things therein contained; and we do further solemnly plight and engage the faith of our respective constituents, that they shall abide by the determinations of the United States in Congress assembled, on all questions which, by the said confederation are submitted to them; and that the articles thereof shall be inviolably observed by the states we respectively represent; and that the Union be perpetual.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, we have hereunto set our hands, in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress. Done at Philadelphia, in the state of Pennsylvania, the ninth day of July, in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and seventy-eight, and in the third year of the independence of America.</p>
<closer>
<signed>New Hampshire.<lb/>
<list><item>Josiah Bartlett,</item></list>
<list><item>John Wentworth, Jr.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Massachusetts Bay.<lb/>
<list><item>John Hancock,</item></list>
<list><item>Samuel Adams,</item></list>
<list><item>Elbridge Gerry,</item></list>
<list><item>Francis Danna,</item></list>
<list><item>James Lovell,</item></list>
<list><item>Samuel Holten.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Rhode Island.<lb/>
<list><item>William Ellery,</item></list>
<list><item>Henry Marchant,</item></list>
<list><item>John Collins.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Connecticut.<lb/>
<list><item>Roger Sherman,</item></list>
<list><item>Samuel Huntington,</item></list>
<list><item>Oliver Wolcott,</item></list>
<list><item>Titus Hosmer,</item></list>
<list><item>Andrew Adams.</item></list></signed>
<signed>New York.<lb/>
<list><item>James Duane,</item></list>
<list><item>Francis Lewis,</item></list>
<list><item>William Duer,</item></list>
<list><item>Gouverneur Morris.</item></list></signed>
<signed>New Jersey.<lb/>
<list><item>John Witherspoon,</item></list>
<list><item>Nath. Scudder.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Pennsylvania.<lb/>
<list><item>Robert Morris,</item></list>
<list><item>Daniel Roberdeau,</item></list>
<list><item>Jonathan Bayard Smith,</item></list>
<pb n="1248" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Articles of Confederation.</fw>
<list><item>William Clingan,</item></list>
<list><item>Joseph Reed.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Delaware.<lb/>
<list><item>Thomas M&#8217;Kean,</item></list>
<list><item>John Dickinson,</item></list>
<list><item>Nicholas Van Dyke.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Maryland.<lb/>
<list><item>John Hanson,</item></list>
<list><item>Daniel Carroll.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Virginia.<lb/>
<list><item>Richard Henry Lee,</item></list>
<list><item>John Banister,</item></list>
<list><item>Thomas Adams,</item></list>
<list><item>John Harvie,</item></list>
<list><item>Francis Lightfoot Lee.</item></list></signed>
<signed>North Carolina.<lb/>
<list><item>John Peen,</item></list>
<list><item>Constable Harnett,</item></list>
<list><item>John Williams.</item></list></signed>
<signed>South Carolina.<lb/>
<list><item>Henry Laurens,</item></list>
<list><item>William Henry Drayton,</item></list>
<list><item>John Matthews,</item></list>
<list><item>Richard Hutson,</item></list>
<list><item>Thomas Heyward, Jr.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Georgia.<lb/>
<list><item>John Walton,</item></list>
<list><item>Edward Telfair,</item></list>
<list><item>Edward Longworthy.</item></list></signed>
</closer>
</div1>
</body>
</text>