<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1249" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED STATES.</head>
<p>We, the People of the United States, in order to form a more perfect union, establish justice, ensure domes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tic tranquility, provide for the common defence, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mote the general welfare, and secure the blessings of liberty to ourselves and our posterity, do ordain and establish this Constitution for the United States of America.</p>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section I.</head>
<p>All legislative power herein granted shall be vested <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Legislative powers.</p></body></floatingText> in a Congress of the United States, which shall consist of a Senate and House of Representatives.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section II.</head>
<p>The House of Representatives shall be composed of <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Members House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives, how chosen.</p></body></floatingText> members chosen every second year, by the people of the several States; and the electors in each State shall have the qualifications requisite for electors of the most numerous branch of the State Legislature.</p>
<p>No person shall be a Representative who shall not <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Qualifications of members House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives.</p></body></floatingText> have attained to the age of twenty-five years, and been seven years a citizen of the United States, and who shall not, when elected, be an inhabitant of that State in which he shall be chosen.</p>
<p>Representatives and direct taxes shall be appor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Apportion<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives.</p></body></floatingText>tioned among the several States which may be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluded within the Union, according to their respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ive numbers, which shall be determined by adding to <pb n="1250" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>the whole number of free persons, including those bound to service for a term of years, and excluding In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians not taxed, three-fifths of all other persons.&#8212;The actual enumeration shall be made within three years after the first meeting of the Congress of the United States, and within every subsequent term of ten years, in such manner as they shall by law direct. The num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of Representatives shall not exceed one for every thirty thousand, but each State shall have at least one Representative; and until such enumeration shall be made, the State of New Hampshire shall be entitled to choose three; Massachusetts eight; Rhode Island and Providence Plantations one; Connecticut five; New York six; New Jersey four; Pennsylvania eight; Dela<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ware one; Maryland six; Virginia ten; North Carolina five; South Carolina five; and Georgia three.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Vacancies how filled.</p></body></floatingText>When vacancies happen in the representation from any State, the Executive authority thereof shall issue writs of election to fill such vacancies.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives choose offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers.</p></body></floatingText>The House of Representatives shall choose their Speaker and other officers, and shall have the sole power of impeachment.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section III.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Senate, how chosen.</p></body></floatingText>The Senate of the United States shall be composed of two Senators from each State, chosen by the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture thereof, for six years; and each Senator shall have one vote.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Senators classed.</p></body></floatingText>Immediately after they shall be assembled in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequence of the first election, they shall be divided, as equally as may be, into three classes. The seats of the Senators of the first class shall be vacated at the expiration of the second year; of the second class at the expiration of the fourth year; and of the third class at the expiration of the sixth year; so that one-third may be chosen every second year; and if va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancies happen, by resignation or otherwise, during the recess of the Legislature of any State, the Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecutive thereof may make temporary appointments, until the next meeting of the Legislature, which <pb n="1251" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>shall then fill such vacancies. No person shall be a <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Senator&#8217;s qualifications.</p></body></floatingText> Senator who shall not have attained the age of thirty years, and been nine years a citizen of the United States, and who shall not, when elected, be an inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tant of that State for which he shall be chosen. <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Vice Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent vote.</p></body></floatingText></p>
<p>The Vice President of the United States shall be President of the Senate, but shall have no vote unless they be equally divided.</p>
<p>The Senate shall choose their other officers, and also <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Senate choose officers.</p></body></floatingText> a President pro tempore, in the absence of the Vice President, or when he shall exercise the office of Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the United States.</p>
<p>The Senate shall have the sole power to try all im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Try impeach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments.</p></body></floatingText>peachments: when sitting for that purpose, they shall be on oath or affirmation. When the President of the United States is tried, the Chief Justice shall preside; and no person shall be convicted without the concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rence of two-thirds of the members present.</p>
<p>Judgment in cases of impeachment shall not extend <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Judgment on impeachment.</p></body></floatingText> further than to removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit, under the United States; but the party convicted shall, nevertheless, be liable and subject to indictment, trial, judgment, and punishment, according to law.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section IV.</head>
<p>The times, places, and manner of holding elections <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Elections, how held.</p></body></floatingText> for Senators and Representatives, shall be prescribed in each State by the Legislature thereof; but the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress may at any time, by law, make or alter such regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations, except as to the places of choosing Senators.</p>
<p>The Congress shall assemble at least once in every <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />semble annu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly.</p></body></floatingText> year; and such meeting shall be on the first Monday in December, unless they shall, by law, appoint a different day.</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1252" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section V.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Elections how judged.</p></body></floatingText>Each House shall be the judge of the elections, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns, and qualifications, of its own members; and a majority of each shall constitute a quorum to do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Quorum, Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate and House of Represent<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />atives.</p></body></floatingText>ness; but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day, and may be authorized to compel the attendance of absent members, in such manner, and under such pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alties, as each House may provide.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Rules.</p></body></floatingText>Each House may determine the rules of its proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, punish its members for disorderly behavior, and, with the concurrence of two thirds, expel a member.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Journals by each House.</p></body></floatingText>Each House shall keep a journal of its proceedings, and from time to time publish the same, excepting such parts as may, in their judgment, require secrecy; and the yeas and nays of the members of either House, on any question, shall, at the desire of one-fifth of those present, be entered on the journal.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Adjournment.</p></body></floatingText>Neither House, during the session of Congress, shall, without the consent of the other, adjourn for more than three days, nor to any other place than that in which the two Houses shall be sitting.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section VI.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p></body></floatingText>The Senators and Representatives shall receive a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation for their services, to be ascertained by law, <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Privileges.</p></body></floatingText> and paid out of the Treasury of the United States. They shall in all cases, except treason, felony, and breach of <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Arrests.</p></body></floatingText> the peace, be privileged from arrest during their attend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance on the session of their respective Houses, and in going to or returning from the same: and for any speech or debate in either House, they shall not be questioned in any other place.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Members not appointed to office.</p></body></floatingText>No Senator or Representative shall, during the time for which he was elected, be appointed to any civil office under the authority of the United States, which shall have been created, or the emoluments whereof shall have been increased during such <pb n="1253" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>time; and no person holding any office under the United States shall be a member of either House during his continuance in office.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section VII.</head>
<p>All bills for raising revenue shall originate in the <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Bills, revenue, House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives.</p></body></floatingText> House of Representatives, but the Senate may propose, or concur with, amendments, as on other bills.</p>
<p>Every bill which shall have passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Bills, their formalities.</p></body></floatingText>resentatives and the Senate, shall before it becomes a law, be presented to the President of the United States; if he approve, he shall sign it, but, if not, he shall return it, with his objections, to that House in which it shall have originated, who shall enter the objections at large on their journal, and proceed to reconsider it. If, after such reconsideration, two-thirds of the House shall agree to pass the bill, it shall be sent, together with the objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, to the other House, by which it shall likewise be reconsidered, and if approved by two thirds of that House, it shall become a law. But, in all such cases, the votes of both Houses shall be determined by yeas and nays, and the names of the persons voting for and against the bill shall be entered on the journal of each House respectively. If any bill shall not be returned by the President within ten days (Sundays excepted) after it shall have been presented to him, the same shall be a law, in like manner as if he had signed it, unless the Congress, by their adjournment, prevent its return, in which case it shall not be a law.</p>
<p>Every order, resolution, or vote, to which the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Resolutions and votes be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident of the United States.</p></body></floatingText>currence of the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives may be necessary, (except on a question of adjournment,) shall be presented to the President of the United States, and before the same shall take effect, shall be approved by him, or being disap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by him, shall be repassed by two-thirds of the Senate and House of Representatives, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1254" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>ing to the rules and limitations prescribed in the case of a bill.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section VIII.</head>
<p>The Congress shall have power&#8212;</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Congress lay taxes.</p></body></floatingText>To lay and collect taxes, duties, imposts, and excises; to pay the debts and provide for the common defence and general welfare of the United States; but all duties, imposts, and excises, shall be uniform throughout the United States:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Borrow mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eys.</p></body></floatingText>To borrow money on the credit of the United States:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Commerce &#38;c.</p></body></floatingText>To regulate commerce with foreign nations and among the several States, and with the Indian tribes:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Naturaliza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, &#38;c.</p></body></floatingText>To establish a uniform rule of naturalization, and uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form laws on the subject of bankruptcies, throughout the United States:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Coin, &#38;c.</p></body></floatingText>To coin money, regulate the value thereof, and of foreign coin, and fix the standard of weights and meas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ures:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Punish coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terfeiting.</p></body></floatingText>To provide for the punishment of counterfeiting the securities and current coin of the United States:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Post Offices &#38;c</p></body></floatingText>To establish post offices and post roads:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Promote sci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence.</p></body></floatingText>To promote the progress of science and useful arts, by securing, for a limited time, to authors and inventors, the exclusive right to their respective writings and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />coveries:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Congress con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute courts.</p></body></floatingText>To constitute tribunals inferior to the Supreme Court:</p>
<p>To define and punish piracies and felonies committed on the high seas, and offences against the law of nations:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Declare war.</p></body></floatingText>To declare war, to grant letters of marque and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisal, and make rules concerning captures on land and water:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Raise armies.</p></body></floatingText>To raise and support armies: (but no appropriation of money to that use shall be for a longer term than two years:)</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Navy.</p></body></floatingText>To provide and maintain a navy:</p>
<p>To make rules for the government and regulation of the land and naval forces:</p>
<pb n="1255" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
<p>To provide for calling forth the militia to execute <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Militia.</p></body></floatingText> the laws of the Union, suppress insurrections, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pel invasions:</p>
<p>To provide for organizing, arming, and disciplining <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Organize militia.</p></body></floatingText> the militia, and for governing such part of them as may be employed in the service of the United States; reserv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the States, respectively, the appointment of the officers, and the authority of training the militia, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to the discipline prescribed by Congress:</p>
<p>To exercise exclusive legislation in all cases whatso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Exclusive ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />risdiction ten miles.</p></body></floatingText>ever, over such district (not exceeding ten miles square) as may by cession of particular States, and the accept<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of Congress, become the seat of Government of the United States, and to exercise like authority over all places purchased, by the consent of the Legislature of the State in which the same shall be, for the erection of forts, magazines, arsenals, dock-yards, and other need<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful buildings: And,</p>
<p>To make all laws which, shall be necessary and proper <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Congress make laws general.</p></body></floatingText> for carrying into execution the foregoing powers, and all other powers vested by this Constitution in the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the United States, or in any department or offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer thereof.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section IX.</head>
<p>The migration or importation of such persons as any <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Importation of persons after 1808.</p></body></floatingText> of the States now existing shall think proper to admit, shall not be prohibited by the Congress prior to the year one thousand eight hundred and eight; but a tax or duty may be imposed on such importation, not exceeding ten dollars for each person.</p>
<p>The privilege of the writ of habeas corpus shall not <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Habeas corpus</p></body></floatingText> be suspended, unless when, in cases of rebellion or inva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, the public safety may require it.</p>
<p>No bill of attainder or ex post facto law shall be <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Attainder.</p></body></floatingText> passed.</p>
<p>No capitation or other direct tax shall be laid, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Tax.</p></body></floatingText> <pb n="1256" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>unless in proportion to the census or enumeration here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in before directed to be taken.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>No exporta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion duty.</p></body></floatingText>No tax or duty shall be laid on articles exported from any State. No preference shall be given, by any regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of commerce or revenue, to the ports of one State over those of another; nor shall vessels bound to or from one State be obliged to enter, clear, or pay duties in an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Money, how drawn.</p></body></floatingText>No money shall be drawn from the Treasury but in consequence of appropriations made by law; and a regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar statement and account of the receipts and expendi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures of all public money shall be published from time to time.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Titles not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred.</p></body></floatingText>No title of nobility shall be granted by the United States; and no person holding any office of profit or trust under them, shall, without the consent of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress, accept of any present, emolument, office, or title of any kind whatever, from any king, prince, or foreign state.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section X.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>States not make treaties.</p></body></floatingText>No State shall enter into any treaty, alliance, or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federation; grant letters of marque and reprisal; coin money; emit bills of credit; make any thing but gold and silver coin a tender in payment of debts; pass any bill of attainder, ex post facto law, or law impairing the obligation of contracts; or grant any title of nobility.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>States not lay imposts, &#38;c.</p></body></floatingText>No State shall, without the consent of the Congress, lay any impost duties on imports or exports, except what may be absolutely necessary for executing its inspection laws; and the nett produce of all duties and imposts laid by any State on imports or exports shall be for the use of the Treasury of the United States; and all such laws shall be subject to the revision and control of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress. No State shall, without the consent of Congress, <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Of tonnage.</p></body></floatingText>lay any duty of tonnage, keep troops or ships of war in time of peace, enter into any agreement or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pact with another State, or with a foreign power, <pb n="1257" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>or engage in war, unless actually invaded, or in such im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minent danger as will not admit of delay.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section I.</head>
<p>The Executive power shall be vested in a President <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Executive power.</p></body></floatingText> of the United States of America. He shall hold his office during the term of four years, and, together with the Vice President, chosen for the same term, be elected as follows:</p>
<p>Each State shall appoint, in such manner as the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Electors, how appointed.</p></body></floatingText>islature thereof may direct, a number of electors, equal to the whole number of Senators and Representatives to which the State may be entitled in the Congress; but no Senator or Representative, or person holding an office of trust or profit under the United States, shall be appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed an elector.</p>
<p>The electors shall meet in their respective States, and <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Electors meet.</p></body></floatingText> vote by ballot for two persons, of whom one at least shall not be an inhabitant of the same State with themselves. And they shall make a list of all the persons voted for, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Proceedings.</p></body></floatingText> and of the number of votes for each, which list they shall sign and certify, and transmit sealed to the seat of the Government of the United States, directed to the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Senate. The President of the Senate shall, in the presence of the Senate and House of Representatives, open all the certificates, and the votes shall then be counted. The person having the greatest number of votes shall be the President, if such number be a majority of the whole number of electors appointed; and if there be more than one who have such majority, and have an equal number of votes, then the House of Representatives shall immediately choose, by ballot, one of them for President; and if no person have a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority, then, from the five highest on the list, the said house shall, in like manner, choose the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent. But, in choosing the President, the votes shall be taken by States, the representation from <pb n="1258" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>each State having one vote: a quorum for this purpose shall consist of a member or members from two-thirds of the States, and a majority of all the States shall be necessary to a choice. In every case, after the choice of the President, the person having the greatest number of votes of the electors shall be the Vice President. But if there should remain two or more who have equal votes, the Senate shall choose from them, by ballot, the Vice President.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Day electors meet.</p></body></floatingText>The Congress may determine the time of choosing the electors, and the day on which they shall give their votes, which day shall be the same throughout the United States.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Qualifications of President of the United States.</p></body></floatingText>No person except a natural born citizen, or a citizen of the United States at the time of the adoption of this Constitution, shall be eligible to the office of President; neither shall any person be eligible to that office who shall not have attained to the age of thirty-five years, and been fourteen years a resident within the United States.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Removal of President U. States in case.</p></body></floatingText>In case of the removal of the President from office, of his death, resignation, or inability to discharge the powers and duties of the said office, the same shall de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />volve on the Vice President, and the Congress may, by law, provide for the case of removal, death, resignation, or inability, both of the President and Vice President, declaring what officer shall then act as President, and such officer shall act accordingly, until the disability be removed, or a President shall be elected.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>President Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted States, compensation.</p></body></floatingText>The President shall, at stated times, receive for his services a compensation, which shall neither be increased nor diminished during the period for which he shall have been elected: and he shall not receive within that period any other emolument from the United States, or any of them.</p>
<p>Before he enters on the execution of his office, he shall take the following oath or affirmation:</p>
<p><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Oath.</p></body></floatingText>&#8220;I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully execute the office of President of the United States; and will, to the best of my ability, preserve, <pb n="1259" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>protect, and defend the Constitution, of the United States.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section II.</head>
<p>The President shall be Commander-in-Chief of the <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>President Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted States, powers.</p></body></floatingText> Army and Navy of the United States, and of the Militia of the several States, when called into the actual service of the United States; he may require the opinion, in writing, of the principal officer in each of the Executive Departments, upon any subject relating to the duties of their respective offices; and he shall have power to grant reprieves and pardons for offences against the United States, except in cases of impeachment.</p>
<p>He shall have power, by and with the advice and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Make treaties.</p></body></floatingText>sent of the Senate, to make treaties, provided two-thirds of the Senators present concur: and he shall nominate, and, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint, Ambassadors, or other public Ministers, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Appoint offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers.</p></body></floatingText> and Consuls, Judges of the Supreme Court, and all other officers of the United States whose appointments are not herein otherwise provided for, and which shall be estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by law. But the Congress may, by law, vest the appointment of such inferior officers as they think proper in the President alone, in the courts of law, or in the heads of Departments.</p>
<p>The President shall have power to fill up all vacancies <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Vacancies in office.</p></body></floatingText> that may happen during the recess of the Senate, by granting commissions, which shall expire at the end of their next session.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section III.</head>
<p>He shall, from time to time, give to the Congress <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>President Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted States, du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties.</p></body></floatingText> information of the state of the Union, and recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mend to their consideration such measures as he shall judge necessary and expedient: he may, on extraordinary occasions, convene both Houses, or either of them; and, in case of disagreement be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween them, with respect to the time of adjourn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1260" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>journment, he may adjourn them to such time as he shall think proper: he shall receive Ambassadors and other public Ministers; he shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed; and shall commission all the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers of the United States.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section IV.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Officers re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />movable by impeachment.</p></body></floatingText>The President, Vice President, and all civil officers of the United States, shall be removed from office on im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peachment for, and conviction of, treason, bribery, or other high crimes and misdemeanors.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section I.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Judicial pow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers and tenure of judges.</p></body></floatingText>The Judicial power of the United States shall be vest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed in one Supreme Court, and in such inferior Courts as the Congress may, from time to time, ordain and estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish. The judges, both of the Supreme and inferior Courts, shall hold their offices during good behavior, and shall, at stated times, receive for their services a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation, which shall not be diminished during their continuance in office.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section II.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Judicial pow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, extension.</p></body></floatingText>The judicial power shall extend to all cases in law and equity arising under this Constitution, the laws of the United States, and treaties made, or which shall be made, under their authority; to all cases affecting Am<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bassadors, other public Ministers, and Consuls; to all cases of admiralty and maritime jurisdiction to which the United States shall be a party; to controversies be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween two or more States, between a State and citizens of another State, between citizens of different States, between citizens of the same State claiming lands under grants of different States, and <pb n="1261" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>between a State, or the citizens thereof, and foreign States, citizens, or subjects.</p>
<p>In all cases affecting Ambassadors, other public Minis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Supreme Court Juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction.</p></body></floatingText>ters, and Consuls, and those in which a State shall be a party, the Supreme Court shall have original jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion. In all the other cases before mentioned, the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court shall have appellate jurisdiction, both as to law and fact, with such exceptions, and under such regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations, as the Congress shall make.</p>
<p>The trial of all crimes, except in cases of impeach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Trial by jury.</p></body></floatingText>ment, shall be by jury; and such trial shall be held in the State where the said crimes shall have have been committed; but when not committed within any State, the trial shall be at such place or places as the Congress may by law have directed.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section III.</head>
<p>Treason against the United States shall consist only in <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Treason.</p></body></floatingText> levying war against them, or in adhering to their ene<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mies, giving them aid and comfort. No person shall be convicted of treason, unless on the testimony of two wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses to the same overt act, or on confession in open court.</p>
<p>The Congress shall have power to declare the pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Attainder.</p></body></floatingText>ishment of treason; but no attainder of treason shall work corruption of blood, or forfeiture, except during the life of the person attainted.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IV.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section I.</head>
<p>Full faith and credit shall be given in each State to <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Acts of States accredited.</p></body></floatingText> the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of ev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ery other State. And the Congress may, by general laws, prescribe the manner in which such acts, records, and proceedings shall be proved, and the effect thereof.</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1262" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section II.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Citizens&#8217; priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges.</p></body></floatingText>The citizens of each State shall be entitled to all priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges and immunities of citizens in the several States.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Persons charg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed with crimes fleeing.</p></body></floatingText>A person charged in any State with treason, felony, or other crime, who shall flee from justice, and be found in another State, shall, on demand of the Execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive authority of the State from which he fled, be deliv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered up, to be removed to the State having jurisdiction of the crime.</p>
<p>No person held to service or labor in one State, under the laws thereof, escaping into another, shall, in conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quence of any law or regulation therein, be discharged from such service or labor, but shall be delivered up on claim of the party to whom such service or labor may be due.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section III.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>New States admitted.</p></body></floatingText>New States may be admitted by the Congress into this Union; but no new States shall be formed or erected within the jurisdiction of any other State, nor any State be formed by the junction of two or more States, or parts of States, without the consent of the Legislatures of the States concerned, as well as of the Congress.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Territory of United States.</p></body></floatingText>The Congress shall have power to dispose of, and make all needful rules and regulations respecting the territory or other property belonging to the United States; and nothing in this Constitution shall be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued as to prejudice any claims of the United States, or of any particular State.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Section IV.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Republican form.</p></body></floatingText>The United States shall guaranty to every State in this Union a republican form of government, and shall protect each of them against invasion; and on applica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Legislature, or of the Executive, (when the Legislature cannot be convened,) against domestic vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lence.</p>
<pb n="1263" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE V.</head>
<p>The Congress, whenever two-thirds of both houses <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Amendments, how attained.</p></body></floatingText> shall deem it necessary, shall propose amendments to this Constitution; or, on the application of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures of two-thirds of the several States, shall call a con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention for proposing amendments, which, in either case, shall be valid, to all intents and purposes, as part of this Constitution, when ratified by the Legislatures of three-fourths of the several States, or by conventions in three-fourths thereof, as the one or the other mode of ratification may be proposed by the Congress: Provided, that no amendment which may be made prior to the year one thousand eight hundred and eight, shall in any manner affect the first and fourth clauses in the ninth section of the first article; and that no State, without its consent, shall be deprived of its equal suffrage in the Senate.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VI.</head>
<p>All debts contracted, and engagements entered into, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Debts prior to adoption of Constitution.</p></body></floatingText> before the adoption of this Constitution, shall be as valid against the United States under this Constitution as under the Confederation.</p>
<p>This Constitution, and the laws of the United States <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Treaties, law of land.</p></body></floatingText> which shall be made in pursuance thereof, and all trea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties made or which shall be made under the authority of the United States, shall be the supreme law of the land; and the Judges in every State shall be bound thereby, any thing in the Constitution or laws of any State to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<p>The Senators and Representatives before mentioned, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Oath or affir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation to members.</p></body></floatingText> and the members of the several State Legislatures, and all Executive and Judicial officers, both of the United States and of the several States, shall be bound, by oath or affirmation, to support this Constitution; but no reli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gious test shall ever be required as a qualification to any office or public trust under the United States.</p>
<pb n="1264" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VII.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Ratification.</p></body></floatingText>The ratification of the conventions of nine States shall be sufficient for the establishment of this Constitution between the States so ratifying the same.</p>
<p>Done in Convention, by the unanimous consent of the States present, the seventeenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and eighty-seven, and of the independence of the United States of America the twelfth. In witness whereof we have hereunto subscribed our names.</p>
<closer>
<signed>GEORGE WASHINGTON,<lb/> President, and Deputy from Virginia.</signed>
<signed>New Hampshire.<lb/>
<list><item>John Langdon,</item></list>
<list><item>Nicholas Gilman.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Masaschusetts.<lb/>
<list><item>Nathaniel Gorham,</item></list>
<list><item>Rufus King.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Connecticut.<lb/>
<list><item>William Samuel Johnson,</item></list>
<list><item>Roger Sherman.</item></list></signed>
<signed>New York.<lb/>
<list><item>Alexander Hamilton.</item></list></signed>
<signed>New Jersey.<lb/>
<list><item>William Livingston,</item></list>
<list><item>David Brearley,</item></list>
<list><item>William Patterson,</item></list>
<list><item>Jonathan Dayton.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Pennsylvania.<lb/>
<list><item>Benjamin Franklin,</item></list>
<list><item>Thomas Mifflin,</item></list>
<list><item>Robert Morris,</item></list>
<list><item>George Clymer,</item></list>
<list><item>Thomas Fitzsimmons,</item></list>
<list><item>Jared Ingersoll,</item></list>
<list><item>James Wilson,</item></list>
<list><item>Gouverneur Morris.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Delaware.<lb/>
<list><item>George Reed,</item></list>
<list><item>Gunning Bedford, Jr.,</item></list>
<list><item>John Dickinson,</item></list>
<list><item>Richard Bassett,</item></list>
<list><item>Jacob Broom.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Maryland.<lb/>
<list><item>James McHenry,</item></list>
<list><item>Daniel of St. Thos. Jenifer,</item></list>
<list><item>Daniel Carroll.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Virginia.<lb/>
<list><item>John Blair,</item></list>
<list><item>James Madison,</item></list>
<list><item>Jr.</item></list></signed>
<signed>North Carolina.<lb/>
<list><item>William Blount,</item></list>
<list><item>Richard Dobbs Spaight,</item></list>
<list><item>Hugh Williamson.</item></list></signed>
<signed>South Carolina.<lb/>
<list><item>John Rutledge,</item></list>
<list><item>Charles C. Pinckney,</item></list>
<list><item>Charles Pinckney,</item></list>
<list><item>Pierce Butler.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Georgia.<lb/>
<list><item>William Fow,</item></list>
<list><item>Abraham Baldwin.</item></list></signed>
<signed>Attest: WILLIAM JACKSON, Secretary.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1265" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">IN CONVENTION.</head>
<dateline>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 17, 1787.</dateline>
<p>Resolved, That the preceding Constitution be laid be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the United States in Congress assembled, and that it is the opinion of this Convention that it should after<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wards be submitted to a convention of delegates chosen in each State by the people thereof, under the recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mendation of its Legislature, for their assent and rati<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fication; and that each convention assenting to and rati<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fying the same should give notice thereof to the United States in Congress assembled.</p>
<p>Resolved, That it is the opinion of this Convention, that, as soon as the conventions of nine States shall have ratified this Constitution, the United States in Congress assembled should fix on a day on which electors should be appointed by the States which shall have ratified the same, and a day on which electors should assemble to vote for the President, and the time and place for com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencing proceedings under this Constitution. That, after such publication, the electors should be appointed, and the Senators and Representatives elected. That the electors should meet on the day fixed for the election of the President, and should transmit their votes, cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified, signed, sealed, and directed, as the Constitution requires, to the Secretary of the United States, in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress assembled; that the Senators and Representatives should convene at the time and place assigned; that the Senators should appoint a President of the Senate, for the sole purpose of receiving, opening, and counting the votes for President; and that, after he shall be chosen, the Congress, together with the President, should, without delay, proceed to execute this Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution.</p>
<byline>By the unanimous order of the Convention:</byline>
<closer>
<signed>GEO. WASHINGTON, President.</signed>
<signed>W<smcap>ILLIAM</smcap> J<smcap>ACKSON</smcap>, Secretary.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1266" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">IN CONVENTION.</head>
<dateline>S<smcap>EPTEMBER</smcap> 17, 1787.</dateline>
<p>S<smcap>IR</smcap>: We have now the honor to submit to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration of the United States in Congress assembled that Constitution which has appeared to us the most advisable.</p>
<p>The friends of our country have long seen and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sired that the power of making war, peace, and treaties; that of levying money, and regulating commerce, and the correspondent Executive and Judicial authorities, should be fully and effectually vested in the General Government of the Union; but the impropriety of dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gating such extensive trusts to one body of men is evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent: hence results the necessity of a different organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>It is obviously impracticable, in the Federal Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of these States, to secure all rights of independent sovereignty to each, and yet provide for the interest and safety of all. Individuals entering into society must give up a share of liberty to preserve the rest. The mag<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nitude of the sacrifice must depend as well on situation and circumstance, as on the object to be obtained. It is at all times difficult to draw, with precision, the line be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween those rights which must be surrendered, and those which may be preserved; and, on the present occa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, this difficulty was increased by a difference among the several States, as to their situation, extent, habits and particular interests.</p>
<p>In all our deliberations on this subject, we kept steadily in our view that which appears to us the greatest interest of every true American&#8212;the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />solidation of our Union; in which is involved our prosperity, felicity, safety&#8212;perhaps our national existence. This important consideration seriously and deeply impressed our minds; and led each State in the Convention to be less rigid on points of inferior magnitude than might have been other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise expected; and thus the Constitution which <pb n="1267" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>we now present is the result of a spirit of amity, and of that mutual deference and concession which the pe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culiarity of our political situation rendered indis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensable.</p>
<p>That it will meet the full and entire approbation of every State, is not perhaps to be expected; but each will doubtless consider, that, had her interest been alone consulted, the consequences might have been particu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />larly disagreeable or injurious to others. That it is liable to as few exceptions as could reasonably have been expected, we hope and believe; that it may promote the lasting welfare of that country so dear to us all, and secure her freedom and happiness, is our most ardent wish. With great respect, we have the honor to be, sir, your excellency&#8217;s most obedient and humble ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vants.</p>
<byline>By unanimous order of the Convention:</byline>
<closer>
<signed>GEO. WASHINGTON, President.</signed>
<signed>His Excellency, the President of Congress.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<opener>The United States in Congress assembled:</opener>
<dateline>F<smcap>RIDAY</smcap>, S<smcap>EPTEMBER</smcap> 8, 1787.</dateline>
<p>Present&#8212;New Hampshire, Massachusets, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Delaware, Vir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Georgia; and from Maryland, Mr. Ross.</p>
<p>Congress having received the report of the Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion lately assembled in Philadelphia,</p>
<p>Resolved, unanimously, That the said report, with the resolutions and letter accompanying the saine, be transmitted to the several Legislatures, in order to submit to a convention of delegates chosen in each State by the people thereof, in conformity to <pb n="1268" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>the resolves of the Convention, made and provided in that case.</p>
<closer>
<signed>C<smcap>HARLES</smcap> T<smcap>HOMSON</smcap>, Secretary..</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AMENDMENTS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the First.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>No religious establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, or pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibition of its exercise. Freedom of speech and of the press. Right of peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, &#38;c.</p></body></floatingText>Congress shall make no law respecting an establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Second.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Right to keep arms.</p></body></floatingText>A well regulated militia being necessary to the se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Third.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Quartering of soldiers for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bidden.</p></body></floatingText>No soldier shall, in time of peace, be quartered in any House without the consent of the owner, nor in time of war, but in a manner to be prescribed by law.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Fourth.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Rights against unreasonable searches and seizures.</p></body></floatingText>The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated; and no war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant shall issue, but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched, and the person or things to be seized.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Fifth.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Presentment in criminal prosecutions.</p></body></floatingText>No person shall be held to answer for a capital or otherwise infamous crime, unless on a present<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment or indictment of a grand jury, except in cases <pb n="1269" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>arising in the land or naval forces, or in the militia when in actual service, in time of war or public dan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ger; nor shall any person be subject, for the same of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence, to be twice put in jeopardy of life or limb; nor shall be compelled, in any criminal case, to be witness against himself; nor be deprived of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor shall private <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Private prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty held sacred.</p></body></floatingText> property be taken for public use without just compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Sixth.</head>
<p>In all criminal prosecutions, the accused shall enjoy <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Trial by jury in criminal prosecutions.</p></body></floatingText> the right to a speedy and public trial, by an impartial jury of the State and district wherein the crime shall have been committed, which district shall have been previously ascertained by law; and to be informed of the nature and cause of the accusation; to be confronted with the witnesses against him; to have compulsory pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Form of trial.</p></body></floatingText>cess for obtaining witnesses in his favor; and to have the assistance of counsel for his defence.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Seventh.</head>
<p>In suits at common law, where the value in contro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Jury trial in civil cases over $20.</p></body></floatingText>versy shall exceed twenty dollars, the right of trial by jury shall be preserved; and no fact tried by jury shall be otherwise re-examined in any court of the United States than according to the rules of the common law.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Eighth.</head>
<p>Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Excessive bail.</p></body></floatingText> fines imposed, nor cruel and unusual punishments in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flicted.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Ninth.</head>
<p>The enumeration in the Constitution of certain <pb n="1270" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Rights not grrnted re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in the people.</p></body></floatingText> rights shall not be construed to deny or disparage oth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers retained by the people.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Tenth.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Powers not delegated re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served to the States.</p></body></floatingText>The powers not delegated to the United States by the Constitution, nor prohibited by it to the States, are reserved to the States respectively, or to the people.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Eleventh.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Limitation of judicial power.</p></body></floatingText>The Judicial power of the United States shall not be construed to extend to any suit, in law or equity, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced or prosecuted against one of the United States, by citizens of another State, or by citizens or subjects of any foreign State.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Twelfth.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Election of President and Vice Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent.</p></body></floatingText>The electors shall meet in their respective States, and vote, by ballot, for President and Vice President, one of whom, at least, shall not be an inhabitant of the same State with themselves: they shall name in their ballots the person voted for as President, and in distinct ballots the person voted for as Vice President; and they shall make distinct lists of all persons voted for as Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, and of all persons voted for as Vice President, and of the number of votes for each; which lists they shall sign and certify, and transmit, sealed, to the seat of Government of the United States, directed to the President of the Senate: the President of the Senate shall, in the presence of the Senate, and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives, open all the certificates, and the votes shall then be counted: the person having the greatest number of votes for President shall be the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, if such number be a majority of the whole num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of electors appointed; and if no persons have such majority, then from the persons having the highest numbers, not exceeding three, on the list of those voted for as President, the House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1271" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>sentatives shall choose immediately, by ballot, the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent. But in choosing the President, the votes shall be taken by States, the representation from each State having one vote: a quorum for this purpose shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sist of a member or members from two-thirds of the States, and a majority of all the States shall be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to a choice. And if the House of Representatives shall not choose a President, whenever the right of choice shall devolve upon them, before the fourth day of March next following, then the Vice President shall act as President, as in the case of the death or other constitutional disability of the President.</p>
<p>The person having the greatest number of votes as Vice President shall be the Vice President, if such a number be a majority of the whole number of electors appointed; and if no person have a majority, then, from the two highest numbers on the list, the Senate shall choose the Vice-President: a quorum for the purpose shall consist of two-thirds of the whole number of Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ators, and a majority of the whole number shall be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to a choice.</p>
<p>But no person constitutionally ineligible to the office of President, shall be eligible to that of Vice President of the United States.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ADDITIONAL ARTICLES.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Thirteenth.</head>
<p>Section 1. Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to their jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Section 2. Congress shall have power to enforce this Article by appropriate legislation.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Fourteenth.</head>
<p>Section 1. All persons born or naturalized in the United States and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are citizens of the United States and of the State where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in they reside. No State shall make or enforce any law <pb n="1272" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prive any person of life, liberty, or property without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</p>
<p>Section 2. Representatives shall be appointed among the several States according to their respective num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers, counting the whole number of persons in each State, excluding Indians not taxed; but when the right to vote at any election for the choice of Electors for President and Vice President of the United States, Representatives in Congress, the Executive and Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial officers of a State, or the members of the Legislature thereof, is denied to any of the male inhabitants of such State (being twenty-one years of age and citizens of the United States), or in any way abridged, except for participation in rebellion or other crime, the basis of representation therein shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duced in the proportion which the number of such male citizens shall bear to the whole number of male citizens twenty-one years of age in said State.</p>
<p>Section 3. No person shall be a Senator or Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative in Congress, or Elector, or President, or Vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />President, or hold any office, civil or military, under the United States, or under any State, who, having pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viously taken an oath as a member of Congress, or as an officer of the United States, or as a member of any State Legislature, or as an executive or judicial officer of any State, to support the Constitution of the United States, shall have engaged in insurrection, or rebellion against the same, or given aid or comfort to the enemies thereof; but Congress may, by a vote of two-thirds of each House, remove such disability.</p>
<p>Section 4. The validity of the public debt of the United States; authorized by law, including debts in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curred for payment of pensions and bounties, for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices in suppressing insurrection or rebellion, shall not be questioned: but neither the United States nor any State shall assume or pay any debt or obligation incurred in aid of insurrection or rebellion against the United States, or any claim for the loss or emancipation of any <pb n="1273" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the United States.</fw>slave. But all such debts, obligations, and claims, shall be held illegal and void.</p>
<p>Section 5. The Congress shall have power to enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provisions of this Article.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article the Fifteenth.</head>
<p>Section 1. The right of the citizens of the United States to vote shall not be denied or abridged by the United States, or by any State, on account of race, color, or previous condition of servitude.</p>
<p>Section 2. The Congress shall have power to enforce this Article by appropriate legislation.</p>
<pb n="1274" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" />
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>