<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1041" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" />
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">ABSTRACT<lb/> OF<lb/> PRIVATE ACTS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS<lb/> PASSED BY THE EIGHTH CONGRESS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Daniel Alexander,&#8221; approved February 5th, 1844&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to Daniel Alexander, assignee of Samuel Moore, a patent for three hundred and sixty-nine acres of land, being the augmentation of said Moore&#8217;s headright, upon proof of said assignment and loss of the same.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act legitimatizing certain children therein named,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 27th 1844&#8212;declares Nancy Jane, and Sarah Bour<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />land, the issue of James Bourland and Mary Rochels, to be legiti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mate, and lawful heirs of James Bourland, and capable of inherit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.</p>
<p>&#8220;A Joint Resolution for the relief of Thomas Bristow,&#8221; passed January 16th, 1844&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to respect, as fully as if the same had been recommended by the Board of Travelling Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, the certificate, in favor of Thomas Bristow, issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of the county of Shelby, for<pb n="1042" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw> two-thirds of a league and labor of land, the same being a part of the head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right claim of the said Thomas Bristow.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act transferring a certain appropriation made the twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seventh of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, for the redemption of son and nephew of J. Cox,&#8221; passed January 12th 1844&#8212;places at the disposition of William Cox the amount of an appropriation &#8220;made in an act,&#8221; approved January 27th 1842, for the redemption of certain Texian prisoners.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Parker S. Doss,&#8221; passed January 6th 1844&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to the said Doss a head-right certificate for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act to legitimate certain children therein named,&#8221; approved January 14th 1844&#8212;declares Mary Dunn and Martha Dunn, the issue of Thomas Dunn and his wife, Eliza Dunn, legitimate, and capable of inheriting.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Maria Jesusa Garcia,&#8221; approved Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 1st 1844&#8212;gives to the said Maria Jesusa Garcia a pension of one hundred dollars, per annum, for and during the period of her natural life, to commence from and after the first day of January 1843.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Monia E. Goodwin, Louisiana Harris, Eliza V. Harris, and other heirs of Robert W. Harris, deceased,&#8221; approved February 3d 1844&#8212;requires the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue a certificate, for three hundred and twenty acres of land, to the said Monia E. Goodwin, Louisiana Harris, Eliza V. Harris, and other heirs, at law, of Robert W. Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris, deceased, in place of certificate No. 217, (second class) issued by the Board of Land Commisioners, for the county of Bastrop, to said Robert W. Harris, dated December 19th 1839.</p>
<pb n="1043" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of John Hibbins, deceased,&#8221; approved February 2d 1844&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to amend, in a certain manner, the orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal title to a certain league of land, situated on the east bank of the La Vaca, and to deliver a certified copy of the title, so amended, to the heirs of the said John Hibbins, deceased.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act to legitimate John S. Hodges, and declare him capable of inheriting, as a lawful heir of James Hodges, Senior,&#8221; approved January 27th 1844&#8212;declares the said John S. Hodges a legitimate child of the said James Hodges, Senior, and capable, in law, of inheriting the property of his said parent, in the same manner as if he had been born in lawful wedlock.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Mrs. Sarah N. Hubert,&#8221; passed by a constitutional majority, February 1st, 1844&#8212;requires the Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditor of Public Accounts &#8220;to audit the sum of five hundred and thirteen dollars,&#8221; the same being the amount due to Mrs. Sarah N. Hubert, for and on account of mail transportation; and directs the Treasurer to pay the same out of ally money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Mary Johnston,&#8221; approved February 3d 1844&#8212;authorizes and requires the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to respect the claim of Mary Johnston, for one league and labor of land, and to issue patents for the same, provided, the government dues be paid thereon.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Stephen Jones and H. H. Hall,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 5th 1844&#8212;requires the Secretary of War and Marine to issue to the said Stephen Jones, for and in considera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of his services in the seige of San Antonio, in the year 1835, a certificate for 640 acres of land; also a warrant to the said H. H. Hall, for 320 acres of land, for and in consideration of his ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices, in the army of Texas, from July 4th 1836, until the 4th Oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tober following, as per discharge from Captain W. Scurlock.</p>
<pb n="1044" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>&#8220;A Joint Resolution for the relief of League, Andrews &#38; Co.,&#8221; passed February 5th, 1844&#8212;releases the said League, Andrews &#38; Co. from the payment of judgments, obtained against them, in favor of the Republic of Texas, for the sum of $2822 78 (Texas promissory notes) together with the interest thereon, from the date of the rendition of said judgments, provided, the said League, Andrews &#38; Co. relinquish to the Government their claim, for the schooner Correo, for the sum of $3,500, par funds.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Samuel Lemons, his heirs and assigns,&#8221; approved February 2d 1844&#8212;requires the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land-Office to respect the certificate of the said Samuel Lemons, number six, issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners, for the county of Red River, for one league and labor of land, and that patents be issued for the same.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Antonio Menchaca,&#8221; approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 3d 1844&#8212;authorizes the Auditor to audit the claims of Antonio Menchaca, for services rendered, as Captain in the army, under the commission of the President, from July 1st to September 11th 1842.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act to permit the Administratrix of Neil Munn, deceased, to keep together the property of said deceased,&#8221; approved January 8th 1844&#8212;invests, upon certain conditions, the said administratrix with the curatorship of the estate of the said Neil Munn, deceased.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution making an appropriation for the pay of Sam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uel Gr. Novel, for services rendered the Republic of Texas as a soldier,&#8221; approved February 5th 1844&#8212;requires the Auditor of Public Accounts to audit the account of the said Samuel G. Novel, for $150., for five months&#8217; services as a soldier, under the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand of Captain Hays, in the year 1842.</p>
<pb n="1045" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of Captain Robert Oliver,&#8221; approved February 2nd 1844&#8212;directs that the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land-Office respect the head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate of Robert Oliver, for one-third of a league of land; and that a patent be issued to the heirs of said Robert Oliver, deceased, or their attorney, for the lands, lawfully located, under said certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of John Saunders,&#8221; approved February 5th 1844&#8212;requires the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to the said John Saunders, his heirs or assigns, a certificate for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act requiring the Auditor to audit the accounts of the heirs of Erastus Smith,&#8221; approved February 2nd 1844&#8212;requires the Auditor and Comptroller to audit the accounts of the heirs of Erastus Smith, for $300., out of the amount due them; also for $150., for the year 1844; makes the requisite appropriation for the payment of the same; and repeals the joint resolution, entitled &#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of the family of Erastus Smith,&#8221; approved December 18th 1837.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of George W. Smyth, as administrator of the estate of Joseph Grigsby, deceased,&#8221; approved February 3d 1844&#8212;prescribes the manner in which said estate may be disposed of by the said administrator.</p>
<p>&#8220;A Joint Resolution for the relief of George W. Smyth, late Commissioner to run the boundary line between the United States and Texas,&#8221; approved February 5th 1844&#8212;appropriates the sum of $1,818 92, to be paid to the said George W. Smyth, for his ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices, as Commissioner, in running the boundary line aforesaid.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act to legitimate certain children therein named,&#8221; approved December 29th 1843&#8212;declares Charles James Spikes and Emeline Spikes, children of James Spikes and Lucy Taylor, legitimate, and capable, in law, of inheriting their parents&#8217; property, in the same manner as if they had been born in lawful wedlock.</p>
<pb n="1046" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of James Truitt and Andrew J. Truitt, in relation to their head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certificates,&#8221; approved January 1st 1844&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spect the head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certificates of the said James Truitt and An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drew J. Truitt, and declares the same to be as valid, as if they had been recommended, for patents, by the Travelling Board of Land Commissioners.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Thomas Wm. Ward,&#8221; approved February 5th 1844&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit the sum of $125., in favor of the said Thomas Wm. Ward, in acordance with a joint resolution, fixing the compensation of Heads of Departments and Bureaux, &#38;c., approved January 1st, 1841.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">Y</head>
<p>Joint Resolution for the relief of the Administrator of Thomas D. Yocum&#8217;s estate,&#8221; approved February 5th 1844&#8212;authorizes the said administrator to remove, upon certain terms and conditions, the administration of the said estate from the county of Jefferson to the county of Harris.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>