<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="821" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main"><b>LAWS</b> PASSED BY <b>THE SEVENTH CONGRESS</b> OF THE <b>REPUBLIC OF TEXAS</b></head>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>WASHINGTON:<lb/> 1843</byline>
<pb n="822" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="823" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub"><b>LAWS OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</b></head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an act, entitled an act to divide the County of Red River, and to create and establish the Counties of Bowie and Lamar.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the ninth section of the above recited act, to which this is a sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement, be so amended as to make it the duty of the Clerk of the County and Probate Courts of said Red River County, to transmit all the papers, of every description, to the Counties of Bowie and Lamar, which belong to said Counties according to the division as recited in the above act; any thing in the law to the contrary not<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />withstanding; and that this act take effect from and after is pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>26th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To designate the Southern boundary of Lamar County, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the main stream, or principal south fork of the Sulphur Fork of Red River be, and is hereby declared to be the South boundary of said County.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That George Wilson, Jesse<pb n="824" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> Shelton, Joel Wafer, Joseph Bowerman and Doctor John Davis, be, and they are hereby appointed, or a majority of them, to as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />certain the geographical centre of said County, and proceed to denominate some two or more points, within three miles of the said centre so ascertained, having due respect to donations, that may be offered for a town site for the use of said County. The Commissioners shall then proceed to issue writs of election to the different precincts, directed to some Justice of the Peace in the same, to open and hold an election on a day named by said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, by giving ten days notice of the same, for the points in nomination; and the said Justice shall make return of said election, on the third day thereafter; and the place having the high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est number of constitutional votes, shall be declared the County Seat of Lamar; and said site shall be named by said Commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said Commissioners shall proceed to lay out a town, sell lots, contract for public buildings and do all things necessary for the promotion of the interest of the County, for which services they shall be allowed three dollars per day, out of the proceeds of the sales of the County town lots.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all the records of the Courts held at said town, when the same shall be located in accordance with the provisions of this act, shall be legal and valid, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>26th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Transferring an unexpended appropriation for the contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses and the pay of the seventh Congress.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That four thousand eight hundred dollars of the unexpended appropriation for the protection of the frontier, placed at the disposition of the Executive by act of Congress, passed Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary the third, one thousand eight hundred and forty two, be, and the same is hereby transferred and appropriated in the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing manner, to wit: five hundred dollars to meet the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses of the two Houses of the seventh Congress,<pb n="825" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> and the other four thousand three hundred dollars to be pro rata distributed between the Senators and Representatives and the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers of the two Houses of the seventh Congress.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>26th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to a joint resolution granting further time for the payment of Government Dues, and the return of Field Notes, approved November twenty seventh, one thousand eight hundred and forty one.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Senate, and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the provisions of a joint resolution, approved November twenty seventh, one thousand eight hundred and forty one, granting fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther time for the payment of government dues and the return of field notes, be, and the same is hereby extended and declared in force until the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty six.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>27th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for collecting and conveying Indian prisoners to the Waco village.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas the Honorable Congress has recently been assured, that the different tribes of Indians have in their possession no less than eleven Texian prisoners, and that they will be brought to the Waco village on the ninth day of February next, with the intention on the part of the Indians, to exchange them for their own people held by us as prisoners; and whereas we firm<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly believe that unless all the Indian prisoners, which are now<pb n="826" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> in our possession, are restored to their different tribes on the day set apart to meet them at the Waco village, that they will neither ratify the treaty of peace which has been commenced with them, nor deliver over to us our Texian brethren; the releasement of whom from Indian captivity is a matter of vital interest to their relatives as well as to every feeling heart: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the President is hereby authorized and required to employ such person or persons, as may be necessary to collect all the Indian prisoners now in the possession of Texian citizens, or in the pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session of the Lipan or Tancahua tribes of Indians; and to convey the said Indian prisoners to the Waco village, by the time set apart to conclude a treaty of peace with the different tribes of Indians on our Northern and North-Western borders.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That any person or persons who shall refuse to deliver to such person or persons, as may be em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed by the President, any Indian prisoner or prisoners, which he, she, or they may have in possession, shall, for each and every offence, be fined in a sum not less than five hundred, nor more than one thousand dollars, at the discretion of the court, to be recovered by motion against the offending party in the District Court, (three days previous notice being given,) or on conviction on indictment.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That if any person shall refuse to deliver up such Indian prisoner or prisoners, it shall be lawful for the prisoner, or any other person for him, to apply to any Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Judge, Chief Justice of the County, or Justice of the Peace, for a writ of Habeas Corpus; and if found to be an Indian prisoner, he shall be discharged from the service of the person who may detain him, or her, and placed in the custody of the person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, whom the President may appoint to carry out the provisions of the previous sections.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the person or persons, so employed by the President, shall, each, receive four dollars per diem, so long as he or they may reasonably be employed in collect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and conducting the Indian prisoners to the treaty ground.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the President is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to purchase comfortable clothing and blankets for the Indian prisoners, before they are delivered over to the differ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent tribes; and that the sum of two thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for that purpose, as well as for the purpose of paying the expenses of conveying the prisoners to<pb n="827" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> the Waco village; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>28th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize John McMullen to order the election of County officers in the County of Bexar, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That during the absence of the Chief Justice of said County of Bexar, John McMullen, one of the associate Justices, be, and he is hereby authorized to do and perform all matters and things touching the duties of said Chief Justice, until the said County shall be or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>29th Dec., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend an act, entitled an act to reduce into one and amend the several acts concerning executions, approved January twenty seventh, one thousand eight hundred and forty two.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the twenty first section of the above recited act be so amended as to read, that the provisions of the seventeenth, eighteenth, and nineteenth sections of this act shall apply only to debts and other legal liabilities contracted and incurred prior to the first day of May, one thousand eight hundred and forty two, instead of March, as mentioned in said section of the above recited act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>3d Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="828" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Making appropriations for the support of the Government for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the following sums be, and they are hereby appropriated for the service of the Government, for the year one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty three, viz:</p>
<p>For pay and mileage of members of the seventh Congress, fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For the pay of Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives, dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the recess of Congress, seven hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the seventh Congress, two thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the President of the Republic, five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the Vice President, one thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the President&#8217;s Private Secretary, seven hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For Contingent expenses of Executive Department, three thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to Secretary of State, one thousand five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of State Department, one thousand six hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For hire of porters, subject to the control of the Secretary of State, three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Post Office Bureau, five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>For transporting the mails for the year one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty three, twelve thousand dollars, and all the moneys arising from the receipts of the Post Office Department, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Secretary of the Treasury, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Treasury Department, five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Comptroller, one thousand dollars</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Comptroller&#8217;s office, three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Treasurer, one thousand dollars.</p>
<pb n="829" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Treasurer&#8217;s office, three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Auditor, one thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Auditor&#8217;s office, three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the Secretary of War and Marine, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the War Department, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the Attorney General, one thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the Attorney General&#8217;s office, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, one thousand five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Draftsman of the General Land Office, eight hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the General Land Office, two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation for twenty one clerks employed in the va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rious offices and Departments of the Government, fifteen thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation of Charg&#233; d&#8217;Affaires, nine thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Secretary of Legation to the United States, twenty-five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For the relief of George S. McIntosh, former Secretary of Lega<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to France, five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of Legation, one thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to Captain of Ordnance, Armorer, and la<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />borers employed in Ordnance department, two thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of Ordnance department, subject to the control of the Secretary of War and Marine, five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>For Indian purposes, subject to the control of the Executive, ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Justice of the Republic and seven associate Judges, fourteen thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses, of the Supreme Court, five hundred dollars, subject to the order of the Chief Justice.</p>
<p>For compensation to the Clerk of the Supreme Court, five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>For printing of laws and journals of the Seventh Congress, five thousand dollars.</p>
<pb n="830" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>For pension to Joseph Cecil, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty two, three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pension to Jospeh Cecil, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty three, three hundred dollars; seventy five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars to be paid quarterly.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the unexpended balances of the appropriations for the salaries of officers of the Government, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty two, shall be transferred to and made a part of the appropriations for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty three, in addition to the appropriations specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the compensations allowed by this act to the officers of the civil list, shall be computed from the first day of December, one thousand eight hundred and forty two, or from the time of their appointment.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the officers of the Seventh Congress shall receive the same per diem pay as the officers of the Sixth Congress; and the sum of five thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury be, and he is hereby required to issue Exchequer bills to pay the foregoing appropriation, and disburse them in such manner that not a greater amount shall be in circulation at any one time, than fifty thousand dollars, in denominations as now required by law, until the first day of March, one thousand eight hundred and forty three, after which time, it shall be his duty to issue the bills in denominations of one, two, three, five, ten, and twenty dollars, issuing as many of the smaller denominations as may be practicable under the provisions of this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the sum of ______ dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to procure the engrav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and signing of the bills to meet the foregoing appropriations.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>6th Jan., 1846</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="831" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the several laws regulating the Post Office Department.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, the following, and none others, shall be regarded as mail routes, on which the public mail shall be transported, that is to say:</p>
<p>No. One. From Galveston to Matagorda, via San Luis and Ve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lasco.</p>
<p>No. Two. From Galveston to Houston.</p>
<p>No. Three. From Houston to Patillo&#8217;s, via Liberty and Beau<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mont.</p>
<p>No. Pour. From Houston to Washington.</p>
<p>No. Five. From Houston to Egypt, via Richmond.</p>
<p>No. Six. From Egypt to Victoria, via Menefee&#8217;s.</p>
<p>No. Seven. From San Antonio to Rutersville, via Gonzales, Obarr&#8217;s and La Grange.</p>
<p>No. Eight. From Rutersville to Cincinnati, via Mount Vernon, Independence, Washington, Montgomery and Huntsville.</p>
<p>No. Nine. From Cincinnati to San Augustine, via Crockett and Nacogdoches.</p>
<p>No. Ten. From San Augustine to Sabine Town, via Milam.</p>
<p>No. Eleven. From San Augustine to Daingerfield, via Shelby<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville and Marshall.</p>
<p>No. Twelve. From Daingerfield to Fort English, via Boston, De Kalb, Savannah and Clarksville.</p>
<p>No. Thirteen. From Jasper to Sabine Town.</p>
<p>No. Fourteen. From Velasco to Washington, via Brazoria, Co<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lumbia, Richmond, San Felipe and Burleigh.</p>
<p>No. Fifteen. From Matagorda to La Grange, via Egypt and Co<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lumbus.</p>
<p>No. Sixteen. Form La Grange to Austin, via Bastrop.</p>
<p>No. Seventeen. From Victoria to Gonzales, Via Cuero.</p>
<p>No. Eighteen. From Independence to Nashville, via Caldwell.</p>
<p>No. Nineteen. From Washington to Franklin, via Boone<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville.</p>
<p>No. Twenty. From Huntsville to Swartwout.</p>
<p>No. Twenty One. From Swartwout to Jasper, via Town Bluff.</p>
<pb n="832" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That upon the routes mentioned in the preceding section of this act, the mails shall be transported weekly:&#8212;Provided, that nothing herein contained, shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />garded as conflicting with the provisions of the third section of the act, entitled &#8220;an act to amend and reduce into one, the several laws regulating the Post Office Department;&#8221; approved February the sixth, one thousand eight hundred and forty.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>6th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the law regulating proceedings in Justices Courts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That hereafter, when any suit shall be commenced before a Justice of the Peace on a note of hand, bill, or other evidence of debt, signed by the defendant, if it shall appear, on the return of the proper officer, that the defendant has been duly served with process&#8212;the said Justice shall proceed at the time appointed for trial, to give judgment against the defendant for whatever amount may appear to be due by the instrument sued on; unless the defendant, on being called, shall appear and make defence; in which case the trial shall proceed as now regulated by law in other cases: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, the amount does not exceed the Justice&#8217;s jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That so much of the eleventh sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of an act, approved twentieth December, one thousand eight hundred and thirty six, entitled an act organizing Justices Courts, &#38;c.; as conflicts with the provisions of this act, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>6th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="833" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the payment of Assessors of Taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That whenever an assessment of the direct taxes shall have been prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erly made and returned, it shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury, to draw a draft or drafts, in favor of the assessor, upon the Sheriff of the County in which he is the assessor, for the amount which may be due as his compensation, which draft or drafts shall be receivable in payment of the taxes due the Republic, in the County in which the assessment has been made, or paid by the Sheriff out of the first money by him collected of the taxes of such County; and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>7th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Amendatory to an act, entitled an act to amend an act to raise a revenue by direct taxation, approved February fifth, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and forty two.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the tenth section of the above recited act be so amended as to make it the duty of assessors hereafter to make their returns to the collectors of their respective counties, on the first monday of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember of each and every year, in lieu of the first day of December.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>9th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="834" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the Probate Law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That hereafter, when any person shall die intestate, or shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressly forbid it by will, the same amount of property, and the same kind&#8212;if so much belong to the estate in kind&#8212;that is exempt from sale under fieri facias, or execution, by an act approved twenty fifth January, one thousand eight hundred and thirty nine, enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled &#8220;an act to exempt certain property therein named from ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecution,&#8221; be, and the same is hereby declared to be exempt from sale by order from any Probate Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when an inventory is made out and returned to the Probate Court, of the property and effects belonging to a succession, the Judge thereof shall set apart, the property and articles as contemplated in the preceding section, for the sole use and benefit of the widow and children of the deceased.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the appraisers required to appraise property previous to its sale, be appointed by the Probate Judge at the time of issuing the order of sale, or on some day pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious to the sale, and that they be sworn by any person legally au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to administer an oath.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That so much of the Probate law as authorizes administration to be granted to the Sheriff or a Justice of the Peace be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That any testator by his last will may so provide, that no other action than the probate and registra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the will, in whatsoever county he may designate, shall be had in the Probate Courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all laws conflicting with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That appraisers, and commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners of partitions, for each day they may serve as such, shall be entitled to receive two dollars per day and no more, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>9th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="835" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the County Court of Brazoria county to levy a tax for certain purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the County Court of the county of Brazoria be, and is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to collect a tax, not exceeding one fourth of one per cent, on all propery being in said county, on which an assessment has been made for the year 1842, to be appropriated for the complet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the court house and jail in said county; and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To incorporate the Matagorda Caney Navigation Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there shall be and is hereby established a corporate body, under the name of the Matagorda Caney Navigation Company, with a capital of sixty thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of five hundred dollars each&#8212;that said corporation shall have power to sue and be sued by its said name, to have a common seal, and the same to break and after, to receive donations, to borrow money and to hold lands and personal property for the purpose of carry<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing out the objects of this incorporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That books for the subscription of stock shall be opened on the first day of March next at the house of Abram Shepard, in the county of Matagorda, under the superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendence of the following Commissioners: James T. Belknap, James Shepard, John Duncan and Abram Shepard, or any two of them, and said books shall remain open until the full amount of said stock shall have been subscribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That after said stock shall have been subscribed, the said corporate body shall be governed by such officers and by-laws, as the said stockholders shall adopt:&#8212;Provided, that nothing in such by-laws shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to or conflict with the Constitution of the Republic, and<pb n="836" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> in the election of officers and adoption of by-laws, each share shall be entitled to a vote, and voting by proxy shall be allowed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That said corporate body by a majority of votes, may from time to time order instalments of said capital stock to pe paid on each and every share, and in case any instalment thus ordered to be paid shall remain unpaid upon any share or shares, for the space of thirty days after the same shall have become due, it shall be lawful for the officers of said corporate body to sell such share or shares to the highest bidder for cash.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said corporate body shall have power to clear out the channel of old Caney Creek in the county of Matagorda, and to improve the navigation thereof, by dams or locks, and otherwise, from the rise or head of the channel of said creek to the mouth thereof into the Gulf of Mexico, or so far up the channel of said creek as it will be practicable to render the same navigable, and shall have power to use the banks of said creek, and the earth and timber thereon for that purpose, and to navigate said creek.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That in case any owner or owners of the soil in said creek shall refuse to surrender the same to the said corporate body for said purposes, then said corporate body shall have power to apply to any Justice of the Peace in said county, whose duty it shall be to summon a jury of six free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders, not stockholders, to estimate the damage which such owner or owners of the soil in said creek will suffer by the provisions of this act, and by the prosecution of the work in this act contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated, and it shall be the duty of the said corporate body to pay the damage so estimated to the said owner or owners, and then the title to the soil in said creek shall be vested in said corporate body.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That after the said corporate body, shall have rendered said creek navigable from a place near its mouth, commonly called the town of Manhattan, up said creek to any point fifteen miles above where the tide ebbs and flows, the said corporate body shall have the right to charge and collect tolls on all vessels, steam-boats, rafts and freight passing up or down said creek.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That after thirty years, from and after the passage of this act, it shall be lawful for the county of Matagorda to pay to the said corporate body, the full amount of the expenses of clearing out the channel of said creek, and of constructing the said works, and of the damages that<pb n="837" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> may have been assessed under the provisions of the sixth section of tins act; and upon said payment, the right of said corporate body to charge tolls shall cease and determine, and this act shall become null and void: Provided, that if said county shall not make said payment within one year after the expiration of said thirty years, then the said right to charge tolls as aforesaid shall ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ist in said Corporate body, and this act shall remain in force for thirty years thereafter; at the expiration of which period, the said county shall have the further space of one year in which to make said payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That this charter shall not be so construed as to give to said corporate body, any banking privileges whatever; and that said corporate body shall not in any case make use of its capital stock for any other purposes than those herein set forth, and for the purpose of navigating said creek by steam-boats, lighters, or otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all vessels belonging to the Government of Texas, shall pass on said creek free from tolls.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That said corporate body shall complete the work contemplated by this act, so far up said creek as is mentioned in the seventh section, within five years after the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the protection of the Sea Coast.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the sum of seven thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated for the erection and manning of fortifications for the better protection of Galveston harbor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the sum of one thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the protection at the mouth of the Brazos river; and that the sum of one thousand dollars be appropriated to the defence of the pass into Matagorda bay.</p>
<pb n="838" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That a squad of ten men, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded by a second Lieutenant, be raised and stationed at the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tification on Galveston, to take charge of the guns and munitions of war; the expense of which, to be paid out of the appropriation for the protection of that place.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the President of the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic be, and he is hereby authorized and required to carry the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act into effect; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
********<salute>To incorporate the Galveston Orphan&#8217;s Friend Society.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That Rhoda Huckins, Sarah Sydnor, Henrietta Barnard, and Ann N. Jones, and their associates, be, and they are hereby created and declared to be a body politic and corporate, by the corporate name of the Galveston Orphan&#8217;s Friend Society, and by that name shall enjoy perpetual succession, shall be capable in law of contracting and being contracted with, may sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, and shall have all the rights and privileges incident to corporations of a like character.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said corporation shall have power to take and hold by purchase, devise, donation, or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, both real and personal estate, not to exceed in value fifty thousand dollars, for the purpose of founding, erecting and sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining in the city of Galveston, an asylum for destitute orphans, and to have and use a common seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said corporation shall have full power to pass and adopt such by-laws, rules, regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and orders, as they shall from time to time think proper, for their own government, not inconsistent with the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of the Republic, and to appoint from their own body, or otherwise, all such officers, under such names and titles, as they may at any time think proper for the conducting and management of the bosiness and affairs of said corporation,<pb n="839" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> with such limitations, and restrictions as they may impose.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the County Courts of Brazoria and Galveston to raise a Revenue by license on Public Ferries.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the County Courts for Brazoria and Galveston counties be, and they are hereby authorized and empowered to let out the ferries in said counties for any term of years, not more than five, on such terms as they may think proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all persons shall give suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient bond and security for the faithful discharge of their duty, and in case of neglect or failure to discharge the duties promptly, the said County Courts may revoke and annul the right to the ferry; and all laws conflicting with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an act supplementary to an act, to detect fraudu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lent land certificates and to provide for the issuing patents to legal claimants.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all suits contemplated by the first section of the act to which this is a supplement, shall be commenced on or before the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty four, and not there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="840" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Directing the auditing of the claims for carrying the mail for the years one thousand eight, hundred and forty one, and one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and forty two.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor be, and he is hereby authorized to audit the residue of the claims against this Government, for carrying the mails for the years one thousand eight hundred and forty one, and one thousand eight hundred and forty two, and the sum of six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars for pay of mail contractors for one thousand eight hundred and thirty nine; which said claims, when so audited, shall be receivable in payment of direct tax at the same rate as Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chequer bills are received for the same dues.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force and take effect from and after is passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an act making appropriations for the support of the Government for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the act, to which this is a supplement, shall be in force and take effect from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the sum of one thousand five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the order of the Secretary of the Treasury, to procure the engraving and signing of the Exchequer bills ordered to be issued by the act to which this is a supplement; and the further Sum of two hundred dollars for printing Treasury warrants for Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller&#8217;s office, and other printing, including printing for one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and forty two.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the sum of five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any money that may hereafter come into the Treasury, and not <pb n="841" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> otherwise appropriated, for the payment of the contingent expen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ses of the Treasury Department, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty two.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That in addition to the appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation already made for the pay and mileage of members of Congress, the further sum of three thousand seven hundred and fifty one dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the arrearages due the members of the Sixth Congress, at the extra session in the summer of one thousand eight hundred and forty two.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend an act entitled an act, regulating sales by judgment or decree of a Probate Court, or Court of Chancery, approved, Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 4th, 1841.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all sales of the property of any deceased person, made by any ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministrator, executor, or guardian, under or by order of any judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment or decree of any Probate Court, or Court of Chancery, shall be made upon a, credit of twelve months, with security, to the sat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isfaction of such administrator, executor, or guardian, or for cash, as the said Probate Court, or Court of Chancery, shall deem most advisable for the interest of the estate of said deceased person, and of the creditors thereof; Provided, that all such sales for cash shall be made upon appraisement, and shall not be made for less than two thirds of the appraised value of the property to be sold; and provided, that in case any property ordered to be sold for cash, shall not sell for two thirds of its appraisement, it shall be within the discretion of the Judge to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />order the sale, on a credit of twelve months.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That a like notice, as that required for sales under execution, shall be given for all sales to be made by virtue of this act; and that on all sales for cash, by virtue of this act, the Chief Justice of the county where such <pb n="842" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> sales are to be made, or in his absence, the associate Justices, shall, on the day of such sales, or a day previous, appoint three apprais<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, who shall on oath appraise the value of the property to be sold; Provided, that the heirs or legatees of such estate, if present in person, or by attorney, or guardian, shall have the right of ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointing one of said appraisers, by making said appointment in writing, filed in the clerk&#8217;s office of the Probate Court of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty where said sale is to take place, at least three days before the day of sale; and provided, that all such appraisers shall be free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders of the county where such sale is to be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws contrary to, or conflicting with this act be, and the same are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after the passage thereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the establishment and maintenance of peace, and to regulate friendly intercourse with the Indians.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there shall be, and there is hereby created and established, a Bureau of Indian affairs, to be attached to the War Department; and the chief cleric of that Department shall perform the duties without any additional compensation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the President shall cause to be laid before Congress, at each regular session, a report of the affairs and transactions of the Indian Bureau, with his views and recommendations in relation thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have power, whenever he may deem it necessary, to appoint interpreters, not exceeding four; whose salaries, each, shall not exceed two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have power to appoint as many agents, not exceeding four, as may be necessary for the preservation of peace among the border tribes;<pb n="843" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> the salary of each of which shall not exceed five hundred dollars per annum; and one superintendent, whose salary shall not exceed seven hundred and fifty dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That all officers and agents, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by the President and connected with Indian affairs, shall take an oath to support the Constitution and laws of the Republic, and obey the instructions of the President.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all agents shall report at least twice a year to the Executive, and oftener if required so to do; communicating all facts and intelligence connected with the performance of their duties, and every thing affecting the welfare of the Republic and the Indians, that they may have come to their knowledge.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the President shall cause to be established trading houses, or posts; which posts or trading houses shall be established as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>No. 1. On or near the south fork of the Trinity, some where between the lower and upper Cross Timbers.</p>
<p>No. 2. At or near the Comanche Peak.</p>
<p>No. 3. At or near the old San Saba Fort, or mission.</p>
<p>No. 4. At or near Porto Vandero.</p>
<p>No. 5. At or near the junction of the Moras and Rio Grande.</p>
<p>The places to be designated by the commissioners that make the treaty with the Indians, not to exceed twenty five miles from the places designated in this section..</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the traders shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed and licensed by the President, and give bond, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the President, for the faithful performance of their duties; and at all times be subject to the instructions of the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, or his proper officers. Any person or persons, trading with the Indians without said appointment and license, shall be liable to indictment and punishment in any county in the Republic, by fine, in a sum not less than fifty, nor more than five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars for each and every offence, and imprisonment at the discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Court; and such persons thus licensed, shall pay into the Treasury of the Republic such sums as the President may require, and no license shall extend beyond one year, but may be renewable.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That no agent shall in any wise be connected with the Indian trade, unless by the express appointment and license of the Government therefor; and only then, when it is evident some useful end is, by that course, to be attained; but where a trader may act as agent he shall<pb n="844" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> receive no salary; and where such agent may be a trader, he shall make out his invoices and swear to them before some Chief Justice of a county, or Justice of the Peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That each trader shall render, under oath, to the Indian agent, a full and accurate invoice of all goods, wares and merchandize of every description whatsoever, taken to the trading<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house; which invoice said agent shall transmit, retaining a copy thereof, to the Bureau of Indian affairs.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That no person or persons shall, under any circumstances, trade, within the settlements, with any Indian for any horse, mule, or other property, unless by express permission, in writing, of some Chief Justice or Justice of the Peace; and then only in the presence of two or more witnesses of good character.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That whenever any property is found among the whites, belonging to the Indians, it shall be the duty of any Chief Justice, Justice of the Peace, Sheriff or Constable, to see that the same is restored; and, on the other hand, whenever property belonging to the whites is found among the Indians, the same shall be restored in like manner by the In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dian agent.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That no trader shall furnish any warlike stores to the Indians, unless by permission of the President.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That no ardent spirits, or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toxicating liquors, of any kind, shall, under any circumstances, be introduced within the limits of any nation of Indians, or at any trading<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house; and any such liquors, found within ten miles of the line of trading<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />houses, shall be destroyed by the agent, or any other person; and the person or persons introducing, or attempting to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troduce the same, shall be liable therefor to indictment in any county of the Republic, and, upon conviction, to a fine of not less than fifty nor more than five hundred dollars; and otherwise pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished at the discretion of the Court. If such person or persons are in the employment of the Government, they shall be immed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iately removed by the President.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That no person or persons shall, without special permission of the President, pass the line of trad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />houses, and then only for friendly purposes; nor shall any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons reside among, or remain within the limits of the territory assigned to the Indians, unless by express direction of the President.</p>
<pb n="845" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the Indians shall not come below the line of their territory, without the special permission of an agent, and then only when accompanied by one or more white men, appointed by the agent for that purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That any person or persons, who shall attempt to molest the Indians or their property, while they remain peaceable under the treaties, shall be held guilty of felony and punished accordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Be it further enacted, That any killing or outrage whatsoever, committed by a white man upon any Indian, in time of peace, shall be punished in the same manner as though the Indian were a white man: Provided, any such Indian or Indians shall not be within the limits of any settlement in violation of the provisions of this law; and the person or persons so offending, shall be liable to indictment, and punished in any court in the Republic.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. Be it further enacted, That any person or persons, who shall attempt to raise a force for the purpose of making war upon the Indians, while at peace, without direct authority from the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, shall be held guilty of felony, and punished accordingly; and fined, where their property will admit of the assessment, in a sum not less than fifty, nor more than five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have power to make such arrangements and regulations with the several tribes of Indians as he may deem expedient for the establishment and preservation of peace, and the promotion of the common wel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fare.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have power to procure the release of prisoners held by the Indians, upon such terms as he may deem advisable.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. Be it further enacted, That in making any treaties with the Indian tribes, the commissioners are hereby required to insert an article, if practicable, reserving to the Republic the right of working mines in the Indian Territory; and the President is hereby authorized to grant permission to proper persons to work any mines within the Indian Territory, under such restrictions as he may think proper; and the Republic shall receive five per cent., on the net proceeds, from all such mines.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have power to regulate the relative grades of Indians in council; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>14th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="846" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the protection of the Western and the South Western frontier, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That immediately slier the passage of this act, the two Houses of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress shall proceed to elect, by joint ballot, a Major General of militia, who shall be commissioned by the President, and shall hold his office until the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty four, and shall be eligible to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />election.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the President of the Republic of Texas, when he issues his proclama<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for the election of members of the eighth Congress, to require the Chief Justices of the several counties of the Republic to open the polls for the election of a Major General, who shall hold his office for the term of four years, and make returns thereof to the Secretary of State, and the person receiving the highest number of votes shall be commissioned in like manner as is provided for in the preceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That should a vacancy occur in the office of Major General, as provided for in the first section of this act, the duties of that office shall devolve upon and be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charged by the senior General of brigade, commanding Texas mi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />litia.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That should the Major General of militia deem it expedient, he may at any time take the field, and command in his official capacity any number of troops: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, however, that he shall be entitled to receive no compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, unless a thousand or more troops shall be in active service.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be his duty forth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />with to organize the militia throughout the Republic, in the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing manner, viz: by dividing them into six classes, from one to six; and when so organized, he shall have power to call them into service, in the order in which they stand in said classifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation; and he shall immediately require six companies, of fiftysix men each, rank and file, from either of the classes organized as above, to act as piquets, or for such other service on the frontier as he may deem necessary; and the troops so raised shall elect<pb n="847" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> their company officers, and shall be commanded by two field of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers, one Lieutenant Colonel and a Major, who shall be elected by the companies raised in virtue of the provisions of the sixth section of this act, at the place of rendezvous to be designated by the Major General.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Major General to make the requisition for the first six companies from the third and fourth brigades, and shall serve for six months from the time they reach their respective places of rendezvous; and that the second six companies shall be drafted from the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond and first brigades; Provided, that the captain&#8217;s companies of the third and fourth brigades, which are situated on the immed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iate frontier, be, and are hereby exempt from the provisions of this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Major General shall have power to appoint his general staff: and the Adjutant General shall keep his office at the seat of Government.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That he shall be allowed to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive volunteers, in lieu of drafted men; but shall not draft or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive volunteers for a less term than six months, nor for a longer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />term than twelve months: Provided, always, that volunteers shall have the right of electing, in like manner, their company officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Major General, when in the field, to make full and complete re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports of his proceedings to the Secretary of War.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of War be required to furnish the Major General with arms, munitions, and such other necessaries as may be within his control, upon requisi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion made by that officer, for the public service.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That every person refusing to obey a call made upon him or them, in virtue of the draft, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in this act, shall pay the sum of fifty dollars, to be made out of any property belonging to him or them, in the same manner as provided for by an act approved January twenty-fourth, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and thirty nine.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That all troops, when in service, shall be under the same rules and regulations as if in the regular army of the Republic.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That all spoil, not the property of citizens of the Republic, captured from the enemy, shall be divided by the field officers equally among the captors, without regard to rank; and the property of citizens on identification shall be restored to the owners.</p>
<pb n="848" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the Quarter Master, or Quarter Master General, before entering upon the discharge of the duties of his office, shall give bond, with sufficient personal security, to be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, payable to the President of the Republic of Texas, and his successors in office, conditioned for the faithful performance of the duties of the same; and that he be, and is hereby made the disbursing officer for the purposes men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That all officers and privates shall be allowed the same pay, as provided for by law in the dragoon and cavalry service of the Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the companies raised by the provisions of this act, shall be stationed at or near the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing places, viz: two companies at the crossing of the Presido road of the Leona river; two companies at the White House on the Nueces river; one company at Tumblinson&#8217;s Block House; and the remaining company to be posted in the West, at the discretion of the commanding officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That martial law shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared and enforced from the Rio Frio and Nueces rivers, to the Rio Grande, for and during the time hostilities may exist between the Republic of Texas and Mexico.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Be it further enacted, That it shall, and is hereby made the duty of the President, to reserve and keep from circulation, of the fifty thousand dollars of Exchequer bills which, by the general appropriation bill, is the largest amount which at any time may be put in circulation, the sum of ten thousand dollars for military purposes, and to carry into effect the provisions of this bill.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. Be it further enacted, That the commanding officer shall not permit more than one subaltern, nor more than three privates from any one company, to absent themselves at the same time, nor for a longer time than three days, unless on special duty; and the commanding officer shall not absent himself for a longer time than three days, without permission from the Major General, or the Secretary of War.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, That the sum of fifty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this act; and that all laws and parts of laws, contrary to the provisions of this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed by a constitutional majority, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="849" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To legalize the proceedings of the Fall term, one thousand eight hundred and forty two, of the District Court of Bexar County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the records of the District Court of said county of Bexar, at the fall term thereof, made and entered on the sixth to the ninth, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive, of September, one thousand eight hundred and forty-two be, and the same are hereby legalized in the same manner and form, as if the Judge of said Court had signed the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the existing laws in relation to proceedings in Courts of Probate.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That in no case shall any administrator, executor, or guardian, be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to sell any other property, than that of a perishable nature, belonging to the estate of any deceased person or ward, nor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to render and settle their accounts, except upon application, by petition, of some creditor, or creditors, heir or heirs, legatee or legatees, or of some next friend of the ward, any law now in ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istence to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="850" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of the purchasers of lots in the City of Austin, and upon the City tract adjoining.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all purchasers of lots in the City of Austin, or of lots on the City tract of said City, or their assigns, who have not completed their payments for said lots, or any other of them, be, and are hereby allowed the additional term of twelve months, from and after the passage of this act, to complete said payments; and no lot, or out lot of said city shall be forfeited by reason of the non-payment of any instalment due thereon, until after the expiration of the said term of twelve months from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Amendatory to an act, to establish, and incorporate the College of De Kalb.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the tenth section of &#8220;an act to establish and incorporate the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege of De Kalb,&#8221; be so altered and amended as to allow the four leagues of land granted to the said college, to be surveyed and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented in tracts not less than six hundred and forty acres: Provided, that the same be located within the Senatorial District in which De Kalb is situated, any thing in any law to the contrary notwith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />standing; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="851" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>To modify the provisions of an act, entitled an act granting land to Emigrants.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, by an act passed by the Congress of Texas, entitled, &#8220;an act granting land to emigrants,&#8221; and bearing date the fourth day of February, 1841, a grant was made to Daniel Joseph Carroll, Henry J. Peters and others, their associates, therein named, for the introduction and settlement of emigrants within the territory of this Republic, and upon the terms and conditions therein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided; and whereas, by said act, the President of this Republic was authorized to make a contract with said Daniel J. Carroll, Henry J. Peters, and their associates aforesaid, collectively, in conformity with the provisions of the same; and whereas, in pursuance of such authority, the President did make a contract with the aforesaid grantees, which was duly executed in their behalf, by their attorney, Samuel Browning, and which bears date the thirtieth day of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust, 1841; and whereas, the President did make a further contract with the same parties, which bears date the twentieth day of No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember, 1841; and whereas, the President did make a yet further contract with the same parties, through their attorney, Horace Burnham, which bears date the twenty sixth day of July, 1842, said last two contracts being supplementary to, and making one with the said first contract; and whereas, it is deemed expedient to modify some of the provisions of said act and contracts, and to extend some of the privileges therein granted; now, therefore:</p>
<p>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas in Congress assembled, That the President be, and he hereby is authorised and required to make such modification of the aforesaid contracts, or such further contract or contracts, with the grantees named in the aforesaid act, or with their assigns or legal representatives, as shall be deemed by him for the benefit of this Republic, and as shall not be inconsistent with the provisions of the said act:</p>
<p>Provided, however, that he shall have full power and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to extend the time to the grantees named in the aforesaid act, or to their assigns or legal representatives, for the introduc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and settlement of emigrants in this Republic, to a period not exceeding five years from the first day of July next; and that he shall be authorized to prescribe the limits within which the grantees or their assigns or legal representatives shall be<pb n="852" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> permitted to introduce and settle any number of families, not exceeding ten thousand, within the whole time limited; that he shall be authorized to make the title and conveyance of each sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of six hundred and forty acres of land, which has been or shall be acquired under any contract made or to be made, by the President of this Republic, with the grantees, or their assigns or legal representatives, to the said grantees or their assigns, or le<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gal representatives direct: Provided, that said grantees, their as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs or legal representatives, shall survey the land assigned to them, as provided in the act aforesaid; and shall be required to settle or receive such lots only as are of fair quality for agricultural pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses, and not too far situated in the interior of a prairie for such purposes; and whenever they shall have completed the surveys of any number of sections, and built a corresponding number of small comfortable houses, or cabins of logs or other materials, thereon, and placed families therein, they shall receive a title from this Government to one section of six hundred and forty acres for each family so introduced and settled; and shall be required to im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately convey to the legal representative of said family, not less than one hundred and sixty, nor more than six hundred and forty acres of said land; conditioned that said family shall remain upon said land so conveyed, and enclose with fence and cultivate fifteen acres, for at least three years; and in default thereof, shall forfeit the same to this Republic:</p>
<p>Provided, further, that in the contract to be made by the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />den of this Republic with the said grantees, or with their assigns, or legal representatives, they shall be required to settle each year, within the territory prescribed, or to be prescribed to them, at least two hundred and fifty families, reckoning from and after the first day of July next, and including the families which shall then have been settled on the tract prescribed; and in default of intro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducing and settling such number of families, their contract shall be forfeited:</p>
<p>Provided, however, that they shall be allowed to introduce and settle any number of families, not exceeding ten thousand in all, on the same terms and conditions; and</p>
<p>Provided, further, that they shall be permitted to settle all the sections within any limits prescribed, or to be prescribed, and not located previous to the time of defining such limits; and that for every alternate section of six hundred and forty acres which shall be conveyed to them, they shall pay into the Treasury of this Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public twelve dollars in specie, on receiving the title from the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment; and</p>
<pb n="853" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Provided, further, that in case of forfeiture, the party shall only be affected prospectively, any thing in the aforesaid act, or contracts, to the contrary notwithstanding:</p>
<p>Provided, further; that the Cherokee lands shall be exempt from the provisions of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To organize the First, Second, Fourth, Fifth and Sixth Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, the first Judicial District of this Republic shall be composed of the counties of Galveston, Brazoria, Fort Bend, Austin and Matagorda; and the District Court for the county of Matagorda shall be holden on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks; in the county of Brazoria, on the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks; in the county of Fort Bend, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; in the county of Austin, on the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; and in the county of Galveston, on the fourth Mondays after after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the second Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Colorado, Gonzales, Bexar, Jackson and Victoria, and that the District Courts shall be holden in Colorado county, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; in Gonzales county, on the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; in the county of Bexar on the third Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue one week; in the county of Jackson, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue one week; and in the county of Victoria, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<pb n="854" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the fourth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict shall be composed of the counties of Goliad, Refugio and San Patricio, and the District Courts shall be holden as now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the sixth Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Jefferson, Liberty, Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery and Harris, and the District Courts shall be holden in Jefferson county on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; in Liberty on the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks; in Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery, on the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks; in Harris, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays of March and September, and may continue until the business if disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That hereafter the counties of Jasper, Sabine, San Augustine, Shelby, Nacogdoches, Busk and Houston, shall compose the fifth Judicial District, and the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts for the county of Jasper, shall commence its sessions on the second Mondays in March and September, in each and every year, and may continue its sessions one week; in the county of Sabine, on the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue its sessions one week; in the county of San Augustine, on the fourth Mondays in March, and September, and may continue its sessions three weeks; in the county of Shelby, on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue its sessions two weeks; in the county of Nacogdoches, as heretofore, on the first Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Rusk, on the fourth Mondays in May and November, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week; in the county of Houston, as heretofore, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in May and November, and may continue its sessions until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That writs, petitions, or any other process or proceedings, returnable at any other time, or to any other time, or to any other district than such as is fixed by this law, shall be returnable, and triable at the time and within the district established by this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="855" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To exempt from execution and forced sale, the property of certain persons.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, the property of all such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons as are now in the army of Texas, or as may hereafter be mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered into the service of the Republic, by virtue of the law of the land, shall not be liable to forced sales, so long as he or they may remain in said service.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To extend to the Chief Justice and associate Justices, the authority to issue certificates of Head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rights to Emigrants.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Chief Justice and associate justices shall constitute a board of commissioners for their respective counties, who shall be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to issue unconditional and conditional certificates for head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rights to lands, to all citizens of the second, third and fourth classes, who arrived in the country previous to the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty two, who shall have resided in the Republic three years, in conformity to the laws under which they emigrated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said board of commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners shall be, and they are hereby authorized to continue to issue unconditional certificates to emigrants and citizens, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by an act, approved January the fifteenth, one thousand eight hundred and forty one, that expired by its own limitation on the first day of October, one thousand eight hundred and forty-one.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the party claiming shall pay for each certificate the sum of two dollars, which shall be equally divided between the clerk and the commissioners present.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="856" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of the Texian prisoners captured by the Mexicans, during the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-two.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all persons who were captured and made prisoners during the cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paign of General Woll, in September last, be, and they are hereby exempt from paying taxes for the year (A. D.) one thousand eight hundred and forty two, and as long thereafter as they shall remain prisoners of war; and that the provisions of this act shall extend to Jose Antonio Navarro.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the estates of all those who were slain under the command of Captain N. M. Dawson, near the Salado, on the eighteenth of September last, be included in this act; and also all those who were slain in the county of Bexar, from the eleventh to the nineteenth of September; and where returns have been made by the assessor to the different sheriffs, upon satis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />factory evidence being given to said sheriff of the party having fallen in that unfortunate massacre, or taken prisoner as before mentioned, he, the sheriff, shall return under his hand and seal to the Treasury Department, a list of all such, with the amounts due, and the same shall be filed, with a copy of this act, in said De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment, for the exemption of the said dues for the year (A. D.) one thousand eight hundred and forty two.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Legalizing the location of the County Site of Fannin County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the location of a county site for the county of Fannin, as made by the commissioners elected for that purpose by the citizens of said county, in October last, be, and the same is hereby declared to be the county site of said county, to be known and called by the name of Bois d&#8217;Arc.</p>
<pb n="857" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the records of the Probate, County and District Courts of said county be, by their respective clerks, immediately removed to said site.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Post Office at Fort En<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />glish he removed to Bois d&#8217;Arc, and hear the name of Bois d&#8217;Arc Post Office.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an act, entitled an act to divide the County of Red river, and to create and establish the Counties of Bowie and Lamar.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the second section of the above recited act, to which this is a sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement, be so amended, that all the territory comprehended with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in the following limits: Beginning on Red River, at Hugh B. Shaw&#8217;s ferry; running from thence due South, to the Southern boundary line of old Red River county; thence East, with said line, to Perry Lake or lake Soda; and with said lake or lakes to the boundary line between the United States and Texas; thence with said line, North to Red River, and up said river with its meanders, to the place of beginning, be, and the same is hereby taken from the county of old Red River, and created a new county, to be called the county of Bowie.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the county seat of Bowie county, shall be and remain within five miles of the centre of the territory lying between Red River and the Sulphur Fork, which shall be the county seat of all the territory of Bowie county; and all that portion of said territory belonging to Bowie, South of the Sul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phur Fork shall vote with, and in every other respect be subject to the jurisdietion of Bowie county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the third section of the above recited act, to which this is a supplement, be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued, that the boundary line between Red River and Lamar shall be continued on from the Big or main Sulphur, to the Southern boundary of old Red River county, and thence on as<pb n="858" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> described in said section; and all that portion of the territory of Lamar, lying south of the Sulphur Pork, shall vote with and be under the jurisdiction of Lamar county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the county surveyors of the counties of Bowie and Lamar, shall complete the running and mark<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the boundary lines between those counties and the county of Red River, as above recited; for which they shall receive a compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation equal to that allowed other surveyors; one-third to be paid by the county of Red River on both lines, and the balance by the counties of Bowie and Lamar.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the clerks of the District and County Courts, and the county surveyor of Red River county, are hereby required to transmit all the documents and papers of every description, which belong within the territories of Bowie and La<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mar, to their respective counties; and any jurisdiction which the counties of Bowie and Lamar may have heretofore exercised over that portion of their territory, as designated South of the Sulphur Fork, shall be considered valid and binding, any law to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary notwithstanding; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To after the time of holding the District Courts in the Seventh Judicial District of the Republic of Texas, and for other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, the District Courts in the seventh Judicial District shall be holden as follows; viz: in the county of Fannin, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week; in the county of Lamar, on the second Mondays in March and September, and shall continue one week; in the county of Red River, on the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks; in the county of Bowie, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue<pb n="859" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> one week; and in the county of Harrison, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all writs, process, and other proceedings heretofore issued and had in and from the District of the several counties above named, which were returnable at the time heretofore fixed by law, shall be, and they are hereby made returnable to the said District Courts, to be held in accordance with the provisions of this act; and all parties, witnesses and jurors, are required to be in attendance as though heretofore regularly sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moned.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the honorable John T. Mills, Judge of the seventh Judicial District, have leave of ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sence from this Republic, during the summer vacation of the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts in his District for the year, (Anno Domini,) one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Creating the County of Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, all that portion of the county now included in the county of Nacogdoches, within the following<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />limits, viz: Beginning at a point due North, and sixteen miles from Nacogdoches; thence due East to the Attoyac creek; thence due West (retracing the last line thirty miles); hence due North to the Sabine river; thence down the Sabine river to the crossing of Trammel&#8217;s trace, South and West, to where said trace crosses the West boundary line of J. W. Adams&#8217; league; thence clue South to the Attoyac; thence with the meanders of said Attoyac, to the place of beginning, be, and the same is hereby constituted a county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the above described county shall be known and styled by the name of Rusk county; and that the first Monday in March next is hereby set apart for the election of five commissioners, to select a site for the county<pb n="860" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> seat of said county; and the place selected by said commissioners, shall be the county seat of said county, and shall be styled &#8220;Hen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson&#8221;; and all voters, qualified to vote for members of Congress, shall be entitled to vote for said commissioners; and it shall be, and is hereby made the duty of the said commissioners, to select said site within five miles of the center of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the commissioners, so select<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, shall have the right to purchase, or receive by donation, any quantity of land, not exceeding six hundred and forty acres, as will be to the interest of said county in erecting public buildings, and such other expenses as are incident to the same; and a majority of said board of commissioners shall have power to fill all vacancies which may occur in said board, until otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the county of Rusk be at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tached to, and form a part of the fifth Judicial District of this Republic; and all causes now pending in the county, of which said county is formed, in which the defendants reside in said county, shall be transferred to said county, for trial and adjudication.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That on the first Monday in March next, any two Justices of the Peace, in said Busk county, shall be authorized to hold an election for all county officers, in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with the laws now in force, regulating elections; and shall make their returns to the Secretary of State in twenty days from the time of such election.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Probate Judge, and all county officers, of said county, shall immediately enter upon the discharge of the duties of his office, under the authority of a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of election, until his commission shall issue from the State Department.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Probate Judge shall immediately lay off said county into a convenient number of beats, and cause elections to be held immediately therein for Justices of the Peace and Constables; said elections to be held by any two free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders of the beat; the returns of said elections to be made within twenty days to the State Department.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the time of holding the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferior courts for said county, shall be on the fourth Mondays of January, April, July and October of each year; and that the time of holding the District Court of said county shall be on the ______ day of ______ in each year.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Rusk<pb n="861" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> shall hereafter be entitled to one representative in Congress; who shall be elected at the same time, and in the same manner, that such representatives are elected in other counties of this Republic; and the voters of said county shall vote for a Senator as heretofore, and returns thereof shall be made to the county of Nacogdoches; and that Nacogdoches county shall hereafter be entitled to one representative in Congress; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning Rents.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all persons granting a lease of lands or tenements, either at will or for a term, shall have a lien upon all the property of the tenant upon such premises, for the payment of the rents becoming due under such lease, whether the same is to be paid in money, cotton, corn, or whatever else may be raised upon the rented premises; and in case where the rent is to be paid in com, cotton, or other articles raised upon the rented premises, it shall not be lawful for such tenant to remove off the premises any of such corn, cotton or other article, in which such rent is to be paid; and such lien shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue and be in force so long as such tenant shall occupy the rented premises, and for three months thereafter: Provided, however, that such lien shall not attach to any property for more than three months after the same shall be removed off the rented premises; nor to any goods, wares, and merchandize of a merchant or trader, after the same shall be sold in good faith and removed from the premises.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when any rent shall become due, or the tenant about to remove from such rented premises, or remove his property from such rented premises, it shall be lawful for the person to whom the rent is payable, his agent, attorney or assigns, to apply to any Justice of the Peace, in the county where the premises is situated, for a distress warrant, to seize the property of such tenant: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, such plaintiff, his agent, or attorney, shall make oath that the amount sued forcs for rent; or shall produce a writing<pb n="862" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> from such tenant to that effect; and it shall be the duty of such Justice to issue his warrant of distress to the proper officer, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding him to seize the property of the defendant, or so much thereof as will satisfy the demand; which warrant shall be, if the sum is not more than one hundred dollars, returnable to said Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice, or to some Justice of the county; but if more than one hundred dollars, the warrant shall be returnable to the District Court; in which case it shall be the duty of the Justice to transmit all the papers of said cause to the District Court, on or before the first day of the next term thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the officer to whom such warrant is directed, to seize the property of such tenant, or so much thereof as shall be of value sufficient to satisfy such debt and cost; and the same in his possession safely keep, (unless the defendant will replevy the same,) and make due return thereof to the Court in which such warrant is returnable, at the next term thereof: Provided, that if the property is of a perish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able or wasting kind, the Sheriff or other officer, or the plaintiff, or the defendant, may apply to the Justice issuing the warrant, or any other Justice, for an order to sell such property.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be lawful for the plaintiff, at the return of such warrant, to proceed to judgment, as in ordinary cases; Provided, that in case the return is to be made to the District Court, the plaintiff shall not be obliged to file his peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion before the suing out of such warrant: and Provided further, no other formalities shall be required than those mentioned in this act; and in case the defendant does not apply, the plaintiff may ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ply to the Court where such judgment was rendered for an order of sale; which sale shall be conducted as sales under execution.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws, in conflict with the provisions of this act, be, and the same are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="863" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To prescribe the manner in which suits shall be tried, in which the District Judges may be interested.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That hereafter, it shall be the duty of any one of the District Judges of the Republic of Texas, to change the venue upon the motion of any practising attorney, in any case in which said Judge may be interested, from the county in which he may be presiding, to the nearest adjoining county, out of his District, any law to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the several laws, regulating the Post Office Department.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the following rates of postage shall be charged on all letters, news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />papers, pamphlets and packages (except such as are authorized by law to be conveyed free of postage,) conveyed by the public mails.</p>
<p>For each letter, composed of a single piece of paper, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed not exceeding fifty miles, twelve and a half cents.</p>
<p>Over fifty, and not exceeding one hundred miles, twenty-five cents.</p>
<p>Over one hundred, and not exceeding two hundred miles, thirty seven and a half cents.</p>
<p>Over two hundred miles, fifty cents.</p>
<p>For each letter, composed of two pieces of paper, double the above rates of postage.</p>
<p>For each letter, composed of three pieces of paper, treble the above rates of postage, &#38;c.</p>
<p>For each letter or package, made up and sealed in letter form, whether composed of one or more pieces of paper, and weighing<pb n="864" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> one ounce, and less than two ounces, conveyed not exceeding fifty miles, quadruple the rate of a single letter for that distance; when conveyed over fifty miles, and not exceeding one hundred, or over one hundred, and not exceeding two hundred miles, or over two hundred miles, quadruple the rates of single letters for these dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tances.</p>
<p>For each letter or package, made up and sealed in letter form, whether composed of one or more pieces of paper, and weighing two ounces, and less than three ounces, and conveyed not exceeding fifty miles, sextuple the rate of a single letter for that distance, and so on in like proportion.</p>
<p>On each ship letter, there shall be charged an additional postage of twelve and a half cents.</p>
<p>On letters lodged for delivery, twelve and a half cents.</p>
<p>On way letters, there shall be charged an additional postage of twelve and a half cents, in stead of the postage heretofore desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated by law.</p>
<p>On each newspaper, conveyed not exceeding one hundred and fifty miles, two cents; over one hundred and fifty miles, three cents.</p>
<p>On all books, or pamphlets, for each sheet, the same as newspaper postage.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That, in payment of postage, the Exchequer bills of the Government he receivable at par.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after the thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />first day of March, one thousand eight hundred and forty-three.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws, contrary to, or conflicting with this act, be, and the same are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Authorizing an additional compensation to be paid to certain offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers of the Civil List.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the heads of Bureaux, and clerks of the various Departments, Bureaux and offices of Government (the clerks of Custom Houses excepted) shall, for the year eighteen hundred and<pb n="865" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> forty three, he allowed, each, the sum of twelve dollars and fifty cents per month, in addition to the salaries now allowed by law; and that a sufficient amount of Exchequer bills be, and the same are hereby appropriated to carry into effect the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the President to accept the services of one company of mounted men, to act as spies on the South Western frontier.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the President be, and he is hereby authorized to accept of the ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices of one company of mounted men, to act as spies on the South Wetsern frontier, until the provisions of an act, entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the protection of the Western and South Western fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier, and for other purposes,&#8221; can be carried into effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the sum of five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars be, and is hereby appropriated to carry out the provisions of this bill.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>For organizing the Militia of the Counties of Robertson and Brazos.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the militia of the counties of Robertson and Brazos shall<pb n="866" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> hereafter constitute and compose one regiment, to belong to the second brigade, and to be styled the ______ regiment of the second brigade.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the militia of the counties of Robertson and Brazos shall, each, constitute a battalion, and shall, respectively, be styled, the first and second battalions of said regiment.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said regiment shall be commanded by a Colonel, Lieutenant-Colonel, and Major; the Colonel and Major to be elected by the militia of Robertson county, and the Lieutenant Colonel to be elected by the militia of Brazos county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the militia of Robertson county shall be commanded by the Colonel, and the militia of Brazos county shall be commanded by the Lieutenant-Colonel.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the elections for the officers contemplated in this act, shall take place on the first Monday in February next; and the Chief Justices of Robertson and Brazos counties, respectively, are hereby required to issue the necessary writs of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1842</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To repeal in part, an act approved July 23d, 1842, entitled, an act to regulate the collection of impost duties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the passage of this act, the act, approved the 23d July, 1842, entitled &#8220;an act to regulate the collection, of impost duties,&#8221; be, and the same is hereby repealed, so far as the provisions of the same in any wise relate to the direct tax and postage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="867" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the several laws regulating the Post Office Department.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the twenty-sixth section of the act, entitled &#8220;an act to amend and to reduce into one the several laws regulating the Post Office De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment,&#8221; approved February 6th, 1840, and all other enactments providing for the franking privilege, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that from and after the passage of this act, all let<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters and packages to and from the following officers of this Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic, and none others, shall be conveyed by post free of postage,&#8212;that is to say&#8212;</p>
<p>1. President of the Republic.</p>
<p>2. Vice-President of the Republic.</p>
<p>3. Secretary of State.</p>
<p>4. Secretary of Treasury.</p>
<p>5. Secretary of War and Navy.</p>
<p>6. Attorney General.</p>
<p>7. Treasurer.</p>
<p>8. Chief Clerk of the Bureau of the General Post Office.</p>
<p>9. Members of both branches of Congress, during the time of their session, and for thirty days thereafter: Provided, neverthe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less, that no letter or package from any public officer shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed by post, free of postage, unless he shall frank the same, by writing his name and office on the outside of such letter or package.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That every printer of a newspaper in Texas, may send one paper to each and every other printer of a newspaper in Texas; may send to, and receive from, printers of newspapers in foreign countries, any number of newspapers, not exceeding ten, free of postage; under such regulations as the Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of State may prescribe; and that all former laws, in any wise conflicting with the provisions of this section, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be lawful for the Secretary of State, in advertising proposals for carrying the mail, to have such advertisements inserted more than three times, in any one newspaper, unless the same may be done without cost to the Government.</p>
<p>Sec. 4 Be it further enacted, That Post Masters are hereby authorized to frank letters, or receive letters, or newspapers free<pb n="868" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> of postage: Provided, that any one who shall frank a letter, not written by himself, shall be removed from office, and liable to a fine of ten dollars, for each and every offence, to be recovered before any Justice of the Peace: and any letter, or news paper, sent to such Post Master, being intended for other persons, shall pay double postage.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the more certain collection of License Taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the first day of February next, those persons who desire to pursue any vocation upon which, by the existing law, a license tax is levied, shall pay to the Treasurer of the County, the amount of money due for such license; and on presenting the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer&#8217;s receipt, staling distinctly the vocation to be pursued, to the Clerk of the County Court, he shall issue the corresponding license.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That if any person shall engage in any vocation, which, by existing law, is subject to a license tax, without having first obtained said license, he shall be liable to pay one fourth of the amount of the annual license tax, for each and every week he, or she may be thus engaged; and in the same pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portion for each day, to be recovered before any Justice of the Peace, or District Court, according to the amount; one fourth part of which shall be paid to the informer or prosecutor, one fourth to the County Treasury, and the balance to the Republic.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That whenever information is lodged before any Justice of the Peace, on oath or affirma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, stating that there is good reason to believe that any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, or persons, have been guilty of a violation of this law, such Justice shall issue a warrant against the person, or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, complained of, notifying him or them, to appear before him forthwith, or in such time as the Justice may think proper;<pb n="869" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the Republic of Texas.</fw> and shew cause, if any, he or they have, why judgment should not be rendered against him or them, for the penalties incurred by this act; and if found to be guilty, judgment shall be rendered for the penalty and costs; upon which execution may immediately issue: Provided, that either party may appeal to the District Court, as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That where any person may desire to obtain a license for a shorter period than one year, (and not less than four months,) the Treasurer may receive the amount which would be due for the time, adding thereto fifteen per cent.; and on his receipt, the Clerk will issue a license for the time, cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding with the amount which has been paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That in no case shall the offices of County Clerk and Treasurer he vested in one person; and if in any case any person may now be holding both of these offices, he shall no longer be Treasurer, and shall immediately account with his successor for all moneys received by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all laws contrary to, or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flicting with this act, are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>16th Jan., 1843</date>.</dateline>
<pb n="870" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" />
<signed>REPUBLIC OF TEXAS,<lb/> Department of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>I, the undersigned, Secretary of State of the Republic of Texas, do certify that the regular session of the Seventh Congress of said Republic, adjourned on the sixteenth day of January A. D. one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>Given under my hand and seal of office, at Wash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ington, the eighteenth day of January, A, D. one thousand eight hundred and forty three.</p>
<closer>
<signed>ANSON JONES.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>N<smcap>OTE</smcap>.&#8212;The laws in the foregoing volume which were signed by the President, are designated by the word &#8220;Approved;&#8221; those which were returned to the State Department without Iris signature, and became laws by lapse of time, by the word &#8220;Passed;&#8221; and those which were vetoed and passed, by the words, &#8220;Passed by a constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional majority.&#8221;</p>
<pb n="871" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>A<smcap>DJUTANT</smcap> G<smcap>ENERAL</smcap>&#8212;where office to be kept, 27.</p>
<p>A<smcap>DMINISTRATION</smcap>&#8212;not to be grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed to Sheriffs or Justices of the Peace, 14.</p>
<p>A<smcap>DMINISTRATORS</smcap>&#8212;not required to settle their accounts, except upon petition of creditor or representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive, 29.</p>
<p>A<smcap>GENTS</smcap>, I<smcap>NDIAN</smcap>&#8212;(See Indians.)</p>
<p>A<smcap>PPRAISERS</smcap> &#8212; appointment, 14; compensation, 14.</p>
<p>A<smcap>PPROPRIATIONS</smcap>&#8212;pay of members of Congress, 5, 8, 21; Chief Clerk, 8, 10; President, 8; Vice President, 8; President&#8217;s Private Secretary, 8; Secretary of State, 8; Secretary of Treasury, 8; Comptroller, 8; Treasurer, 8; Auditor, 9; Secreta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ry of War and Marine, 9; Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney General, 9; Commissioner of General Land Office, 9; Draftsman, 9; Clerks in various departments and offices, 9, 44; Charges d&#8217;Af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />faires, 9; Secretary of Legation, 9; Captain of Ordnance, 9; Armo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rer, 9; laborers in armory, 9; Chief Justice and associate Judges, 9; Clerk of Supreme Court, 9: Jos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eph Cecil, 10; contingent expenses of Congress, 4, 8; Executive De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment, 8; State Department, S; Post Office Bureau. 8; Treasury Department, 8, 20; Comptroller&#8217;s Office, 8, 20; Treasurer&#8217;s Office, 9; Auditor&#8217;s Office, 9; War Depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, 9; Attorney General&#8217;s office, 9; General Land Office, 9; Lega<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, 9; Ordnance Department, 9; Supreme Court, 9; hire of porters, 8; mail transportation 8, 20; relief of George S. McIntosh, 9; Indian purposes, 6, 9; printing, 9, 20; un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />expended balances, 10; officers of Congress, 10; coast defence, 17, 18; engraving and signing Exchequer bills, 20; frontier protection, 28; spy company, 45,</p>
<p>A<smcap>RDENT</smcap> S<smcap>PIRITS</smcap> &#8212; introduction among Indians prohibited, 24; penalty therefor, 24.</p>
<p>A<smcap>SSESSORS</smcap> OF T<smcap>AXES</smcap>&#8212;how paid, 13; when to make returns, 13.</p>
<p>A<smcap>USTIN</smcap> C<smcap>ITY</smcap>&#8212;purchasers of lots al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed further time for payment, 30.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>B<smcap>ALANCES</smcap>, U<smcap>NEXPENDED</smcap> &#8212; trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred, 10.</p>
<p>B<smcap>EXAR</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;election of officers, 7; John McMullen to perform du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Chief Justice, 7; records of District Court legalized, 29.</p>
<p>B<smcap>OIS</smcap> D&#8217;<smcap>ARC</smcap>&#8212;county site of Fannin, 36.</p>
<p>B<smcap>OWIE</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;certain papers to be transmitted to, 3, 38; limits de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined, 37; county site, 37; jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, 37, 38; boundary line to be surveyed, 38.</p>
<p>B<smcap>RAZORIA</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;County Court may levy a tax for certain purposes, 15; may lease public ferries, 19.</p>
<p>B<smcap>RAZOS</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;militia, how or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized, 45, 46.</p>
<p>B<smcap>RAZOS</smcap> R<smcap>IVER</smcap> &#8212; protection of mouth, 17.</p>
<p>B<smcap>UREAU</smcap> of I<smcap>NDIAN</smcap> A<smcap>FFAIRS</smcap>&#8212;es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished, 22.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>C<smcap>ANEY</smcap> N<smcap>AVIGATION</smcap> C<smcap>OMPANY</smcap>&#8212; (See Matagorda Caney Navigation Company.)</p>
<p>C<smcap>ECIL</smcap>, J<smcap>OSEPH</smcap>&#8212;pension, 10.</p>
<p>C<smcap>HEROKEE</smcap> L<smcap>ANDS</smcap>&#8212;reserved from colonization, 33.</p>
<p>C<smcap>HIEF</smcap> J<smcap>USTICES</smcap>&#8212;may, with asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates, issue certificates of head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right, 35; fees for same, 35.</p>
<p>C<smcap>LERKS</smcap> OF G<smcap>OVERNMENT</smcap>&#8212;additional compensation, 44.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OLLEGE</smcap> OF D<smcap>E</smcap> K<smcap>ALB</smcap>&#8212;lands, how surveyed,30.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OLONIZATION</smcap>&#8212;(See contracts for Introduction of Emigrants.)</p>
<p>C<smcap>OMMISSIONERS</smcap> OF P<smcap>ARTITION</smcap>&#8212; compensation, 14.</p>
<p>C<smcap>ONGRESS</smcap>&#8212;contingent expenses, 4,<pb n="872" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw> 8; pay of members, 5, 8, 21; Chief Clerk of House, 8, 10; officers, 10.</p>
<p>C<smcap>ONTRACTS</smcap> FOR I<smcap>NTRODUCTION</smcap> OF E<smcap>MIGRANTS</smcap>&#8212;acts relating to W. S. Peters and others, and their contracts with President, recited, 31; President may modify and make new contracts, 31; may ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend time to five years, 31; may designate boundaries, 31; may al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />low introduction of ten thousand families, 32; may make title 32; contractor shall survey lands, 32; what lands required to be settled, 32; improvements required, 32; contractors to make conveyance to emigrants, 32; to settle two hundred and fifty families yearly, 32; forfeiture, 32, 33; alternate sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, 32; Cherokee lands exempt, 33.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap> C<smcap>LERK</smcap> AND T<smcap>REASURER</smcap>&#8212; offices not to be held by the same person, 49.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>, C<smcap>HANCERY</smcap>&#8212;gales by de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cree, 21; appraisement, 21; notice, 21.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>, D<smcap>ISTRICT</smcap> &#8212; (See Dis&#8217;t Courts.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>, J<smcap>USTICES</smcap>&#8212;law regulating proceedings, amended, 12.</p>
<p>C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>, P<smcap>ROBATE</smcap> &#8212; (See Probate Courts.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>D<smcap>IRECT</smcap> T<smcap>AX</smcap>&#8212;(See Taxes.)</p>
<p>D<smcap>ISTRICT</smcap> C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>&#8212;when holden in 1st., 2nd., 4th., 5th., and 6th., Districts, 33, 34; when holden in 7th., District, 38; process, when and where returnable, 34, 39.</p>
<p>D<smcap>ISTRICT</smcap> J<smcap>UDGES</smcap> &#8212; may change venue, in certain cases, 43.</p>
<p>D<smcap>ISTRICTS</smcap>, J<smcap>UDICIAL</smcap>&#8212;(See Judicial Districts.)</p>
<p>D<smcap>RAFT</smcap>&#8212;penalty for refusal to obey, 27.</p>
<p>D<smcap>UES</smcap>, G<smcap>OVERNMENT</smcap>&#8212;on lands, further time granted for payment, 5.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>E<smcap>LECTION</smcap>&#8212;in Bexar county, 7; of Major General, 26.</p>
<p>E<smcap>MIGRANTS</smcap>&#8212;certificates for headright, 35; (See contracts for Introduction of Emigrants.)</p>
<p>E<smcap>XCHEQUER</smcap> B<smcap>ILLS</smcap> &#8212; to be issued after 1st. March, 1843, in certain denominations, 10; not more than fifty thousand dollars to be in cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culation at any one time, 10; en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graving and signing, 20; receiva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble at par for postage, 44, 46; for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />direct tax, 46.</p>
<p>E<smcap>XECUTION</smcap>&#8212;act of 1842 amended, 7; provisions of 17, 18, and 19 sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of said act made applicable to debts contracted prior to 1st. May, 1842, 7; certain property exempt, 35.</p>
<p>E<smcap>XECUTORS</smcap>&#8212;not required to settle their accounts, except upon peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of creditor or representative, 29.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>F<smcap>ANNIN</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;location of coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty site legalized, 36; naming of site, 36; records of courts to be removed, 37; Post Office, 37.</p>
<p>F<smcap>EES</smcap>&#8212;commissioners of partition, 14; appraisers, 14; head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right, 35.</p>
<p>F<smcap>ERRIES</smcap>, P<smcap>UBLIC</smcap>&#8212;in Galveston and Brazoria counties, 19.</p>
<p>F<smcap>IELD</smcap> N<smcap>OTES</smcap>&#8212;further time granted for return, 5.</p>
<p>F<smcap>RANKING</smcap> P<smcap>RIVILEGE</smcap> &#8212; regulated, 47.</p>
<p>F<smcap>RONTIER</smcap> P<smcap>ROTECTION</smcap>&#8212;volunteers and drafted militia, 27, 28; army regulations to govern troops, 27; spoil, how divided, 27; pay of troops, 28; stations, 28; martial law, 28; appropriation, 28. (See Major General.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>G<smcap>ALVESTON</smcap>&#8212;protection of harbor, 17, 18; county court may license public ferries, 19.</p>
<p>G<smcap>ALVESTON</smcap> O<smcap>RPHAN&#8217;S</smcap> F<smcap>RIEND</smcap> S<smcap>OCIETY</smcap>&#8212;established, 18; privileges, 18.</p>
<p>G<smcap>OVERNMENT</smcap> D<smcap>UES</smcap>&#8212;on lands, further time granted for payment, 5.</p>
<p>G<smcap>UARDIANS</smcap>&#8212;not required to settle their accounts, except upon petition of creditor or representative, 29.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>H<smcap>ENDERSON</smcap>&#8212;county site of Rusk, 40.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>I<smcap>NDIANS</smcap> &#8212; prisoners, 6, 25; appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation, 9; Bureau established, 22; interpreters, 22; agents, 22; superintendent, 23; oath of office, 23; reports, 23; trading<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />houses, 23; trader&#8217;s license, 23; penalty for trading without license, 23; agent not to trade without special<pb n="873" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw> authority, 23; invoices, 24; trade within settlements forbid, except by special authority, 24; property, how restored, 24; warlike stores, 24; introduction of ardent spirits forbid, 24; penalty for introducing the same, 24; intercourse regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated, 24, 25; penalty for breach of peace and other offenses, 25; Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent&#8217;s powers, 25; mines, 25; grades in council regulated, 25.</p>
<p>I<smcap>NTERPRETERS</smcap> &#8212; appointment and salary, 22.</p>
<p>I<smcap>NTESTATES</smcap>&#8217; E<smcap>STATES</smcap>&#8212;except per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ishable property, not to be sold, unless upon petition of creditor or representative, 29.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>J<smcap>UDICIAL</smcap> D<smcap>ISTRICTS</smcap>&#8212;1st, 2d, 4th, 5th and 6th reorganized, 33, 34.</p>
<p>J<smcap>USTICES</smcap> C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>&#8212;proceedings reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulated, 12; former laws amended, 12.</p>
<p>J<smcap>USTICES</smcap> OF THE P<smcap>EACE</smcap>&#8212;right to administer taken away, 14; may issue distress warrants, 41, 42.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>L<smcap>AMAR</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;certain papers to be transmitted to, 3, 38; Southern boundary designated, 3; county site to be selected, and duties of commissioners in relation thereto, 4; certain boundary line defined, 37; jurisdiction, 38; boundary line to be surveyed, 38.</p>
<p>L<smcap>AND</smcap> C<smcap>LAIMS</smcap>&#8212;time within which certain suits may be commenced, limited, 19.</p>
<p>L<smcap>ICENSE</smcap> T<smcap>AX</smcap>&#8212;collection, 48, 49; penalty for non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payment, 48, 49; may be charged for a less period than one year, 49.</p>
<p>L<smcap>IEN</smcap>&#8212;for payment of rents, 41.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>M<smcap>AILS</smcap> &#8212; appropriation for transporting, 8, 20; routes designated, 11; to be carried weekly, 12.</p>
<p>M<smcap>AJOR</smcap> G<smcap>ENERAL</smcap>&#8212;how elected, 26; duration of office, 26; vacancy, how supplied, 26; when he may take the field, 26; compensation, 26; to organize militia, 26; when and how he shall call militia into service, 26; to designate rendez<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vous, 27; may appoint general staff, 27; may receive volunteers, 27; certain companies exempt from draft, 27; shall report to Secretary of War, 27; may require arms, &#38;c., from Secretary of War, 27; absentees from army, 28.</p>
<p>M<smcap>ATAGORDA</smcap> C<smcap>ANEY</smcap> N<smcap>AVIGATION</smcap> C<smcap>OMPANY</smcap>&#8212;incorporated, 15; priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges, 15; stock books to be opened, 15; election of officers, 15; collection of installments, 16; sale of stock, 16; rights of navigation, 16; damages, 16; tolls, 16; right of county to purchase, 16, 17; du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration of charter, 16, 17; not to exercise banking privileges, 17; government vessels not to be charged tolls, 17; completion of work, 17.</p>
<p>M<smcap>ATAGORDA</smcap> B<smcap>AY</smcap>&#8212;protection, 17.</p>
<p>M<smcap>CINTOSH</smcap>, G<smcap>EORGE</smcap> S.&#8212;relief, 9.</p>
<p>M<smcap>CMULLEN</smcap>, J<smcap>OHN</smcap>&#8212;to perform du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Chief Justice for Bexar county, 7.</p>
<p>M<smcap>ILITIA</smcap>&#8212;may be called into service by Major General, 26; certain companies exempt from draft, 27; of Robertson and Brazos coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, how organized, 45, 46.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>N<smcap>ACOGDOCHES</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap> &#8212; divided, 39; representation, 40, 41.</p>
<p>N<smcap>AVARRO</smcap>, J<smcap>OSE</smcap> A<smcap>NTONIO</smcap>&#8212;relief, 36.</p>
<p>N<smcap>AVIGATION</smcap> C<smcap>OMPANY</smcap>&#8212;(See Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda Caney Navigation Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>O<smcap>RPHAN&#8217;S</smcap> F<smcap>RIEND</smcap> S<smcap>OCIETY</smcap>&#8212;(See Galveston Orphan&#8217;s Friend So<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciety.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>P<smcap>ARTITION</smcap>&#8212;compensation of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, 14.</p>
<p>P<smcap>ATENTS</smcap>&#8212;act in relation to land certificates, &#38;c., amended, 19.</p>
<p>P<smcap>ENSION</smcap>&#8212;Joseph Cecil, 10.</p>
<p>P<smcap>OSTAGE</smcap>&#8212;regulated, 43; receivable in Exchequer bills at par, 44, 46.</p>
<p>P<smcap>OST</smcap> O<smcap>FFICE</smcap>&#8212;at Fort English, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved to Bois d&#8217;Arc. 37.</p>
<p>P<smcap>RESIDENT</smcap>&#8212;duty and authority in relation to coast protection, 18; in relation to Indians, 22, 23, 24.</p>
<p>P<smcap>RINTING</smcap>&#8212;laws and journals, 9; for Comptroller&#8217;s office, 20.</p>
<p>P<smcap>RISONERS</smcap>&#8212;Indian, to be conveyed to Waco Village, 6; to be reclaimed, and how, 6; to be clothed, 6; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="874" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>propriation, 6; captured by Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />icans, exempt from taxation, 36.</p>
<p>P<smcap>RIVATE</smcap> S<smcap>ECRETARY</smcap> to President additional compensation, 44.</p>
<p>P<smcap>ROBATE</smcap> C<smcap>OURTS</smcap>&#8212;a certain portion of intestates&#8217; estate exempt from sale, 14; duty of court in relation thereto, 14; sales by order, 21; appraisement, 21; notice of sale, 21; law regulating proceedings amended, 29.</p>
<p>P<smcap>ROPERTY</smcap>&#8212;of intestates, a certain portion exempt from sale, 14; ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept perishable, not to be sold but upon petition of creditor or rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative, 29; of persons in ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tual service, exempt from forced sale, 35; maybe seized for rent, 42.</p>
<p>P<smcap>ROTECTION</smcap>&#8212;of coast, 17, 18; of frontier, 26, 27, 28, 45.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Q</head>
<p>Q<smcap>UARTER</smcap> M<smcap>ASTER</smcap> G<smcap>ENERAL</smcap>&#8212;bond, 28; to be disbursing officer, 28.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>R<smcap>ED</smcap> R<smcap>IVER</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;Clerk to trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit certain papers, 3; certain boundary to be defined, 37.</p>
<p>R<smcap>ELIEF</smcap>&#8212;of George S. McIntosh, 9; Jose Antonio Navarro, 36; per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons captured by Mexicans, 36; persons slain under Capt. Daw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and in county of Bexar, 36.</p>
<p>R<smcap>ENTS</smcap>&#8212;collection, 41, 42.</p>
<p>R<smcap>OBERTSON</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;militia, how organized, 45, 46.</p>
<p>R<smcap>USK</smcap> C<smcap>OUNTY</smcap>&#8212;established, 39; lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its defined, 39; county site, 40; donations, 40; attached to 5th Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District, 40; causes trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred, 40; election, 40; officers, when to enter upon their duties, 40; beats, 40; time of holding in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferior courts, 40; representation, 41.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>S<smcap>ALES</smcap> &#8212; certain property of intes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tates exempt, 14; to be sold only upon petition of creditor or repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative, 29; property of persons in actual service exempt, 35; for rent. 42.</p>
<p>S<smcap>EA</smcap><pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />C<smcap>OAST</smcap> &#8212; appropriation for de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence, 17; Galveston, ]7; mouth of the Brazos, 17; Matagorda bay, 17; squad of men, 18; duty of President, 18.</p>
<p>S<smcap>ECRETARY</smcap> OF T<smcap>REASURY</smcap>&#8212;to issue Exchequer bills, 10; to draw in favor of assessors of taxes, 13.</p>
<p>S<smcap>HERIFF</smcap>&#8212;to pay assessors of taxes, 13; when returns of assessment shall be made to him, 13; right to administer taken away, 14.</p>
<p>S<smcap>PY</smcap> C<smcap>OMPANY</smcap>&#8212;services to be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cepted, 45; appropriation, 45.</p>
<p>S<smcap>UPERINTENDENT</smcap>&#8212;(See Indians).</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>T<smcap>AXES</smcap> &#8212; assessors, how paid, 13; when assessment to be returned, 13; County Court of Brazoria may levy for certain purposes, 15; prisoners captured by Mexicans, and those slain under Capt. Daw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and in county of Bexar, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from payment, 36; Excheq<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uer bills receivable at par for di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect, 46.</p>
<p>T<smcap>ESTATOR</smcap>&#8212;May make certain pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions by will, 14.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>V<smcap>ACANCY</smcap>&#8212;in office of Major General, how supplied, 26.</p>
<p>V<smcap>ENUE</smcap>&#8212;may be changed in certain cases, 43.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>W<smcap>ILLS</smcap>&#8212;may embrace certain provisions, 14.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
