<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="801" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main"><b>ABSTRACT</b> OF PRIVATE ACTS AND JOINT RESOLUTIONS</head>
<byline>PASSED BY THE SIXTH CONGRESS.</byline>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of K. L. Anderson,&#8221; approved January 12th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit his claim for $500&#8212;receivable for government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;An act for the relief of 1ST. B. Anderson,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him a certificate for 640 acres of land, as his head-right,</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of John Appleman,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs his account to be audited for $800, receivable for government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Thomas H. O. S. Addicks,&#8221; passed by a constitutional majority, February 5th, 1842&#8212;directs the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him a certificate (first class) for one-third of a league of land; and, upon the return of the survey, a corresponding patent.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Elijah Bennett,&#8221; passed January 7th, 1842&#8212;directs that his claim for $140 be audited, payable at the pleasure of the Government.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint resolution for the relief of Samuel K. Blish,&#8221; approved January 11th, 1842&#8212;authorizes the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue, to him, scrip for 1280 acres of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Armstead Bennett and Tho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="802" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>mas Lagow,&#8221; approved January 17th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit their claim for $565.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Josiah Gr. Beaty, and others, passed January 25th, 1842&#8212;directs the payment of their accounts, amounting to $1000, in par funds, or the equivalent in promissory notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Rebecca Brown, adminis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tratrix of the estate of Jeremiah Brown, deceased,&#8221; passed Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 2d, 1843&#8212;authorizes the property of said Brown, deceased, to be received, at valuation, in payment of debts due from his estate to the Government.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Jesse Billingsly, assignee of Noah Smithrwick,&#8221; passed &#8220;February 5th, 1842&#8212;authorizes the Secretary of War to issue, to him, a &#8220;miltary land warrant&#8221; for 1280 acres of land.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Joseph Cecil,&#8221; approved De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember 21st, 1841&#8212;allows him a pension of $25, par funds, per month&#8212;payable at the pleasure of the Government.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Robert J. Calder, sheriff of Brazoria county,&#8221; approved January 4th, 1842&#8212;requires the Audi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor to audit his claim for $4911&#8212;receivable for public dues hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of N. H. Cochrane,&#8221; approved January 11th, 1842&#8212;requires the Secretary of the Treasury to pay to him $375 in promissory notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Holland Coffee, approved January 22d, 1842&#8212;provides for the issuing to him a patent for one-third of a league of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Samuel Craig,&#8221; approved January 22d, 1842&#8212;provides for the issuing to him a patent for a certain ten acre lot, near the city of Austin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Samuel Craig,&#8221; approved January 24th, 1842&#8212;provides for the issuing to him a patent for a certain ten acre lot, near the city of Austin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of J. Harris Catlin,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs the Secretary of the Treasury to pay to him $747 50, in promissory notes.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Edward Daniel,&#8221; approved <pb n="803" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>January 12th, 1842 &#8212; directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him a certificate for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of M. R. De Graffenreid,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land-Office to issue to him six certificates for 640 acres of land each.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act, to be entitled &#8216;An Act for the relief of Augustus Doug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lass,&#8217;&#8221; approved February 1st, 1842&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him a patent for one-third of a league of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint resolution for the relief of John Davis,&#8221; approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 3d, 1842 &#8212; directs the Auditor to audit the account of said Davis, use of Caleb Willborne, for $56 50&#8212;receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Abel L. Eaves,&#8221; approved February 5th, 1842 &#8212; requires the Commisisoner of the General Land-Office to respect the certificate issued to George W. Glass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cock, assignee of said Eaves, for one league and labor of land.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Daniel Faris,&#8221; approved De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember 10th, 1841&#8212;requires the Commisioner of the General Land<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Office to respect, as valid, his head-right certificate for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the honorable discharge of E. J. Felder,&#8221; passed January 18tli, 1842&#8212;directs the Secretary of War to give him an honorable discharge from the Texas volunteer service.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution appropriating one thousand six hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, in par funds, or its equivalent in the promissory notes of the Government,&#8221; passed December 28th, 1841&#8212;appropriates $1600 for the payment of Messrs. Highsmith and Jones, mail-contractors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of certain persons therein named,&#8221; passed January 13th, 1842&#8212;directs the Comptroller to approve the accounts of John A. Hueser, and others, for services rendered under an order of the committee on Indian Affairs.</p>
<pb n="804" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Memucan Hunt, Esq., late Commissioner to run the boundary line between the United States and Texas,&#8221; approved January 18th, 1842&#8212;prescribes the manner in which his accounts for services, as commissioner, shall be audited.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution concerning Captain A. C. Hinton,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;acquits him of all charges affecting him as an officer, or gentleman, whilst in the naval service of the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Sarah N. Hubert,&#8221; approved February 4th, 1842&#8212;requires the Treasurer, upon receiving the one-half of a certain five hundred dollar hill, to pay to her, or her agent, $500 in promissory notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Joseph M. Harris, approved February 5th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit his claim for $193&#8212;receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of John Ingram,&#8221; approved Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 4th, 1842&#8212;authorizes the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue to him, upon certain conditions, a certificate for 299 acres of land.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of H. Kloppenburg,&#8221; passed Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary 7th, 1842&#8212;directs the payment of his account for services as an extra clerk in the Treasury Department.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of A. G. Kimbell,&#8221; approved Jan. 17th, 1842&#8212;directs his claim to be audited for $2,588 53, payable in par funds or its equivalent, and receivable for govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment dues heretofore accrued.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution to authorize the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land-Office to employ extra clerks,&#8221; approved November 16th, 1841&#8212;authorizes the employment of four clerks, for six weeks, as assistants.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Joseph Levens,&#8221; approved November 17th, 1841&#8212;requires the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him an order of survey for 1280 acres of land.</p>
<pb n="805" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Joseph Lee,&#8221; approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 29th, 1842&#8212;provides for the issuing to him a patent for a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain lot in the city of Austin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of sundry persons therein men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs the Auditor to audit the following claims, to wit: the claim of Martin Lacy for $515: William Perry, for $584 50; P. O. Lumpkin, for $30; heirs of C. C. Campbell, deceased, for $15; Malethel Campbell, for $16; heirs of John Grigsby, deceased, for $175; Samuel C. Box, for $81 75; Martin A. Walker, for $46 10; Humphries Ussery, for $100; John D. Miller and Crawford Grigsby, for $30; Richard H. Chisholm, for $100; Hiram Williams, for $226; William Gragg, for 20; John Newgent for $86; James Latimer, for $30; John Blanton, for $40; Able Blana for $30; H. H. Clifton, for $378; and Richard Tankersly, for $180: all receivable for government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Willis H. Landrum, approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 1st, 184-2&#8212;authorizes the payment, at the pleasure of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, to him, of the sum of $311, in par funds.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Eliza T. Logan,&#8221; approved February 4th, 1842&#8212;provides for the issuing to her a patent for a certain lot in the city of Austin.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of George D. McJimpsey,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved December 23d, 1841&#8212;directs the Auditor to issue to him audited scrip for $621 50&#8212;receivable only for Government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Jarret Menefee,&#8221; passed Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 7th, 1842&#8212;authorizes the payment, at the pleasure of the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, to him of the sum of $210.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution permitting Samuel McCullock to enter of record a certain deed,&#8221; approved January 12th, 1842&#8212;permits him to execute and enter of record, a deed to perpetuate the evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the freedom of certain persons of color.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of the heirs of George McKnight, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 17th, 1842&#8212;requires the Secretary of War to issue to them a certificate for the donation land granted to those who were in the battle of the 19th March, 1836; also, the donation land granted to soldiers who died or were slain in the ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice of Texas; and, also, the bounty land for three months&#8217; services in the army. It also requires the Auditor to audit the <pb n="806" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>claim of said McKnight for three months&#8217; services in the army of 1835 and 1836.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Nathaniel Moore,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Commissioner of the General Land Office to respect as genuine a certain land certificate, No. 233, issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners of Bas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trop county.</p>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of John S. Martin,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to issue to him an audited draft for $311 84, receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of A. C. Macfarlane, late Sheriff of Travis County,&#8221; approved February 4th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit certain accounts of said Macfarlane.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Helena Nelson,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit her claim for $185&#8212;receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of J. T. O&#8217;Reily,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit his claim for $132 44&#8212;payable at the pleasure of the Government.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of the heirs of Capt. John W. Peacock,&#8221; approved February 5th, 1842&#8212;directs a patent to be issued to the administrator of the said J. W. Peacock, for one league and labor of land.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution concerning the fall term, 1841, of the District Court of Refugio,&#8221; approved December 30th, 1841&#8212;directs that no deduction he made in the salary of the Judge, by reason of his not having held said Court.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint resolution for the relief of the executrix of Thomas Ross, deceased,&#8221; approved January 18th, 1842&#8212;authorizes the payment, at the pleasure of the Government, of her account of $23, par money.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution requiring the Auditor to re-audit certain claims,&#8221; approved January 24th, 1842&#8212;directs the Auditor, <pb n="807" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>upon the delivery to him, by James H. Raymond, of certain Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury Warrants, for $471 21 in amount, to issue a Warrant for $94, payable in Exchequer Bills, out of the contingent fund of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress.</p>
<p>An Act for the rebel of William E. Roberts,&#8221; approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 3d, 1842&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land Of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice to respect as genuine his head-right &#8220;claim,&#8221; for one-third of a league of land.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Angeline D. Smith,&#8221; approved December 10th, 1841&#8212;exonerates her from the payment of balance of purchase money on certain lots, near the city of Austin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Adolphus Sterne,&#8221; approved January 3d, 1842&#8212;directs that his claim for $949 50 be audited.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Ensign B. Smith and Stephen Smith,&#8221; approved January 18th, 1842&#8212;directs the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to them patents for one league and labor of land each.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Charles Shearn,&#8221; passed Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 25th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to issue to him drafts to the amount of $4,400&#8212;payable at the pleasure of the Government, and receivable for government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of John R. Slocum,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs the Auditor to audit his account for $425&#8212;receivable for all public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Seth Swift,&#8221; approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit his claim for $217 75 &#8212;payable at the pleasure of the Government.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of William Snodgrass,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;requires the Auditor to audit his claim for $280&#8212;receivable for all dues for which promissory notes are re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceivable.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Andrew J. Titus, and others,&#8221; approved January 5th, 1842&#8212;directs that patents be issued to A. J. Titus and P. W. Titus, for 1280 acres of land each; to Wm. Lewis, or his assignee, for one-third of a league; and to the heirs of James W. Smith for 1280 acres.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Daniel J. Toler,&#8221; approved <pb n="808" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Abstract.</fw>January 20th, 1842&#8212;directs a patent to be issued, to him, for one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution passing a vote of thanks to Captain John G. Tod, late commander of the naval station at Galveston,&#8221; passed by a constitutional majority, February 1st, 1842&#8212;declares him enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to the thanks of Congress for his faithful and important ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices; and directs the resolution and report attached thereto, to be read at the navy yard, &#38;c.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of George W. Terrell, approved February 5th, 1842&#8212;directs the payment of one-half the salaries due to him and Edward T. Branch respectively, as district judges.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>&#8220;An Act for the relief of Daniel M. Wiseman,&#8221; approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 18th, 1842&#8212;directs a patent to be issued to him for one league and labor of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of O. C. Williams,&#8221; approved January 24th, 1842&#8212;directs the claim of said Williams to be audited&#8221; for $150&#8212;receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Thomas G. Western,&#8221; passed January 25th, 1842&#8212;directs that his claim he audited for $440, receivable for public dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Francis F. Wells,&#8221; approved January 29th, 1842&#8212;directs his accounts to be audited for $1,080 &#8212;receivable for government dues heretofore accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of William K. Wilson,&#8221; approved February 3d, 1843&#8212;requires the Commissioner of the General Land-Office to issue to him a patent for a certain league of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Joint Resolution for the relief of Ward and Ingram,&#8221; passed February 5th, 1843&#8212;directs the Auditor to audit their claim for $2,582 03&#8212;payable after the first day of January, 1843, with in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest from the 6th of April, 1841, until paid.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>