<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1225" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">NINTH CONGRESS&#8212;REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</head>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">EXTRA SESSION.</head>
<div3 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Giving the consent of the existing Government to the annexation of Texas to the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Government of the United States hath <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Preamble.</p></body></floatingText> proposed the following terms, guarantees, and condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, on which the people and territory of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas may be erected into a new State, to be called the State of Texas, and admitted as one of the States of the American Union, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Resolved by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the United States of America in Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Consent of Congress giv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />en to annexa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Texas as a State.</p></body></floatingText>sembled, That Congress doth consent that the territory properly included within, and rightfully belonging to the Republic of Texas, may be erected into a new State, to be called the State of Texas, with a republican form of Government, to be adopted by the people of said Republic, by deputies in Convention assembled, with the consent of the existing Government, in order that the same may be admitted as one of the States of this Union.</p>
<p>&#8220;2. And be it further resolved, That the foregoing<floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Conditions and guarantees.</p></body></floatingText> consent of Congress is given upon the following condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and with the following guarantees, to wit:</p>
<pb n="1226" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolution of Texas Consenting to Annexation.</fw>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Boundaries to be adjusted by U. States.</p></body></floatingText>&#8220;First. Said State to be formed, subject to the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />justment by this Government of all questions of bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary that may arise with other Governments; and the <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>State Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution to be adopted and presented.</p></body></floatingText>Constitution thereof, with the proper evidence of its adoption, by the people of said Republic of Texas, shall be transmitted to the President of the United States, to be laid before Congress for its final action, on or before the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty-six.</p>
<p>&#8220;Second. Said State, when admitted into the Union, <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>What to be ceded to the U. States.</p></body></floatingText>after ceding to the United States, all public edifices, fortifications, barracks, ports and harbors, navy and navy-yard, docks, magazines, arms, armaments, and all other property and means pertaining to the public defence, belonging to the said Republic of <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>What to be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained.</p></body></floatingText>Texas, shall retain all the public funds, debts, taxes, and dues of every kind, which may belong to or be due and owing said Republic; and shall also retain all the vacant and unappropriated lands lying within its limits, to be applied to the payment of <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Public debt of Texas not to become a charge upon the U. States.</p></body></floatingText>the debts and liabilities of said Republic of Texas, and the residue of said lands, after discharging said debts and liabilities, to be disposed of as said State may direct; but in no event are said debts and liabilities to become a charge upon the Government of the United States.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>New States may be formed out of Texian territory.</p></body></floatingText>Third. New States, of convenient size, not exceeding four in number, in addition to said State of Texas, and having sufficient population, may hereafter, by the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of said State, be formed out of the territory thereof, which shall be entitled to admission under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the Federal Constitution. And such States as may be formed out of that portion of said territory lying south of thirty-six degrees thirty minutes north latitude, commonly known as the Missouri compromise <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Missouri Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />promise Line established.</p></body></floatingText>line, shall be admitted into the Union, with or without slavery, as the people of each State asking admission may desire. And in such State or States as shall be formed out of said territory north of said Missouri com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />promise line, slavery, or involuntary servitude, (except for crime), shall be prohibited.&#8221;</p>
<pb n="1227" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolution of Texas Consenting to Annexation.</fw>
<p>And whereas, by said terms, the consent of the existing government of Texas is required&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Consent of Texas given to annexation as a State.</p></body></floatingText>tatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the government of Texas doth consent, that the People and territory of the Republic of Texas, may be erected into a new State, to be called the State of Texas, with a republican form of Government, to be adopted by the People of said Republic, by Deputies in Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion assembled, in order that the same may be admitted as one of the States of the American Union; and said consent is given on the terms, guarantees, and condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions set forth in the Preamble to this Joint Resolution.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the proclama<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Consent given to President&#8217;s proclamation calling con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention, and the election of deputies thereto.</p></body></floatingText>tion of the President of the Republic of Texas, bearing date May fifth, eighteen hundred and forty-five, and the election of Deputies to sit in Convention, at Austin, on the fourth day of July next, for the adoption of a Constitution for the State of Texas, had in accordance therewith, hereby receives the consent of the existing Government of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That the President of<floatingText rend="right"><body><p>President to furnish Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ican Minister, and Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, with copy of this Joint Resolution.</p></body></floatingText> Texas is hereby requested immediately to furnish the Government of the United States, through their ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />credited Minister near this Government, with a copy of this Joint Resolution; also to furnish the Convention to assemble at Austin, on the fourth of July next, a copy of the same&#8212;And the same shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JOHN M. LEWIS,<lb/> Speaker of the House of Representatives.</signed>
<signed>K. L. ANDERSON,<lb/> President of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 23, 1845</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<signed>ANSON JONES.</signed>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1228" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" />
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">IN CONVENTION OF THE PEOPLE OF THE RE<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />PUBLIC OF TEXAS JULY 4, 1845.</head>
<div3 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE.</head>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Preamble re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />citing the offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial action of the Congress and President of the United States and of the President and Congress of Texas, in regard to an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nexation.</p></body></floatingText>Whereas the Congress of the United States of America has passed resolutions providing for the annexation of Texas to that Union, which resolutions were ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the President of the United States on the first day of March one thousand eight hundred and forty-five; and whereas the President of the United States has submitted to Texas the first and second sections of the said resolution, as the basis upon which Texas may be admitted as one of the States of the said Union; and whereas the existing government of the Republic of Texas has assented to the proposals thus made, the terms and conditions of which are as follows,</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION FOR ANNEXING TEXAS TO THE UNITED STATES.</head>
<p>Resolved, by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the United States of America in Congress as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Consent of Congress giv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />en to annexa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as a State.</p></body></floatingText>sembled, That Congress doth consent, that the territory, properly included within, and rightfully belonging to the Republic of Texas, may be erected into a new State, to be called the State of Texas, with a republican form of government, to be adopted by the people of said Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public, by deputies in convention assembled, with the consent of the existing government, in order that the same may be admitted as one of the States of this Union.</p>
<p><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Conditions and guarantees.</p></body></floatingText>2nd. And be it further resolved, That the foregoing consent of Congress is given upon the following conditions, and with the following guarantees, to <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>Boundaries to be adjusted by the U. States.</p></body></floatingText>wit: First, Said State to be formed, subject to the adjustment by this government, of all questions of boundary that may arise with other governments; <pb n="1229" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">In Convention of Texas.</fw>and the Constitution thereof with the proper evidence <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>State Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution to be adopted and presented.</p></body></floatingText> of its adoption by the people of said Republic of Texas, shall be transmitted to the President of the United States, to be laid before Congress for its final action, on or before the first day of January, one thousand eight hundred and forty-six. Second, Said State, when ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><floatingText rend="right"><body><p>What to be ceded to the U. States.</p></body></floatingText>mitted into the Union, after ceding to the United States all public edifices, fortifications, barracks, ports and harbors, navy and navy yards, docks, magazines, arms and armaments, and all other property and means per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining to the public defence belonging to the said Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, shall retain all the public funds, debts, <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>What to be retained.</p></body></floatingText> taxes, and dues of every kind, which may belong to or be due &#38; owing to the said Republic; and shall also retain all the vacant and unappropriated lands lying within its limits, to be applied to the payment of the debts and liabilities of said Republic of Texas, and the residue of said lands, after discharging said debts and liabilities, to be disposed of as said State may direct; but in no event are said debts and liabilities to become a <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Public debt of Texas.</p></body></floatingText> charge upon the government of the United States, Third, New States of convenient size, not exceeding <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>New States may be formed out of Texian territory.</p></body></floatingText> four in number, in addition to said State of Texas, and having sufficient population, may hereafter, by the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of said State, be formed out of the territory thereof, which shall be entitled to admission under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the Federal Constitution. And such states as may be formed out of that portion of said territory lying south of thirty-six degrees thirty minutes north latitude, commonly known as the Missouri Compromise <floatingText rend="right"><body><p>Missouri Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />promise Line established.</p></body></floatingText> Line, shall be admitted into the Union, with or without slavery, as the people of each State, asking admission may desire. And in such State or States, as shall be formed out of said territory; north of said Missouri Compromise Line, slavery or involuntary servitude (ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept for crime) shall be prohibited.</p>
<p>Now, in order to manifest the assent of the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple of this Republic as required in the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited portions of the said resolutions; We the deputies <pb n="1230" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">In Convention of Texas.</fw>of the people of Texas in convention assembled in their name and by their authority, do ordain and declare, that we assent to, and accept the proposals, conditions and guarantees contained in the first and second sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the resolution of the Congress of the United States aforesaid.</p>
<p>Done at the city of Austin, Republic of Texas July 4th 1845</p>
<closer>
<signed>THO. J. RUSK, President.<lb/> PHIL. M. CUNY<lb/> H. G. RUNNELS<lb/> ROBERT M. FORBES<lb/> SAM. LUSK<lb/> JNO. CALDWELL<lb/> JOSE ANTONIO NAVARRO<lb/> GEO. WM. BROWN<lb/> GUSTAVUS A. EVERTS<lb/> LEMUEL DALE EVANS<lb/> J. B. MILLER<lb/> R. E. B. BAYLOR<lb/> J. S. MAYFIELD<lb/> R. BACHE<lb/> JAMES LOVE<lb/> WM. L. HUNTER<lb/> JOHN D. ANDERSON<lb/> ISAAC PARKER<lb/> P. O. LUMPKIN<lb/> FRANCIS MOORE, JR.<lb/> ISAAC W. BRASHEAR<lb/> ALEXANDER MCGOWAN,<lb/> ISAAC VAN ZANDT<lb/> S. HOLLAND<lb/> EDWARD CLARK<lb/> GEO. W. SMYTH<lb/> JAMES ARMSTRONG<lb/> JOHN M. LEWIS<lb/> JAMES SCOTT<lb/> ARCHIBALD MCNEILL<lb/> A. C. HORTON<lb/> ISRAEL STANDEFER<lb/> JOS. L. HOGG,<lb/> CHAS. S. TAYLOR<lb/> DAVID GAGE<lb/> HENRY J. JEWETT<lb/> CAVITT ARMSTRONG<lb/> JAMES POWER<lb/> ALBERT H. LATIMER<lb/> WM. C. YOUNG<lb/> J. PINCKNEY HENDERSON<lb/> NICHOLAS H. DARNELL<lb/> EMERY RAINS<lb/> A. W. O. HICKS<lb/> JAMES M. BURROUGHS<lb/> H. L. KINNEY<lb/> WILLIAM L. CAZNEAU<lb/> A. S. CUNNINGHAM<lb/> ABNER S. LIPSCOMB<lb/> JOHN HEMPHILL<lb/> VAN R. IRION<lb/> VOLNEY E. HOWARD<lb/> E. H. TARRANT<lb/> FRANCIS M. WHITE<lb/> JAMES DAVIS<lb/> GEORGE T. WOOD<lb/> G. W. WRIGHT<lb/> H. R. LATIMER<lb/> W. B. OCHILTREE<lb/> OLIVER JONES<lb/> B. O. BAGBY<lb/> CHS. BELLINGER STEW<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><lb/> ART Attest</signed>
<signed>J<smcap>AS.</smcap> H. R<smcap>AYMOND</smcap>,<lb/> Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>