<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd"
 xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="655" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="act">
<head type="main">[APPENDIX.] </head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">A PROCLAMATION</head>
<byline>BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</byline>
<p>Whereas, a Treaty of Amity, Navigation and Commerce, between the Republic of Texas, and his Majesty the King of the French, together with three separate articles annexed to the same, was concluded and signed by the respective Plenipotentiaries of the two Governments, at Paris, on the twenty-fifth day of Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-nine, which treaty and additional articles are word for word as follows:</p>
<p>The President of the Republic of Texas, and his Majesty the King of the French, desiring to regulate, in a permanent manner, the political and commercial relations between Texas and France, have resolved to conclude a Treaty of Amity, Navigation and Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />merce, founded on the common interests of the two countries, and which shall establish the formal recognition, on the part of France, of the Independence of the Republic of Texas; and, to this effect, have named for their Plenipotentiaries, That is to say:&#8212;</p>
<p>The President of Texas&#8212;General James Pinckney Henderson, a citizen of the said Republic; and his Majesty the King of the French&#8212;Jean de Dien Soult, Duke of Dalmatia, Marshal and Peer of France, Grand Cross of His Royal Order of the Legion of Honor, &#38;c. &#38;c. &#38;c., his Minister and Secretary of State for the department of Foreign Affairs, President of his Council of Ministers.</p>
<p>And the aforesaid Plenipotentiaries, after having compared and exchanged their several powers, found to be in due form, have agreed upon the following articles.</p>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 1.</head>
<p>There shall be perpetual peace and amity between his Majesty the King of the French, his heirs and successors, on the one part, and the Republic of Texas, on the other part; and between the citizens of the two states, without exception of persons or of places.</p>
<pb n="656" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 2.</head>
<p>The French and Texians shall enjoy, in their persons and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, in the entire extent of their respective territories, the same rights, privileges, and exemptions, which are or may be granted to the most favored nation. They shall have the right of disposing freely of their property by sale, exchange, by deed of gift, will, or in any other manner, without any impediment or difficulty. In like manner, the citizens of each, inheriting property in either of the states, may become heirs, without any hindrance, to such prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perty which may devolve to them al intestate, and without being held to pay any other or higher tax on the succession than that which shall be paid in similar cases by the citizens of the country themselves. They shall be exempted from all military service,&#8212;from all war contributions,&#8212;forced loans,&#8212;military requisitions, and in every other case, their personal or real estate shall not be subject to any other charge or impost than that which shall be paid by the citizens of the country themselves.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 3.</head>
<p>If it should happen that one of the two contracting parties be at war with any other power whatever, the other power shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibit their citizens from taking or holding commissions or letters of marque to cruise against the other, or to molest the commerce or property of her citizens.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 4.</head>
<p>The two contracting parties adopt in their mutual relations, the principle &#8220;that the flag covers the goods.&#8221;</p>
<p>If one of the two parties remains neuter when the other may be at war with a third power, the goods covered by the neutral flag shall also be considered to be neutral, even if they should belong to the enemies of the other contracting party.</p>
<p>It is equally understood, that the neutrality of flag protects also the freedom of persons, and that the individuals belonging to a hostile power, who may be found on board a neutral vessel, shall not be made prisoners, unless they are actually engaged in the ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice of the enemy.</p>
<p>In consequence of the principle that the merchandise is to be considered as belonging to the nation under the flag of which it sails, neutral property found on board an enemy&#8217;s vessel, shall be considered as an enemy&#8217;s, unless, it shall have been shipped on board the vessel before the declaration of war, or before knowledge of such declaration in the port from whence the vessel may have departed.</p>
<p>The two contracting parties will not apply this principle, as it may concern other powers, except in the case of those by whom it may be recognized.</p>
<pb n="657" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 5.</head>
<p>In case one of the contracting parties should be at war with another power, and her ships at sea should be compelled to exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise the right of search, it is agreed that if they meet a vessel be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing to the other, then neutral, party, they shall send their boat on board said vessel with two persons charged to enter on an examination of the nationality and cargo of said vessel. The com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manders shall be responsible for all vexations, acts of violence, which they may either commit or tolerate on such occasion. The search shall not be permitted but on board vessels which navigate without convoy. It will be sufficient when they are convoyed, that the commander of the convoy declares verbally, and on his word of honor, that the vessels placed under his protection, and under his convoy, belong to the state under whose flag he sails, and that he declares, when the vessels shall be destined to an enemy&#8217;s port, that they have no goods on board, contraband of war.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 6.</head>
<p>In case one of the two countries should be at war with a third power, the citizens of the other country, shall have a right to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue their commerce and their navigation with the same power, with the exception of the towns or ports, before which there shall be established an actual and effective blockade. It is fully under<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stood, that this liberty of commerce and navigation, shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend to articles reputed contraband of war, such as cannon and fire<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />arms, swords, pikes, projectiles, powder, saltpetre, objects of mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary equipment, and all instruments whatever manufactured for the purposes of war. In no case a trading vessel belonging to citizens of either of the two countries, which shall have sailed for a port blockaded by the other state, shall be seized, captured, or condemn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, unless the commander has previously been notified of the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istence of the blockade, by some vessel making a part of the squad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ron or division forming the blockade; and in order that no vessel may allege ignorance of the facts, and really be liable to capture, on her re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appearance before the same port whilst the blockade is enforced, the commander of the ships of war who shall first meet her, must endorse on her papers his visa, indicating the date, the place, or latitude, or longitude, where he has visited the vessel and given the notification in question, which shall contain, besides, all the other indications required for the visa.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 7.</head>
<p>The vessels of one of the two countries, forced into one of the ports of the other by distress, shall be exempt from all duties either upon the ship or cargo, if they enter into no commercial <pb n="658" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>operations; provided, that the necessity of entering such a port is legally established, and that they do not remain in the port longer than the necessity of the case requires.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 8.</head>
<p>The two contracting parties shall have the right to appoint con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />suls, vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consuls, and consular agents in all the cities or ports open to the foreign commerce: these agents shall not enter on their func<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions until they shall have obtained the authorization of the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of the country.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 9.</head>
<p>The respective consuls, vice consuls, consular agents, and their chancellors, shall enjoy in the two countries, the privileges which generally belong to their functions, such as exemption from having soldiers quartered upon them, from all direct contributions as well personal as movable or sumptuary, unless however, they are citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens of the country, or that they become proprietors or holders of real estate, or are engaged in commercial business, in either of which cases they shall be subject to the same taxes and charges as other individuals. These agents shall enjoy besides, all the other privileges, exemptions and immunities, which shall be granted in their places of residence, to the agents of the same rank of the most favored nation.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 10.</head>
<p>The archives, and in general all the papers of the offices of the respective consulates, shall be inviolable; and under no pretext, nor in any case, shall they either be seized or searched by the local authorities.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 11.</head>
<p>The respective Consuls, Vice-Consuls, and Consular agents, shall have the right, on the death of their fellow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />citizens, who shall have died without having made a will or nominated testamentary executors, to execute, either by virtue of their office, or at the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quest of the parties interested, (taking care to give previous notice to the competent local authorities,) all the formalities necessary for the security of the heirs; to take possession, in their name, of the succession; and to liquidate and administer the same, either personally or by substitutes named under their responsibility.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 12.</head>
<p>The respective Consuls, Vice-Consuls, and Consular agents, shall be charged exclusively with the internal police of the commercial vessels of their nation; and the local authorities shall not interfere, except in cases of riot or disturbance of a nature calculated to af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect the public peace, either on shore or on board other vessels.</p>
<pb n="659" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 13.</head>
<p>The respective Consuls, Vice-Consuls, and Consular agents, shall have the right to arrest all sailors who shall have deserted from ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels of war, or merchant vessels belonging to their respective coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tries, and may send them on board, or to their own country. To this effect, they will address themselves in writing to the compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent local authorities, and will justify by the exhibition of the ship&#8217;s register, or roll of the crew; or if the said ship should have sailed, by a copy of said documents, duly certified by them, that the men whom they claim were a part of the same crew. On this de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand thus justified, the delivery shall not be refused them; be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sides, every aid and assistance shall be given to them in seeking out, seizing and arresting the said deserters who shall even be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained and kept in the prisons of the country, on the requisition, and at the expense of the Consuls, until these agents shall have found an opportunity to send them away. If, however, this op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portunity should not present itself in the space of four months, counting from the day of their arrest, the deserters shall be set at liberty, and cannot again be arrested for the same cause.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 14.</head>
<p>French vessels arriving in or sailing out of the ports of Texas, and Texian vessels on their entry in or leaving the ports of France, shall not be subject to other or higher duties of tonnage, of light money, port charges, pilotage, quarantine, or any other affecting the body of the vessel than those which are paid, or shall be paid by the vessels of the country itself.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 15.</head>
<p>The products of the soil, and of the industry of either of the two countries, imported directly into the ports of the other, the origin of which shall be duly ascertained, shall pay the same du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties whether imported in French or Texian vessels. In like man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, the products exported will pay the same duties, and will enjoy the same privileges, allocations and drawbacks, which are or shall be allowed on the exportation of the same articles in the vessels of the country from which they are exported.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 16.</head>
<p>The cottons of Texas, without distinction of quality, will pay on their entry into the ports of France, when they shall be imported directly in French or Texian vessels, a uniform duty of twenty francs on one hundred kilogrammes.</p>
<p>All reduction of duties which may hereafter be made in favor of the cottons of the United States, shall be equally applied to those of Texas, gratuitously, should the concession be gratuitous, or with the same compensation, if the concession is conditional.</p>
<pb n="660" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 17</head>
<p>From the day of the exchange of the ratifications of the present treaty, the duties at present levied in Texas on all fabricks and other articles of silk, or of which silk shall be a chief component,part, imported directly into Texas, the manufacture of France, in French or Texian vessels, shall be reduced one half. It is clearly understood, that if the Texian government reduce the duties upon similar products of other nations, to a rate inferior to one half of the duties now existing, France cannot be obliged, in any case, to pay higher duties than those paid by the most favored nation. The duties at present levied in Texas on the Wines and Brandies of France, also imported directly in French or Texian vessels, shall be reduced, the first two-fifths, and the second one fifth.</p>
<p>It is understood, that in case the Republic of Texas should here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after think proper to diminish the present duties on Wines and<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Brandies, the production of other countries, a corresponding re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duction shall be made on the Wines and Brandies of France, gra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuitously, if the concession is gratuitous, or with the same compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation, if the concession is conditional.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 18.</head>
<p>The inhabitants of the French colonies, their property and ships, shall enjoy in Texas, and reciprocally the citizens of Texas, their property and ships shall enjoy in the French colonies, all the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vantages which are or shall be granted to the most favored nation.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 19.</head>
<p>The stipulations of the present treaty shall be perpetual, with the exception of the articles, the fourteenth, fifteenth, sixteenth, seventeenth, and eighteenth, the duration of which is fixed to eight years, counting from the day of the exchange of the ratifications.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 20.</head>
<p>The present treaty shall be ratified by the contracting parties, and the ratifications shall be exchanged at Paris or Austin, within the period of eight months, or sooner if possible.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, the respective Plenipotentiaries, have signed the present treaty, and have affixed thereto their seals.</p>
<p>Done at Paris, the twenty-fifth day of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and thirty-nine.</p>
<closer>
<signed>[SEAL.] Signed, J. PINCKNEY HENDERSON,</signed>
<signed>[SEAL.] Signed, MAL. DUC DE DALMATIE.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="661" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ADDITIONAL ARTICLES.</head>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 1.</head>
<p>As the laws of France require, as conditions of the nationality of a vessel, &#8212; that it should have been built in France, &#8212; that the own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, the captain, and three-fourths of the crew, shall be citizens of France: and Texas, by reason of the particular circumstances in which she is placed, being unable to comply with the same condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, the two contracting parties have agreed to consider as Texian vessels, those which shall be bona fide the exclusive and real prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty of a citizen or citizens of Texas, residents of the country for at least two years, and of which the captain and two-thirds of the crew, shall also be bona fide citizens of Texas.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 2.</head>
<p>It is understood, that if the Republic of Texas thinks proper, hereafter, to diminish the duties now in force on silk goods, they will maintain between the silk goods the produce of countries be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond the Cape of Good Hope, and similar goods of other countries, a difference of ten per cent. in favor of the latter.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="article">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 3.</head>
<p>The present additional articles shall have the same force for eight years, as if they had been word for word inserted in the Treaty of this day.</p>
<p>They shall be equally ratified by the contracting parties, and the ratifications exchanged at the same time as those of the Treaty.</p>
<p>Done at Paris, the twenty-fifth day of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-nine.</p>
<closer>
<signed>[SEAL.] Signed, J.PINCKNEY HENDERSON,</signed>
<signed>[SEAL.] Signed, MAL. DUC DE DALMATIE.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>And whereas, the said Treaty and Additional Articles have been ratified on both parts, and the respective ratifications of the same were exchanged at Austin, on the fourteenth day of February, one thousand eight hundred and forty, by Abner S. Lipscomb, Secretary of State of the Republic of Texas, and Monsieur Dubios de Saligny, Charg&#233; d&#8217; Affaires of his Majesty the King of the French, Knight of his Royal Order of the Legion of Honor, &#38;c., &#38;c., &#38;c., on the part of the respective governments.</p>
<p>Now, therefore, be it known, that I, Mirabeau B. Lamr, Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident of the Republic of Texas, have caused the said Treaty to be made public, to the end that the same, and every clause and article thereof, may be observed and fulfilled with good faith by the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, and the citizens thereof.</p>
<pb n="662" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the seal of the Republic of Texas, to be affixed.</p>
<p>Done at the City of Austin, this fifteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and forty, and of the Independence of the Republic the fourth.</p>
<closer>
<signed>MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.</signed>
<signed>By the President,<lb/> ABNER S. LIPSCOMB, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">A PROCLAMATION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>By the President of the Republic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, by the eleventh, section of an act entitled &#8220;An Act alter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the several acts to raise a Revenue by Impost Duties,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved the 5th February instant, the President is authorized to issue such instructions as may be necessary to carry into effect such present and future agreements with the government of France, by the regulation of the duties on goods, wares and mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandise, imported from that country:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it known, that I, Mirabeau B. Lamar, President of the Republic of Texas, for the purpose of carrying the above ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects into effect, by virtue of the power vested in me by law, do, in the name and by the authority of said Republic, by these presents, hereby declare and proclaim, that the duties on all wines, the product of France, imported direct from any of the Ports of France, in French or Texian vessels, are for the present abolished. And further, I hereby require all Collectors of customs to permit all wines as aforesaid, to be admitted free of duty into any of the Ports of this Republic, until this Proclamation shall be revoked by the President.</p>
<p>In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the seal of the Republic of Texas to be affixed.</p>
<p>[L. S.] Done at the City of Austin, this 11th day of February, in the year of our Lord one thous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and eight hundred and forty, and of the In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependence of the Republic, the fourth.</p>
<closer>
<signed>MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.</signed>
<signed>By the President,<lb/> ARNER S. LIPSCOMB, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="663" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ERRATA.</head>
<p>Page 20, 2nd line from top, for &#8220;thereof&#8221; read &#8220;therefor.&#8221; &#8220; 20, 7th line 2nd section for &#8220;where the husband&#8221; read &#8220;where her husband.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;20, 5th line 3rd section, for &#8220;being&#8221; read &#8220;living.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;41, 16th line from bottom, for &#8220;bound&#8221; read &#8220;loaned.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;43, 17th line from bottom for &#8220;ratio&#8221; read &#8220;valid.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;45, 8th line from bottom, after &#8220;thence&#8221; read &#8220;in a.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;57, last line section 1st, for &#8220;cases&#8221; read &#8220;causes.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;69, 2nd line from top, for &#8220;county&#8221; read &#8220;country.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;72, 8th line from top, after &#8220;persons&#8221; read &#8220;owning.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;84, 9th line section 8th, for &#8220;entered&#8221; read &#8220;returned.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;84, llth line same section, for &#8220;damage&#8221; read &#8220;demand.&#8221; </p>
<p>&#8220;91, 3rd line 4th section, for &#8220;McRed&#8221; read &#8220;McRea.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;93, 13th line from top, for &#8220;January&#8221; read &#8220;February.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;100, 1st line top, after &#8220;application&#8221; read &#8220;by petiton.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;102, 10th line from bottom, for &#8220;25th&#8221; read &#8220;5th.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;138, 5th line from top, for &#8220;forming,&#8221; read &#8220;framing.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;146, 4th line 3d section, for &#8220;Morthans,&#8221; read &#8220;Wortham.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;162, 11th line from bottom, read &#8220;the General Post Office.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;164, second line from top, for &#8220;when&#8221; read &#8220;where.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;164, 12th line from top, for &#8220;where,&#8221; read &#8220;when.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;168, 7th line 18th section, for &#8220;any,&#8221; read &#8220;an.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;169, bottom line, for &#8220;supreme,&#8221; read &#8220;superior.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;186, Section 5th, 2nd line, after &#8220;convicted&#8221; read &#8220;of.&#8221;</p>
<pb n="664" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, the undersigned, Secretary of State of the Republic of Texas, do certify, that the regular Session of the Fifth Congress of said Republic, adjourned on the fifth day of February, eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty-one.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and seal of office, at the City of Austin, the eighteenth day of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and forty-one.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. S. MAYFIELD.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="665" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Joint resolution Granting further time for the payment of Government Dues, and the return of Field Notes. 3</p>
<p>Joint resolution, requiring the Treasurer to pay five thousand dollars out of the appropriations for the Quartermaster and Postmaster&#8217;s Departments, for the contingent expenses of the two houses of Congress. 3</p>
<p>Joint resolution, appropriating five thousand dollars for the Contingent Expenses of both houses of Congress. 4</p>
<p>An Act concerning certain Free Persons of Color. 4</p>
<p>An Act, Supplementary to &#8220;An act to detect Fraudulent Land Certificates &#38;c.&#8221; passed, January, one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty. 5</p>
<p>Joint resolution, Transferring funds appropriated for the Cav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alry to the Infantry. 5</p>
<p>An act, concerning the powers of Chief Justices of the County Courts. 6</p>
<p>Joint resolution, requiring the Postmaster General not to close the Mail contracts for the year 1841. 6</p>
<p>Joint resolution, Granting a League of Land to the heirs of Jesse Thompson, deceased. 7</p>
<p>An act, to provide for the Navigation of the Guadalupe River. 7</p>
<p>An act, Supplementary to &#8220;An act to repeal a portion of &#8216;an act creating funds for the support of the Government for the year 1840,&#8217;&#8221; approved 10th December 1840. 9</p>
<p>An act, to exempt the citizens of West Columbia, from the provisions of &#8220;An act Incorporating the Town of Colum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bia,&#8221; passed December twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ninth, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-seven. 10</p>
<p>An act, Appropriating four thousand dollars for the purpose therein named. 10</p>
<p>An act, to amend &#8220;An act to suppress Gaming,&#8221;. 11</p>
<p>Joint resolution, Authorizing the President to employ three Spy Companies, for the Western Frontier. 11</p>
<p>Joint resolution, making an appropriation to defray the Civil Contingent expenses of Government. 12</p>
<p>An act, for the election and appointment of Sheriff. 12</p>
<p>An act, to define in part the duties of Judges of District Courts. 13</p>
<pb n="666" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act, to extend to those soldiers who served in the Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paign against San Antonio in the fall of one thousand eight hundred and thirty five, a Donation of Land. 11</p>
<p>Joint resolution, to continue the transportation of the Mails for a limited time. 15</p>
<p>An act, to provide the method of filling the office of City Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder. 15</p>
<p>An act, for the regulation of the Coasting Trade and the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tection of Texian Shipping. 15</p>
<p>Joint resolution, Transferring a certain appropriation. 18</p>
<p>An act, providing the mode of appointing Wreck Masters and prescribng their duties. 18</p>
<p>An act, Concerning Divorce and alimony. 19</p>
<p>An act, to amend the act which provides the mode of taking Testimony by Interrogatories, to provide a mode for taking Depositions. 22</p>
<p>An act, to dispose of the Public Buildings in the City of Austin. 24</p>
<p>An act, to Incorporate the Harrisburg Rail Road and Trading Company. 24</p>
<p>An act, as to the payment of Taxes in the frontier Counties of this Republic. 24</p>
<p>An act, confirming the use and occupation and enjoyment of the Churches, Church Lots and Mission Churches, to the Boman Catholic congregations, living in or near the vicinity of the same. 28</p>
<p>Joint resolution, to provide for the better collection of Monies due from delinquent Agents and Officers of the government 29</p>
<p>An act, prescribing the mode of Organizing the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives. 30</p>
<p>An act, to increase the Bonds of the Sheriff of Harris County. 31</p>
<p>An act, granting the Alamo Church to the use and benefit of the Catholic Church. 32</p>
<p>An act, to make provision for the Vice President, while per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming the duties of the president. 32</p>
<p>An act, to complete the Organization of the Militia. 33</p>
<p>An act, to Charter the Houston and Austin Turnpike Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany. 35</p>
<p>An act, creating a system of Bankruptcy and regulating the Collection of Foreign Debts. 38</p>
<p>An act, the better to define the Boundaries of the County of Galveston. 45</p>
<p>An act, to amend an act entitled &#8220;An act to Incorporate the city of Richmond, and the towns of San Felipe DeAustin, and LaGrange,&#8221; approved November eighteenth one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and thirty-seven. 46</p>
<pb n="667" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act, to repeal in part the thirty-seventh section of the Act to regulate the proceedings in Civil Suits, approved Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary fifth, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 47</p>
<p>An act, to discontinue and abolish certain Ports of Entry and to establish instead thereof, a Port of Entry, to be called Port Calhoun. 47</p>
<p>An act, to establish the county of Spring Creek for Judicial purposes. 49</p>
<p>An act, requiring the Chief Justice of Bastrop County, to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form certain duties therein mentioned. 50</p>
<p>An act, prohibiting forced Sale of Slaves under Execution. 51</p>
<p>An act, Incorporating the Travis Guards. 52</p>
<p>An act, supplementary to &#8220;An act Establishing the Jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and powers of the District Courts&#8221;. 52</p>
<p>An act, to protect the Rights of the Heirs and next of kin, to the members of the Georgia Battalion, and other Volunteers from foreign countries who have fallen in the battles of the Republic, or otherwise died in the limits of the same. 53</p>
<p>An act, defining the time of holding the Courts in the First Judicial District. 54</p>
<p>An act, to regulate Bills of Exception. 54</p>
<p>An act, granting District Attorneys power to Challenge Jurors. 55</p>
<p>An act, to Organize a part of the Counties of Red River, Bowie, and Lamar, for Judicial and other purposes. 56</p>
<p>An act, to Regulate the Proceedings of the District Courts when sitting as Courts of Admiralty. 57</p>
<p>An act, to Repeal and Amend certain parts or portions of an act entitled an &#8220;Act concerning Executions&#8221;. 61</p>
<p>An act, to Repeal certain Acts therein named. 62</p>
<p>An act, supplementary to &#8220;An Act prohibiting the Location of Fraudulent Land Claims,&#8221; approved February the fifth, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 63</p>
<p>An act, to authorize and require the Commisisoner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office to commence the issuing of Land Patents, and for other purposes. 64</p>
<p>An act, to Organize a part of the Counties of Matagorda and Colorado, for Judicial and other purposes. 65</p>
<p>An act, to Regulate Public Sales. 66</p>
<p>An act, to Amend &#8220;An Act to regulate the Proceedings in Civil Suits,&#8221; approved February fifth, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 67</p>
<p>An act Authorizing the chief Justice of Milam County to have Land Appraised and Condemned for Public use, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munerate the owner or owners thereof for the same. 67</p>
<pb n="668" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act, supplementary and Amendatory of certain Acts there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in named. 68</p>
<p>An act to legalize the Acts of the Board of Land Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers of Harrison County. 69</p>
<p>An act supplementary to An act for the Punishment of Crimes and Misdemeanors. 70</p>
<p>An act, for the Relief of the Purchasers of Lots in the City of Austin and on the tract adjoining. 71</p>
<p>An act, granting a Donation of Land to actual Settlers on or near the Military Road on the Northern Frontier. 72</p>
<p>An act, to Organize a certain part of the county of Liberty for Judicial and other purposes. 74</p>
<p>An act, to Incorporate the Galveston University. 75</p>
<p>Joint resolution, authorizing the Sale of Lots, in the town of Calhoun. 77</p>
<p>An act, to Incorporate the Texas Trading, Mining, and Emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grating Company. 78</p>
<p>An act, Incorporating the Galveston Artillery Company. 80</p>
<p>An act, the better to define the Boundaries of the County of Fort Bend. 80</p>
<p>An act, to change the Name of certain persons therein men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned. 81</p>
<p>An act, regulating the time of holding the District Courts of the Seventh Judicial District. 82</p>
<p>An act, to regulate the Granting and Trial of Injunctions, and to empower the Judges of the District Courts to submit is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sues of fact to a Jury in Chancery cases. 82</p>
<p>An Act, for the Relief of certain Free Persons of Color. 85</p>
<p>An act, to define in part the boundaries of the county of Wash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ington and to create the county&#8217;of Navasoto. 86</p>
<p>Joint resolution, to repeal so much of an act entitled &#8220;An act compensating officers of the Civil List,&#8221; passed and approv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed on the ninth day of December, one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and thirty-six, as relates to Chief Justices of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public. 89</p>
<p>An act, to incorporate the &#8220;German Union&#8221; for Texas. 89</p>
<p>An act, granting Land to Emigrants. 90</p>
<p>Joint resolution, for certain purposes therein named. 93</p>
<p>An act, appropriating Eight Thousand Dollars for purposes therein named. 93</p>
<p>An act, to annex the Port of San Luis to the Collectoral Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of the Brazos. 94</p>
<p>An act, to Organize a part of the County of Houston, for ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial and other purposes. 94</p>
<p>An act, relative to the duties of the Collector of the District of Brazos. 95</p>
<pb n="669" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of persons who failed to give in a list of their taxable property to the county Assessor. 96</p>
<p>An act to divide the county of Red River, and to create and establish the counties of Bowie, and Lamar. 97</p>
<p>An act for the benefit of settlers residing near the boundary line of the United States, in the counties of Red River and Harrison. 99</p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Franklin Association, in the city of Houston. 100</p>
<p>An act the better to define the boundary line between the counties of Matagorda and Victoria. 102</p>
<p>An act to amend &#8220;an act organzing justices&#8217; courts, and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fining the powers and jurisdiction of the same&#8221;. 102</p>
<p>Joint resolution to provide for the better collection of monies due from delinquent agents and officers of the government. 104</p>
<p>An act to abolish certain offices therein named, and to fix the military and naval establishments of the republic. 105</p>
<p>An act making appropriations for the support of government, for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-one. 107</p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of persons who have failed to give in a list of their taxable property to the county Assessor 111</p>
<p>All act supplementary to &#8220;an act to raise a public revenue by impost duties;&#8221; approved fifth of February, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 112</p>
<p>An act to amend an act entitled &#8220;an act to raise a public reve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nue by direct taxation,&#8221; approved January sixteenth, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 112</p>
<p>An act to complete the organization of the militia. 115</p>
<p>An act Supplementary to an act entitled &#8220;an act authorizing the issuing of duplicate land warrants, discharges, and head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rights, on certain conditions. 117</p>
<p>An act to amend the several laws establishing a general post<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />office. 117</p>
<p>An act supplementary to &#8220;an act for the benfit of settlers re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding near the boundary line of the United States, in the counties of Red River and Harrison.&#8221; 118</p>
<p>Joint resolution appropriating ten thousand dollars, in par funds, to defray the expenses of running and marking the boundary line between the republic of Texas and the United States of America. 119</p>
<p>An act supplementary to the act of limitation. 119</p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Secretary of State to draw for the appropriation to run the boundary line. 120</p>
<p>An act to repeal a portion of &#8220;an act for creating funds for the support of government, for the year 1840.&#8221;. 120</p>
<pb n="670" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act supplementary to &#8220;an act regulating sales by judgment or decree of a probate court or court of chancery. 121</p>
<p>An act requiring the chief justices of counties to issue writs of election in certain cases. 121</p>
<p>An act securing the right of appeal from the justices&#8217; to the district courts. 122</p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Galveston city Company. 122</p>
<p>An act to repeal the seventh section of &#8220;an act supplementary to an act to raise a revenue by direct taxation, and for other purposes.&#8221; 124</p>
<p>Joint resolution to define the duties of the chief clerk of the bureau of stock commissioner. 124</p>
<p>A joint resolution making an appropriation to defray the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of congress. 125</p>
<p>An act to protect settlers in that portion of the territory of Texas, which has been surveyed by authority and direction of the United States of the North. 125</p>
<p>Joint resolution making an appropriation to pay for muskets. 126</p>
<p>Joint resolution granting the president leave of absence. 126</p>
<p>Joint resolution providing for the election of a board of travel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ling commissioners, east of the Brazos. 127</p>
<p>An act to be entitled an act for the relief of the purchasers of Austin city and outlots. 127</p>
<p>An act to amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston. 128</p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of the postmaster general, the first and second auditors and treasurer. 129</p>
<p>Joint resolution appropriating one of the unoccupied houses belonging to the government for the use of the clerk of the supreme court. 129</p>
<p>Joint resolution supplementary to a joint resolution for the relief of the purchasers of Austin city and out lots. 130</p>
<p>An act defining the mode by which the holders of conditional certificates shall establish the same. 130</p>
<p>An act to authorize the firm of McKinney, Williams &#38; Co., to issue their notes for circulation as money. 134</p>
<p>An act supplementary to an act entitled &#8220;an act the better to define the boundaries of Fort Bend.&#8221;. 136</p>
<p>An act to establish and incorporate the Guadalupe College. 136</p>
<p>An act, legalizing the Official acts of Wm. H. Steele, Commissioner. 140</p>
<p>An act, to Consolidate the several Appropriations for the Navy Department, for the year eighteen hundred and forty. 141</p>
<p>An act, supplementary to &#8220;an act for the Relief of Jonathan Ikin.&#8221;. 141</p>
<pb n="671" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act, supplementary to &#8220;an act to establish and Incorporate Rutersville College,&#8221; approved February fifth, one thousand eight hundred and forty. 142</p>
<p>An act, for the relief of those who have taken the Benefit of the Insolvent Laws of other Countries. 143</p>
<p>An act, prescribing the mode in which Married Persons may dispose of their separate Property. 144</p>
<p>Joint resolution, for the relief of Capt. A. C. Hinton, and other purposes. 145</p>
<p>An act, to establish and Incorporate Trinity College. 146</p>
<p>An act, to legalize the Official acts of Samuel Todd, and those who acted as his Deputies, and for other purposes. 149</p>
<p>An act, to establish and Incorporate the Austin Lyceum. 149</p>
<p>An act, to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to employ a Draftsman, and providing for the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation of County Surveyors. 150</p>
<p>An act, supplementary to &#8220;an act to authorize and require the Commissioner General of the Land Office to commence the issuing of Patents, and for other purposes,&#8221; approved Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary nineteen, eighteen hundred and forty. 151</p>
<p>A Joint resolution for the relief of the Clerks employed in the several Departments and Bureaus of the Government. 152</p>
<p>Joint Resolution extending the time for collection of Taxes. 152</p>
<p>An act to Organize a part of the County of Harrison for Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial and other purposes. 153</p>
<p>An act to after [the] time of holding the Courts in the Fifth Judicial District. 155</p>
<p>An act to Incorporate the Galveston and Virginia Point Bridge Company. 156</p>
<p>An act to repeal so much of an act, as provides for Consular Certificates. 159</p>
<p>Joint resolution requiring Sheriffs of certain Counties to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form certain duties. 159</p>
<p>An act authorizing any holder of Promissory Notes, Bonds, Funded Debt, or any other liquidated claims against the government, to surrender the same, and receive in lieu thereof, Land Scrip. 160</p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of the Clerks, Door-Keepers and Seargeant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />at-Arms, of the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives. 161</p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of the Clerks of the Naval and other Bureaus. 162</p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Postmaster General to sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pend all Contracts for carrying the Mail for the year 1841. 163</p>
<p>An act of Limitations. 163</p>
<pb n="672" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>An act supplementary to &#8220;an act to Detect Fraudulent Land certificates, and to provide for issuing Patents to Legal Claimants.&#8221; 171</p>
<p>An act to authorize the raising of a Corps of Volunteers to dis lodge the hostile Indians on the upper Brazos River. 174</p>
<p>An act to repeal &#8220;An act to provide for the Redemption of the Promissory Notes,&#8221; &#38;c., approved. 175</p>
<p>Joint resolution making appropriation for Pay of District Judges, for the year eighteen hundred and forty, and for other purposes. 175</p>
<p>An act legalizing and confirming certain Marriages therein named. 176</p>
<p>An act to provide for the support and education of Indigent Orphans. 176</p>
<p>An act to quiet the Land Titles within the twenty frontier leagues bordering on the United States of the North. 177</p>
<p>An act regulating Sales by judgment or decree of a probate court, or court of chancery. 179</p>
<p>An act to make certain offences therein named, Grand Lar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceny, and to prescribe their punishment. 180</p>
<p>An act suplementary to an act entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the return of surveys, for the collection of government dues on lands, and for other purposes.&#8221;. 180</p>
<p>Joint resolution fixing the compensation of the heads of de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partments and bureaus, and the clerks in the several depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments and bureaus of government. 181</p>
<p>An act supplementary to &#8220;an act to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />organize the several ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial districts, and to create the sixth and seventh districts,&#8221; approved January twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ninth, eighteen hundred and forty. 182</p>
<p>An act to encourage frontier protection. 182</p>
<p>An act for the relief of certain free persons of color. 184</p>
<p>An act regulating the sale, of runaway slaves. 185</p>
<p>An act defining the time of holding the District Court in the County of Ward. 186</p>
<p>An act to amend an act, entitled &#8220;An Act regulating attach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments,&#8221; approved January twenty-eighth, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-nine. 187</p>
<p>An act to consolidate the several appropriations for the Quar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termaster&#8217;s Department for the year one thousand eight hundred and forty, and for other purposes therein named. 188</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>